[{"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/06/13/105271494-GettyImages-973390454.jpg?v=1531420831", "time": "2018-07-05T15:03:04-0400", "author": "Andrew Harrer | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "description": "The Fed on Thursday released minutes from its June meeting, where members voted to raise the federal-funds rate by a quarter-percentage point. ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/05/fed-meeting-minutes-from-june.html", "title": "Fed: Letting inflation run too hot could lead to 'a significant economic downturn'", "keywords": [{"term": "Fed Minutes", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2:34 PM ET Thu", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "5", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "02:05 Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "minutes", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Thursday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Federal Open Market Committee", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "quarter", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1.75 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "seventh", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "December 2015", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "about 4 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the second quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "minutes", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "next year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the White House", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "minutes", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "The Congressional Budget Office", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "$1 trillion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "2020", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "3.8 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}], "body": " show chapters Fed Minutes: Many districts report concern over tariffs 2:34 PM ET Thu, 5 July 2018 | 02:05 Federal Reserve officials worry that letting the U.S. economy run too strong could cause major problems down the road if left unchecked, according to minutes from the most recent central bank meeting. Some members expressed “concern that a prolonged period in which the economy operated beyond potential could give rise to heightened inflationary pressures or to financial imbalances that could lead eventually to a significant economic downturn,” the meeting summary released Thursday stated. As a result, almost all officials at the central bank believe they should continue to raise interest rates on a regular basis. That comes even amid substantial worry that current tensions between the U.S. and its trading partners could stall the growth the economy has seen this year. Fed business contacts “expressed concern about the possible adverse effects of tariffs and other proposed trade restrictions, both domestically and abroad, on future investment activity.” Moreover, they indicated “capital spending had been scaled back or postponed as a result of uncertainty over trade policy.” Those concerns, however, did not stop the policymaking Federal Open Market Committee from approving another quarter-point hike to the benchmark overnight borrowing rate. The funds rate moved to a range of 1.75 percent to 2 percent, the seventh such increase since December 2015. 'Progressing smoothly' The move came amid an economy expected to grow by about 4 percent in the second quarter amid high levels of consumer and business sentiment and increasing levels of investment. Economic growth is “progressing smoothly” the minutes stated, with activity “expanding at a solid rate,” and “labor market conditions continuing to strengthen.” Inflation is hovering around the Fed’s 2 percent inflation goal, the minutes also said. “Almost all participants” thought the rate hike was appropriate. Committee members even approved removing a long-standing clause known as “forward guidance,” stating that the fund rate would remain “below levels that are expected to prevail in the longer run.” In fact, officials said that if the current course continues, the rate actually could be above what they consider “neutral” by next year. Maintaining forward guidance “was no longer appropriate in light of the strong state of the economy and the current expected path for policy.” Still, there were plenty of worries expressed at the meeting. Trade was a hot topic as the White House prepares to levy a series of tariffs that will take effect Friday. “Most participants noted that uncertainty and risks associated with trade policy had intensified and were concerned that such uncertainty and risks eventually could have negative effects on business sentiment and investment spending,” the minutes stated. Members saw fiscal policy – last year’s tax cuts as well as increased spending plans – as “supportive of economic growth” and posing “upside risks,” though a few worried that it is unsustainable. The Congressional Budget Office has estimated that the U.S. will be running a $1 trillion deficit by 2020, posing worries that debt will stymie economic growth. Fed officials also expressed some worry about conditions overseas. “Many participants saw potential downside risks to economic growth and inflation associated with political and economic developments in Europe and some” emerging market economies. The jobs market and its 3.8 percent unemployment rate also came under some scrutiny. Members noted what has now become a frequently mentioned economic concern, namely the difficulty employers are experiencing in finding qualified workers to fill job openings. Business owners in some cases were increasing salaries and benefits to retain workers while others were offering training or turning to automation in lieu of searching for new workers. However, members noted that wage pressures remain “moderate” though they expect wage inflation to pick up soon. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105306732-1530541742841trump_fed.jpg?v=1530541837", "time": "2018-07-03T12:03:44-0400", "author": "Getty Images", "description": "A look at today’s Federal Reserve indicates that President Trump might have little resistance to gaining total control of the central bank. ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/dick-bove-trump-will-eventually-clash-with-the-federal-reserve.html", "title": "Dick Bove: Trump will eventually clash with the Federal Reserve, turning monetary policy into a political activity", "keywords": [{"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Jerome Powell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Washington", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Anthony Kennedy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Larry Kudlow", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the National Economic Council", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Kudlow", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Kudlow", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Republican", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Democrat", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "more than two and half decades", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Kudlow", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "House", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "White Houses", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Harry Truman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Treasury Department", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Truman", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "William McChesney Martin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Great Society", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Johnson", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Martin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Paul Volcker", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Carter", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Treasury", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "James Baker", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Volcker", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Volcker", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Richard Nixon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Nixon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Nixon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Arthur Burns", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Burns", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "G. William Miller", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "less than two years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "today", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "The Federal Reserve Board of Governors", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "7", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Senate", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "4", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "at least two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Senate", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Board", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Federal", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$20 trillion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "7", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "5", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "4.0 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "year-over-year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "25 years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The White House", "category": "ORG"}], "body": " Getty Images Donald Trump and Jerome Powell Washington and the nation are very focused on the fact that Supreme Court Justice Anthony Kennedy has resigned, leaving the high court vulnerable to ideological change. Not really focused upon as much is an offhand remark made by Larry Kudlow, the director of the National Economic Council, in a recent television interview. Mr. Kudlow suggested that he hoped that the Federal Reserve would raise interest rates very slowly. While one might agree or disagree with Mr. Kudlow’s remark (I agree), what is of greater interest is that he made the statement. It breaks a precedent that presidents — Republican and Democrat — have followed for more than two and half decades – i.e., the independence of the Federal Reserve would be respected. Mr. Kudlow understands that he is changing policy. What’s more, he undoubtedly understands that the While House can, and I believe will, take total control of the Federal Reserve. It is very possible that monetary policy will become a political, not an economic or financial decision. Brief history History indicates that while the modern White Houses have not tread on the Fed, prior presidents always did so. Harry Truman fought so hard to force Marriner Eccles (then Fed chairman) to keep interest rates pegged at low levels that there had to be a meeting between the Treasury Department and the Fed to mediate the dispute. Truman ultimately lost. Lyndon Johnson was outraged that William McChesney Martin would raise rates as his Great Society initiative would take place. Johnson also lost as Martin took his “punch bowl away” and raised rates. Jimmy Carter could do nothing as Paul Volcker may have cost Carter his presidency by driving rates so high that the nation suffered back-to-back recessions. Ronald Reagan and his Treasury Secretary James Baker did everything possible to get rid of Volcker. They ultimately had the support of the international financial community and Volcker was not reappointed. Richard Nixon had greatest success in his short confrontation with the Fed. According to the Nixon tapes and the view of most observers then and now, Nixon bent Arthur Burns to the President’s will and easy monetary policies were put in place. Ultimately, when Burns decided to leave the Fed, G. William Miller took his position, but lasted less than two years due to what was considered to be his political leanings. Cake walk A look at today’s Federal Reserve indicates that President Trump might have little resistance to gaining total control of the organization. The Federal Reserve Board of Governors is supposed to have 7 members. It has three. Two of the three have their current positions because they were nominated by the President and approved by the Senate. The President can now nominate 4 more people to the Board. If at least two of these nominees make it through the Senate confirmation hearings, the President will have a durable majority on the Board. What will the president want? Understanding what the President wants from the Fed is not hard. He will want low interest rates for pragmatic and theoretical reasons. Higher interest rates place tremendous strain on the Federal budget with its $20 trillion in debt. Higher rates theoretically can reduce economic growth. The President wants the stock market to continue to rise as a tangible indicator of the success of his economic programs.The Fed has just raised interest rates 7 times and it is being speculated that there could be 5 more increases. It is shrinking the agency’s balance sheet and this is one key factor in the slowdown in money supply growth to 4.0 percent year-over-year or the lowest in 25 years. History argues that after 12 interest rate increases, a possible inverted yield curve, and very weak money supply growth, the stock market will not rise. Finally, it is unlikely that the President will fear higher levels of inflation. High inflation may be the only way to pay down the budget deficit. Conclusion Clearly the control of the Supreme Court is of critical importance, but so is control of the Federal Reserve. It is unclear who will win the Supreme Court battle, but it is not very hard to imagine who will win the struggle to control the Fed. More focus is needed to understand what this will do to the financial system and the economy. (Editor's note: The White House declined to comment.) "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/01/27/104245575-final-trade-logo.jpg?v=1485535953", "time": "2018-07-03T09:08:49-0400", "author": "", "description": "The \"Fast Money\" traders share their first moves for the market open.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/your-first-trade-for-july-3-2018.html", "title": "Your first trade for July 3, 2018", "keywords": [{"term": "JNJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JD & CAR 6:11 PM ET Mon", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "01:00", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "The \"Fast Money\"", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Carter Worth", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Johnson & Johnson Dan Nathan", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JD.com", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Steve Grasso", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Avis Budget Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tim Seymour", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "JD.com Trader", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "July 2, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fast Money", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "the \"Fast Money\"", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dan Nathan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "XLF Sept", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "Dan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Oct", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Steve Grasso", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "AAPL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BABA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CAR", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JCP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "LEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MJNA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MON", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "OSTK", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PFE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RAD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SNAP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SQ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "TWTR", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "VRX", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Grasso", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Callable Trigger", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "SPX", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RTY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MXEA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Grasso", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "EFA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EFG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EWJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "IJR", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SPY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Grasso’s", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "AEL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "COTY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CTL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CUBA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DIA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "F", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GLD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GSK", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "HPQ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "IAU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "IBM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ICE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "LEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MAT", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MJNA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MSFT, NE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "QCOM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RIG", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "SNAP", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "SNGX", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SPY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "WDR", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "WHR", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "XRX", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ZNGA", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tim Seymour", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "APC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BABA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BIDU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BX", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "CCJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CLF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CMG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CRON", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CSCO", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CX", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DAL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DPZ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DVYE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EEM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ERJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EUFN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EWM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FB, FXI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GILD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GOOGL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "GWPH", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "HAL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "INTC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JD", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "LEAF", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "MAT", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MCD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MO", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MOS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MPEL", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "NKE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PHM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PYPL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RH", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "RL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SBUX", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "SQ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "TIF", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "TWTR", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "UA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "UAL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "VALE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "VIAB", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "VOD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "XLE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "XRT", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "YNDX", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "700.HK", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Tim", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "IWM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RACE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SPY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tim", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "BIDU", "category": "ORG"}], "body": " show chapters Final Trade: JNJ, JD & CAR 6:11 PM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 01:00 The \"Fast Money\" traders shared their first moves for the market open. Carter Worth was a buyer of Johnson & Johnson Dan Nathan was a buyer of JD.com Steve Grasso was a buyer of Avis Budget Group Tim Seymour was a seller of JD.com Trader disclosure: On July 2, 2018, the following stocks and commodities mentioned or intended to be mentioned on CNBC's \"Fast Money\" were owned by the \"Fast Money\" traders: Dan Nathan is short SMH. Dan is long XLF Sept put spread. Dan is long FB Aug put spread. Dan is Long T Oct call spread. Steve Grasso is long stock AAPL, BABA, CAR, EVGN, GE, JCP, LEN, MJNA, MON, OSTK, PFE, RAD, SNAP, SQ, T, TSLA, TWTR, VRX. Grasso owns Callable Trigger contingent yield note linked to SPX, RTY, and MXEA. Grasso’s kids own EFA, EFG, EWJ, IJR, SPY. Grasso’s firm is long stock AEL, COTY, CTL, CUBA, DIA, F, GE, GLD, GSK, HPQ, IAU, IBM, ICE, LEN, MAT, MJNA, MSFT, NE, QCOM, RIG, SNAP, SNGX, SPY, T, TMUS, WDR, WHR, XRX, ZNGA. Tim Seymour is long AMZA, ACB.TO, APC, APH.TO, BABA, BAC, BIDU, BX, C, CCJ, CLF, CMG, CRON, CSCO, CX, DAL, DPZ, DVYE, EA, EEM, ERJ, EUFN, EWM, FB, FXI, GE, GILD, GM, GOOGL, GWPH, HAL, INTC, JD, LEAF, MAT, MCD, MO, MOS, MPEL, NKE, PAK, PHM, PYPL, RH, RL, SBUX, SQ, T, TIF, TWTR, UA, UAL, VALE, VIAB, VOD, X, XLE, XRT, YNDX, 700.HK. Tim is short IWM, RACE, SPY. Tim's firm bought BIDU. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/06/26/105294718-1530014393006rtx2zdzs.jpg?v=1530014518", "time": "2018-07-12T10:56:10-0400", "author": "Jonathan Ernst | Reuters", "description": "President Donald Trump criticizes Harley-Davidson on social media, saying his administration is working with other motorcycle companies. ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/03/trump-blasts-harley-davidson-again-says-his-administration-is-workin.html", "title": "Trump knocks Harley-Davidson again, says administration working to bring other motorcycle companies to the US", "keywords": [{"term": "Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1:23 PM ET Tue", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "3 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Administration", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Motor Cycle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the U.S.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "7%", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Twitter", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Last Wednesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "100%", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "America", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "June 25", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about $2,200", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "The European Union", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump administration's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Harley", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Brazil", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Australia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Thailand", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Kansas City", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Missouri", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "York", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Pennsylvania", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "2014", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "five", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Honda", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Yamaha", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Kawasaki", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Polaris", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "UBS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson Harley-Davidson's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "full-year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "7.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the previous year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "10.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Harley-Davidson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Harley", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Evelyn Cheng", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Thomas Franck", "category": "PERSON"}], "body": " show chapters President Trump just knocked Harley-Davidson again 1:23 PM ET Tue, 3 July 2018 | 00:46 President Donald Trump is blasting Harley-Davidson again for announcing it's shifting some operations overseas in the wake of retaliatory EU tariffs against U.S. duties. Trump said Tuesday that his administration is talking with other motorcycle companies about moving to the U.S. “Now that Harley-Davidson is moving part of its operation out of the U.S., my Administration is working with other Motor Cycle companies who want to move into the U.S. Harley customers are not happy with their move - sales are down 7% in 2017. The U.S. is where the Action is!,” Trump said on Twitter. Tweet Link Trump has repeatedly criticized the motorcycle manufacturer recently. Last Wednesday Trump said in a tweet, \"Harley-Davidson should stay 100% in America, with the people that got you your success. I’ve done so much for you, and then this. Other companies are coming back where they belong! We won’t forget, and neither will your customers or your now very HAPPY competitors!\" Harley-Davidson said on June 25 that tariffs implemented by the EU would increase the average cost per motorcycle by about $2,200 and the company will shift some production overseas as a result. The European Union imposed the tariffs in retaliation against the Trump administration's duties on steel and aluminum imports, which were an effort by Trump to protect U.S. jobs. No production will be moving to Europe as a result of the tariffs, according to the company. Harley's overseas manufacturing plants are in Brazil, India, Australia and Thailand. In the U.S., the company is shutting down a Kansas City, Missouri, factory and transferring operations to York, Pennsylvania. In 2014, the top five companies with the largest motorcycle market share in the U.S. were Harley-Davidson, Honda, Yamaha, Kawasaki and Polaris, according to UBS. Source: Harley-Davidson Harley-Davidson's full-year 2017 motorcycle sales declined 7.2 percent from the previous year. The company's U.S. retail motorcycle unit shipments dropped 10.5 percent in the same time period. When asked for comment, a Harley-Davidson spokesperson said all Harley motorcycles sold in the U.S. are made in the U.S. — CNBC's Evelyn Cheng and Thomas Franck contributed to this report. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/23/105226908-GettyImages-961722614.jpg?v=1530556696", "time": "2018-07-02T18:54:02-0400", "author": "Getty Images ", "description": "J.P. Morgan's John Normand believes that a worst-case scenario event whereby all nations raise tariffs by 10 percent could reduce global growth by at least 1.4 percent.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/what-a-full-out-trade-war-would-cost-the-global-economy.html", "title": "What a full out trade war would cost the global economy", "keywords": [{"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan's", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "second", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "John Normand", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "at least 1.4 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the next two years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Normand", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Normand", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "about 0.4 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the United States", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Washington", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "White House", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "5:08 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "01:07", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Canada", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Canadians", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Mexico", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "later this week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the European Union’s", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$3.2 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "June 22", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "25 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump administration's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump’s", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump has for months", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "American", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "seven-month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Commerce Department", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2.1 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "$46.2 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "September", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the second quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan’s Normand", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "recent months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "“Trumponomics", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Marko Kolanovic", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "June", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "more than $1 trillion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "negative 4.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "March", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Kolanovic", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "June", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "$1.25 trillion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "about two-thirds", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Kolanovic", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan's", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "earlier this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "4 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Canada", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "5:06 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Disclaimer", "category": "FAC"}], "body": " Getty Images President Donald Trump A full-blown trade war would punch a hole in global economic growth because of reduced trade volume, supply chain disruptions, and lost confidence. Quantifying just how much damage an entrenched trade battle could wreak upon the international community is a trickier task, but J.P. Morgan has come up with three scenarios. In J.P. Morgan's first model, the U.S. is assumed to raise tariffs on all imports by 10 percentage points, with no retaliation. In the second, the U.S. action is met in equal fashion, with other countries that are the targets of U.S. tariffs imposing a 10-percentage-point increase in tariffs on imports from the U.S. In the third scenario, the entire world raises tariffs by 10 percentage points, a phenomenon J.P. Morgan calls a trade war. John Normand, the bank's head of cross-asset fundamental strategy, said he believes that the third, worst-case scenario could reduce global growth by a “material” amount of at least 1.4 percent over the next two years. Source: J.P. Morgan “Our economists acknowledge that such frameworks underestimate the likely damage that comes through disrupted supply chains, plus the feedback loops from tighter financial conditions,” Normand said in a note to clients last week. “Policy uncertainty has a habit of denting consumer and business confidence, which in turn lowers household and corporate spending. The team’s proprietary, composite measure of developed market business sentiment already shows such a drop, but from above-average levels due to U.S. tax stimulus.” Though Normand acknowledged that those worst-case fears have yet to materialize, the J.P. Morgan researchers added that global growth could slow by about 0.4 percent if countries targeted by the United States respond by slapping equivalent tariffs on Washington. show chapters White House: Trump's tariffs aim to create a fair playing field 5:08 PM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 01:07 That scenario appears more like the one President Donald Trump finds himself stuck in after Canada started collecting duties on a variety of U.S. products on Sunday, including orange juice, yogurt, and whiskey. The Canadians will be reinforced by Mexico and China later this week in responding to the Trump administration’s tariffs when the two countries take aim at the U.S. pork and soybean industries. Meanwhile, the European Union’s initial duties worth $3.2 billion took effect June 22. The majority are duties of 25 percent and include a slew of U.S. products, including motorcycles, boats, whiskey and peanut butter. The three U.S. allies declared the new tariffs in direct response to the Trump administration's choice to levy imported steel and aluminum products. A cornerstone of Trump’s campaign, the U.S.-centric philosophy remains key to the president’s economic program in office. Trump has for months used his pulpit and economic tariffs to try to effect change in trade deals the administration deems unfair and ultimately harmful to American economic interests. Calling for “fair and reciprocal” trade relationships, Trump has promised to dissolve the new U.S. tariffs only after more favorable deals are struck with trading allies. tweet Trump's battle for more balanced trade could end up helping the economy. The trade deficit appears to be on the decline, falling to a seven-month low in April, according to the Commerce Department. The trade gap dropped 2.1 percent to $46.2 billion, the smallest since September. If the trend continues, trade could contribute to gross domestic product in the second quarter, buoyed by strength in the manufacturing sector and consumer spending. The warning from J.P. Morgan’s Normand, however, represents just the latest iteration in a string of cautious notes from the bank's analysts in recent months detailing the possible dangers of “Trumponomics.” Marko Kolanovic, the bank’s head of quantitative strategy, estimated in June that the Trump’s tough trade tactics have caused the destruction of more than $1 trillion in market value. \"By attributing the trade-related news flow (positive or negative) to the performance of the U.S. market, we estimated the impact on U.S. equities to be negative 4.5 percent\" since March, Kolanovic said in his June note. \"Taking the current market capitalization, this translates into $1.25 trillion of value destruction for U.S. companies. For a comparison, this is about two-thirds of the value of total fiscal stimulus.\" Kolanovic, who heads J.P. Morgan's global quantitative and derivatives strategy, predicted the stock market correction earlier this year and highlighted complacency and high leverage in the market as warning signs. Further, the strategist highlighted the impact of trade and protectionist ideology as \"significant\" market headwinds. \"A negotiation strategy that includes bluffing/threats can be successful in a two-party negotiation setup, but is more likely to deliver self-defeating results in a complex system such as global trade,\" he said. \"The value destroyed by a trade war might be reversible if policies are reversed, while the positive impact of fiscal measures is likely to remain. This would likely catalyze a rough 4 percent market rally.\" WATCH: Who loses from the ketchup tariff show chapters Canada's ketchup tariff will hurt food service businesses the most: Analyst 5:06 PM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 04:43 Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105303750-1530560281925tesla_cars.jpg?v=1539369037", "time": "2018-07-02T16:19:18-0400", "author": "David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "description": "CFRA Research lowers its rating to sell from hold for Tesla shares, citing the stock’s valuation.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/tesla-drops-after-analyst-says-its-production-rate-is-not-sustainable.html", "title": "Tesla downgraded to sell by CFRA, which predicts Model 3 production rate is not 'sustainable'", "keywords": [{"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "8:01 AM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "05:57 CFRA Research", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "one-week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "5,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "the last week of the June quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "second-quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "40,740", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "approximately 51,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Herculean", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "albeit a few hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "5,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Efraim Levy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "2.3 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the beginning of Monday’s session", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Levy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "12-month", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "300", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "12.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "10 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Roger McNamee", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "11:50 AM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "04:24 Disclaimer", "category": "LOC"}], "body": " show chapters Tesla makes Model 3 production push 8:01 AM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 05:57 CFRA Research does not believe Tesla will be able to maintain its Model 3 production rate over the short term. The firm lowered its rating to sell from hold for Tesla shares, citing the stock’s valuation. Tesla said on Monday that the carmaker reached its one-week production goal of 5,000 Model 3 cars for the last week of the June quarter. But the company fell short on its second-quarter deliveries by posting 40,740 vehicles delivered versus the Wall Street consensus of approximately 51,000. “After Herculean efforts and albeit a few hours after a self-imposed deadline, Tesla finally achieved its latest goal to reach production of 5,000 Model 3 sedans per week. In the interim, we do not see this production rate as operationally or financially sustainable,” analyst Efraim Levy said in a note to clients Monday. Tesla shares declined 2.3 percent after the report after opening up 5 percent at the beginning of Monday’s session. Levy reiterated his 12-month $300 price target for Tesla shares, representing 12.5 percent downside to Friday’s close. The company's shares are up 10 percent this year through Friday versus the S&P 500’s 2 percent gain. Tesla did not immediately respond to a request for comment. WATCH: What Tesla needs to do to sustain value show chapters If Tesla can combine real manufacturing with the brand they will sustain value for a while, says Roger McNamee 11:50 AM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 04:24 Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/03/105309478-1530635233704img_7389.jpg?v=1530635299", "time": "2018-07-03T12:58:49-0400", "author": "Source: Joseph Voboril ", "description": "A fired ex-Bank of America executive is hitting a back at the firm with a claim for wrongful termination and defamation, seeking $20 million.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/ex-bank-of-america-exec-claims-wrongful-termination-defamation.html", "title": "Ex-Bank of America exec claims wrongful termination, defamation and seeks at least $20 million", "keywords": [{"term": "Ron Antonelli", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "as an ordinary night", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "six", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the holidays", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "mid-December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Lower East Side", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Et Al", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "weeks", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "late February", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Malik’s", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "One", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Joe Voboril", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "39-year-old", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "more than $20 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Hollywood", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "MeToo", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$100 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Harold Ford", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Morgan Stanley", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Brian Kennedy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "MeToo", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bill Halldin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Charlotte", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "North Carolina", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "September 2015", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "San Francisco", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Joseph Voboril Joseph Voboril", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Martina Slowey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "London", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Slowey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Series", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "24", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "BrokerCheck.org", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Slowey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "” Bank of America's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Halldin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "New York", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "John Singer", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik’s", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Singer", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Middle Eastern", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Slowey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FINRA", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "early January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "about the night of", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Dec. 13-14", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "about 9 p.m.", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "6 p.m.", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "the night", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Et Al", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Days later", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "About a month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "four", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Feb. 28", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Kennedy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Kennedy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "fourth", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "60", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "350", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "weeks", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Feb. 28", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Malik’s", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "30 days later", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "One", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Malik", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Voboril", "category": "GPE"}], "body": " Ron Antonelli | Bloomberg | Getty Images It began as an ordinary night for six Bank of America employees, who were out to celebrate the holidays. In mid-December, the members of the firm’s prime brokerage — a division that caters to hedge funds — had gathered at an intimate Lower East Side lounge called Et Al after leaving the team’s gift-exchange party around the corner. They danced, drank and mingled with the club’s dozens of other patrons. Within weeks, Omeed Malik, the most senior of the bank's employees at the impromptu event, left Bank of America. Soon after, media reports indicated the bank had investigated an accusation of inappropriate behavior by Malik that was lodged by one of the other employees present that night. But within months, the witnesses were also gone. Two of them left recently. But before that, in late February, reports surfaced that the two other employees were let go after the bank determined they “interfered” with the probe into Malik’s behavior. One of them, Joe Voboril, a 39-year-old former director within the prime brokerage unit, is fighting back, saying he did no such thing. He filed a claim on Friday alleging that Bank of America had retaliated against, wrongfully terminated and defamed him. The claim was filed with the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, a self-policing regulatory body for financial firms. Voboril, who says in the claim the bank ruined his reputation and stymied several opportunities for positions within Bank of America or at hedge funds, is seeking more than $20 million in damages, attorney’s fees and to have his record cleared. CNBC reviewed his claim, which will be handled through arbitration, outside the public domain. Voboril declined to comment. After a series of prominent men in Hollywood and on television were ensnared in the #MeToo movement, in which detailed accounts of abuse from victims emerged, some in the media wondered aloud when the spotlight would turn to Wall Street. But many of the high-profile cases on Wall Street have been met by bankers who are fighting back against claims of inappropriate behavior. Malik, in his own FINRA claim against Bank of America, is seeking $100 million for what he says was defamation tied to his dismissal. Harold Ford, a onetime senator-turned-investment banker at Morgan Stanley, was reportedly fired last year after a journalist said he harassed her. The firm ultimately put out a statement saying that he was not terminated due to sexual misconduct. Voboril’s attorney, Brian Kennedy, says that his client was collateral damage in Bank of America’s move to use the #MeToo movement to remove employees. “We stand by our decision to terminate Mr. Voboril,” said Bill Halldin, a spokesman for Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of America. “We will review the filing when we receive it.” In his 60-page claim, Voboril paints the picture of a toxic culture within the bank's equities division. Voboril began at Bank of America in September 2015; he was recruited from a San Francisco-based firm to help Malik bring in new clients to their unit, which works with hedge funds to finance their various trades — including borrowing shares to sell short and bundling securities for sale. Source: Joseph Voboril Joseph Voboril By aligning with Malik, Voboril says in the claim that he immediately made an enemy of Martina Slowey, who ultimately became his direct supervisor within the firm. The claim says she reduced his responsibilities and his compensation, despite positive performance reviews. Both Malik and Voboril raised concerns that London-based Slowey did not have the appropriate FINRA licenses to be managing them — FINRA requires all individuals acting in a supervisory capacity to pass a so-called Series 24 exam. A search of FINRA’s public database, BrokerCheck.org., did not turn up anyone with her name. Slowey didn’t respond to a request for comment, and Bank of America declined to make her available. “The bank had appropriate supervisory structures at all times,” Bank of America's Halldin said. Malik is pursuing his own arbitration claim against the firm, alleging defamation, breach of contract and unjust enrichment over the cancellation of his bonus. He is planning to file a separate suit against Bank of America in New York state court, his attorney said. “Mr. Malik was terminated by the bank not as a result of any of the sham and defamatory reasoning that the bank has noted to its primary regulator and to the news media, but rather, because he had complained about his direct supervisor being bereft of the requisite FINRA licensing,” said John Singer, Malik’s attorney. In firing Malik, “the bank illegally retaliated against Mr. Malik and illegally discriminated against him on the basis of his race, religion and national origin,” Singer said of Malik, who is of Middle Eastern descent. Voboril alleges in his claim that Bank of America was telling FINRA regulators that Malik was his manager, while in the firm’s internal organizational chart, Slowey served as his manager. FINRA declined to comment on the case. These are the grounds in which Voboril believes the bank retaliated. In early January, Voboril was called in to meet with Bank of America’s employee-relations staff who inquired about the night of Dec. 13-14. Voboril got to the gift-exchange party at about 9 p.m. after putting his two children to bed, rejoining colleagues who had been drinking since 6 p.m., according to a person with knowledge of the night. He left Et Al at about 2 a.m. Voboril told them that he hadn’t seen anything inappropriate from Malik or anyone else. Days later, employee relations called Voboril in again and asked him if he wanted to change his account. Others who had attended the party had a different recollection, he was told, and sticking to his original version would have negative repercussions, according to the claim. He replied that he had told the truth from the beginning. About a month after Malik was terminated, Voboril was called in for a third time by employee relations for questioning. He was asked if he wanted to change his story since Malik was gone, and he said no — that he had been telling the truth from the beginning. Of the four witnesses to any potential misconduct, two were put on leave (Voboril and a younger associate). Both were terminated on Feb. 28. Bank of America’s “false statement that Mr. Voboril and another 26-year-old female employee were terminated for ‘interfering’ with a sham review about yet another employee’s personal conduct was merely a convenient cover for the firm,” said Kennedy, Voboril’s lawyer. Kennedy said that of the remaining two witnesses, one of them changed his story to appease the bank. It’s unclear what the fourth witness saw or said. These remaining two employees were given high-profile roles in a Feb. 18 Bank of America conference in front of 60 of the firm's biggest hedge fund clients and 350 of its largest investors, according to the claim. Then, within weeks, both employees left Bank of America to join hedge funds. Within hours of hearing that he had been fired on Feb. 28, Voboril was contacted by reporters who said that sources told them that he and a colleague were let go for interfering with Malik’s investigation. Since the filing with similar language — “interfering” with an investigation — was filed 30 days later, Voboril’s claim alleges that the bank may have been involved in informing reporters about the dismissals. Soon, articles linking him to the investigation into Malik were online. One piece cited sources saying that bank officials believed Malik and his former colleagues were coordinating stories to throw off investigators. Voboril remains unemployed and says he is thinking about starting his own business. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105303750-1530560281925tesla_cars.jpg?v=1539369037", "time": "2018-07-03T15:32:37-0400", "author": "David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "description": "Goldman Sachs is not impressed with Tesla's production announcement and reiterates its sell rating for the company's shares, noting a decline in net Model 3 reservations from last year.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/03/wall-street-is-still-worried-over-tesla-model-3-demand.html", "title": "Street is not impressed by Tesla's Model 3 milestone; stock plunges 7% on negative notes, brake test report", "keywords": [{"term": "David Paul Morris", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images Tesla", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Fremont", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "California", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Wednesday, June 20, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "one-week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "5,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "the last week of the June quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "second-quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "40,740", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "approximately 51,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "7.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "final days", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "2:26 PM ET Tue", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "3", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "00:52 “", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2.3 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the beginning of that day’s", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tuesdaythat Tesla", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Model S", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Goldman Sachs", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "420,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "455,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "David Tamberrino", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "195", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "six-month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "42 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "second-quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2Q", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ryan Brinkman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Brinkman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "180", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Top Tesla", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "3", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "5:54 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Citi Research", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "today", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "FCF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Itay Michaeli", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Michaeli", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "313", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "450", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "5,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the final week of the quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the second half of the year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Romit Shah", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "8 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "this year through Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "second-quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "5,031", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model 3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "the last seven days of the quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "1,913", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Model S", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Michael Bloom", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Tesla", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "4:14 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "2 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}], "body": " David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images Tesla vehicles are transported on a truck after leaving the company's manufacturing facility in Fremont, California, on Wednesday, June 20, 2018. Several Wall Street firms are playing down Tesla's Model 3 production milestone, remaining skeptical over the carmaker's finances and demand trends. Tesla said Monday it reached its one-week production goal of 5,000 Model 3 cars for the last week of the June quarter. But the company fell short on its second-quarter deliveries by posting 40,740 vehicles delivered versus the Wall Street consensus expectation of approximately 51,000. Tesla shares fell 7.2 percent Tuesday. The company's shares hit the lows of the day on a report it decided to skip a \"brake-and-roll\" testing step in the manufacturing of its Model 3 vehicles. Tesla did eliminate the brake test because it deemed it to be redundant. show chapters Tesla eliminated brake tests in final days of Model 3 production 2:26 PM ET Tue, 3 July 2018 | 00:52 “Every car we build goes through rigorous quality checks and must meet exacting specifications, including brake tests. To be extremely clear, we drive *every* Model 3 on our test track to verify braking, torque, squeal and rattle. There are no exceptions,” the company told CNBC. The carmaker's shares declined 2.3 percent on Monday after opening up 5 percent at the beginning of that day’s session. Reuters also reported on Tuesdaythat Tesla shifted workers from other departments including the Model S production line to meet its Model 3 production target. Goldman Sachs was not impressed with the company’s announcement and reiterated its sell rating for Tesla shares, noting net Model 3 reservations declined to 420,000 from 455,000 last year. “Model 3 deliveries did miss our bearish estimates and we see the incremental color on Model 3 net reservations (where the company showed its first declining data point) as incrementally negative,” analyst David Tamberrino said in a note to clients Tuesday. Tamberrino reiterated his $195 six-month price target for Tesla shares, representing 42 percent downside to Monday’s close. One Wall Street analyst believes Tesla shares will drop further when the company reports its second-quarter earnings. “Given the softer overall trend to deliveries and implied negative read-across to 2Q earnings and cash flow, we expect a negative reaction in TSLA shares,” J.P. Morgan analyst Ryan Brinkman said a note to clients Tuesday. Brinkman reiterated his underweight rating and $180 price target for the carmaker’s shares. show chapters Top Tesla watcher's 3 big predictions 5:54 PM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 11:11 In similar fashion, Citi Research reaffirmed its “neutral/high risk” rating Tesla shares, saying Monday’s production announcement doesn’t significantly change the company’s finances. “We don’t believe today’s update will settle bull/bear debates about sustainable production/demand, FCF generating ability and the risks tied to Tesla’s balance sheet position,” analyst Itay Michaeli said in a note to clients Monday. Michaeli reaffirmed his $313 price target for Tesla shares. To be sure, not everyone on Wall Street is negative on Tesla’s prospects. Nomura Instinet reiterated its buy rating and $450 price target for Tesla shares on Monday. “Tesla hit its production target of 5,000 Model 3’s in the final week of the quarter, which is an important milestone that we believe reestablishes some credibility and positions the company for profitability in the second half of the year,” analyst Romit Shah said in a note. “That said, we continue to expect TSLA shares to be volatile near term; we see current weakness as an opportunity to further accumulate shares.” The company's shares are up 8 percent this year through Monday versus the S&P 500’s 2 percent gain. When asked for comment, a Tesla spokesperson referred to the company's second-quarter vehicle production press release, which said the electric car maker produced 5,031 Model 3 vehicles in the last seven days of the quarter, while also producing 1,913 Model S and X vehicles in the same period. — CNBC's Michael Bloom contributed to this story. WATCH: Analysts argue over Tesla production numbers show chapters Analysts feud over Tesla production numbers 4:14 PM ET Mon, 2 July 2018 | 02:46 Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/11/21/104856193-GettyImages-664082360.jpg?v=1530814773", "time": "2018-07-05T15:09:02-0400", "author": "Getty Images", "description": "The bull market underway in equities is like a “fine wine” — it’s great, but it isn’t getting any better, according to American Century Investments' Richard Weiss.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/05/economic-conditions-not-a-recipe-for-a-bull-market-money-manager.html", "title": "Money manager isn't buying on dips, says conditions ‘not ripe for a bull market’", "keywords": [{"term": "2:05 PM ET Thu", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "5", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Richard Weiss", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "American Century Investments", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "“Power Lunch", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Thursday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "$169 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Getty Images", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "nine-year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Wednesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Citigroup", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "only three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "9 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the next 12 months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Citi", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Margie Patel", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo Asset Management", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "“Power Lunch", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "the year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2019", "category": "DATE"}], "body": " show chapters Citi: Global market rally isn't close to ending 2:05 PM ET Thu, 5 July 2018 | 03:59 The bull market underway in equities is like a “fine wine” — it’s great, but it isn’t getting any better, according to Richard Weiss, chief investment officer of multiasset strategies at American Century Investments. That’s why right now he’s not buying on the dips. “Decelerating economic growth, equity valuations fair at best, rising interest rates, the specter of inflation — this is not a recipe for a bull market,” he told CNBC’s “Power Lunch” on Thursday. In fact, his firm, which has $169 billion in assets under management, is neutral to underweight in stocks, particularly for those investors near or in retirement. Within the equity portfolio, he said he’ll likely be rotating from growth stocks to consumer staples and other defensive sectors. Getty Images While Weiss isn’t alone in getting defensive as the nine-year bull market marches on, others are more positive. On Wednesday, Citigroup’s equity strategy team advised clients to continue to buy. They wrote in a note to clients that Citi’s bear market checklist that monitors symptoms of a downturn in stocks suggests that only three of 18 “red flags” have been raised. The strategists still see a 9 percent climb in global equities over the next 12 months. “It is still too early to call the end of this bull market,” the Citi researchers said. “So keep buying the dips. Late cycle bull markets typically narrow into growth and momentum trades. This should favor U.S. equities and information technology stocks.” Margie Patel, senior portfolio manager at Wells Fargo Asset Management, is also confident about the equity market and called recent trade war fears a “minor issue.” She believes people are underinvested in the market right now, looking for a big correction. But she doesn’t think that correction is coming. “People are underestimating the very strong sustainable growth here in the U.S. economy and a lot of the countries worldwide,” she told “Power Lunch.” She anticipates a “lull” in the stock market with a “sideways up and down choppy trading range” before it has a “strong finish” for the rest of the year into 2019 thanks to strong corporate earnings. Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/03/105308881-1530620818987gettyimages-878128942.jpeg?v=1530620860", "time": "2018-07-03T13:18:19-0400", "author": "Luke Sharrett | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "description": "Roku stock is primed for a comeback as the online streaming platform starts to leverage its role as a leading over-the-top television provider, Oppenheimer says.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/03/roku-shares-jump-on-oppenheimer-upgrade.html", "title": "Roku shares jump on Oppenheimer upgrade", "keywords": [{"term": " Luke Sharrett |", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Insignia Roku TV", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Best Buy Co.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Louisville", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Kentucky", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Oppenheimer", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Oppenheimer", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Jason Helfstein", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Los Gatos", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "California", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Roku Channel", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "roughly 21 million", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "$19 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Apple TV", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Chromecast", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "last fall", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "hundreds", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "The Roku Channel", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Netflix", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "The Roku Channel", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Samsung", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "OTT", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Helfstein", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "5.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Oppenheimer", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "roughly 16 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "1.1 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Helfstein", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "50", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "15.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the next 12 to 18 months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "as much as $19 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "14", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Roku", "category": "PERSON"}], "body": " Luke Sharrett | Bloomberg | Getty Images A shopper carries an Insignia Roku TV television at a Best Buy Co. store in Louisville, Kentucky, U.S., Roku stock is primed for a comeback as the online streaming platform starts to leverage its role as a leading over-the-top television provider, Oppenheimer says. Oppenheimer analyst Jason Helfstein on Monday upgraded shares of the Los Gatos, California-based pay TV company to outperform from perform, advising clients that the company's homegrown Roku Channel will likely help add to its roughly 21 million customers in the U.S. and capture $19 billion in revenue potential. The company, which continues to offer an easy way to access the top streaming services like rivals Apple TV and Chromecast, launched its own channel for users of Roku streaming players last fall, connecting customers to hundreds of movies and some TV shows they can stream for free. The Roku Channel includes content it licenses directly from film and television studios as well as content compiled from publishers, pitting the company against streaming giant Netflix. “The rapid adoption of The Roku Channel gives us incremental confidence in the channel's ability to garner viewership on other platforms, such as Samsung, allowing Roku to monetize a broader portion of the OTT ecosystem than we had previously assumed was possible,” Helfstein wrote. Roku should be able to wield “its advantages in pricing and merchandising to remain the market leader in consumer-facing connected television solutions.” Roku shares rose 5.2 percent Tuesday following the Oppenheimer note. The company's stock is down roughly 16 percent in 2018 through Monday versus the S&P 500's 1.1 percent return. Helfstein set a price target of $50 on Roku shares, implying 15.5 percent upside over the next 12 to 18 months. Much of that upside, he wrote, will come from the company’s ability to drive video advertising revenue, which could total as much as $19 billion given its expected market share. The stock went public last September at $14 a share. “Roku’s business today is generating users for the Roku platform, either on a Roku Player or the Smart TV Roku OS, and monetizing its partners’ content, either by taking a share of subscription video on demand/advertising video on demand revenue or selling subscription video on demand advertisements itself and sharing the revenue with its partners,” the analyst added. Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2014/04/23/101607223-Aeron.jpg?v=1530564207", "time": "2018-07-02T17:13:40-0400", "author": "Source: Herman Miller", "description": "See which stocks are posting big moves after the bell on Monday.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/stocks-making-biggest-moves-after-hours-mlhr-acxm--more.html", "title": "After-hours buzz: MLHR, ACXM & more", "keywords": [{"term": "Herman Miller", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Herman Miller", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "more than 11 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "fourth-quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "66 cents", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "58 cents", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Herman Miller", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "$618 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "$601 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Acxiom", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "17 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Interpublic Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$2.3 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Best Buy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "more than 1 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Richfield", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Minnesota", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Centene Corporation", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Centene", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "$3.75 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Fidelis Care", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Centene", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "New York", "category": "GPE"}], "body": " Source: Herman Miller Check out the companies making headlines after the bell: Herman Miller stock surged more than 11 percent in extended trading. The furniture company reported fourth-quarter earnings of 66 cents a share, besting analyst estimates for 58 cents a share. Herman Miller also posted revenue of $618 million, better than the $601 million expected. Shares of Acxiom rocketed 17 percent in after-hours trading. The database marketing company announced Monday that it has agreed to sell its marketing solutions department to Interpublic Group for $2.3 billion on Monday. Shares of Best Buy slid more than 1 percent in late trading. The Richfield, Minnesota-based company recently stopped selling CDs in an effort to phase out old technology. Centene Corporation slipped 2 percent in extended trading. On Monday, Centene said it has completed its $3.75 billion deal with Fidelis Care. The latter is now Centene's health plan in the state of New York. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/06/21/104542613-IMG_3798.JPG?v=1530567782", "time": "2018-07-02T18:13:53-0400", "author": "Anjali Sundara | CNBC", "description": "Mark Mobius says it’s time to be looking at emerging market valuations, noting that some of the currencies are looking “very, very cheap.”", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/mark-mobius-sees-opportunities-after-trade-fears-hit-emerging-markets.html", "title": "Investor Mark Mobius sees opportunities after trade fears hit emerging markets", "keywords": [{"term": "30 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "3:52 AM ET Tue", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "3 July 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "04:28", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Mark Mobius", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Mobius Capital Partners", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "“Closing Bell", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "iShares", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "more than 7 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the last month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Mobius", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trump “", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "’s", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the last 20 or 30 years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bangladesh", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Turkey", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Vietnam", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Mobius", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}], "body": " show chapters 30 percent decline in emerging markets an opportunity: Mobius 3:52 AM ET Tue, 3 July 2018 | 04:28 Emerging markets have sold off on trade war fears, and for noted investor Mark Mobius that means it could be time to buy. “There is concern about these markets and what’s happening. But what a lot of people forget is that this opens up opportunities,” the co-founder of Mobius Capital Partners said on CNBC’s “Closing Bell” on Monday. He says it’s time to be looking at valuations, noting that some of the currencies are looking “very, very cheap.” The iShares MSCI Emerging Markets ETF is down more than 7 percent in the last month as rhetoric on trade has heated up. President Donald Trump is going after what he calls unfair trade practices and has announced or threatened tariffs on several countries, including U.S. allies. He’s specifically called out China, slapping it with a number of measures. The targeted nations have all promised to strike back, with some retaliatory tariffs already now in effect. Mobius said he agreed with Trump “completely” when it comes to China and its trade deficit with the U.S. “The U.S. has been taken for a ride, let’s face it, over the last 20 or 30 years,” he said. He said there are opportunities to be found in countries such as Bangladesh, Turkey and Vietnam because they will replace China in exporting to the U.S. “These are all big producers of garments and shoes and the kind of consumer goods” China exports, Mobius pointed out. He says that in the end the U.S. will “win” by getting some concessions from China, as well as a reduction in the trade deficit. “The U.S. is the biggest importer in the world,” he said. “China needs the U.S.” Disclaimer "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105305644-1530505322084gettyimages-486318608.jpg?v=1530505525", "time": "2018-07-03T21:51:59-0400", "author": "Pradeep Gaur | Mint | Getty Images", "description": "State lenders have the highest exposure to soured loans of as much as $150 billion in India's banking sector.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/06/28/india-banking-crisis-experts-say-growth-opportunity-for-private-banks.html", "title": "India's massive state banks are in trouble. That's great news for some", "keywords": [{"term": " Pradeep Gaur", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "State Bank Of India", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Syndicate Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Canara Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "New Delhi", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "about 70 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "as much as $150 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "about 8.26 trillion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "$120 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Dec. 31", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about 1.1 trillion", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "10-year", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "30 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "60 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Sukumar Rajah", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Franklin Templeton Emerging Markets Equity", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the Reserve Bank of India's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PCA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Sanjeev Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Kotak Institutional Equities", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PCA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "recent years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "AM ET Thu", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "5 April 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "02:27", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Franklin Templeton's", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Rajah", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Indian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "the [Reserve Bank of India", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Rajah", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "nearly $14 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "20", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "March", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "last October", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "about $33 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "two years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Reserve Bank of India", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "February", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "second", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Punjab National Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$2 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "several years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the next few quarters", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Earlier this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tata Steel", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bhushan Steel", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "352 billion", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "$5.14 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "nearly two-thirds", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "enterprise]-type", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "NPL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "3:16 AM ET Fri", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "1 June 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "02:39", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Prasad", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Outlook for the banking sector", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Indian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "the next few years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Geeta Chugh", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "S&P.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "over 4 years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Harsh Modi", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan's", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Asia", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Japan", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Indian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Modi", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "between 12 to 18 months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Modi", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}], "body": " Pradeep Gaur | Mint | Getty Images Branches of State Bank Of India, Syndicate Bank and Canara Bank in New Delhi, India. India's banking sector crisis has left most state lenders hamstrung with mounting levels of bad loans, investigations into fraud and restricted growth opportunities. Amid that storm, private banks are set to emerge as winners. India's public-sector financial institutions control about 70 percent of all banking assets in the country, but they have the highest exposure to soured loans amounting to as much as $150 billion. In fact, the 21 state-owned banks had stressed loans of about 8.26 trillion rupees ($120 billion) as of Dec. 31, Reuters reported. Private sector lenders, meanwhile, reportedly had a bad loan pile of just about 1.1 trillion rupees. Private banks are more competitive Experts believe that, over the years, private sector banks will likely gain more market share from their state-run counterparts because they have stronger balance sheets, they are less exposed to stressed sectors, have stronger governance and are more competitive. \"If you take a 10-year view, currently the private sector banks' market share is 30 percent. Probably it will become 60 percent,\" Sukumar Rajah, senior managing director at Franklin Templeton Emerging Markets Equity, told CNBC. As a result, he said, \"the overall health of the banking system will improve because the better banks will be a bigger portion of the market and the weaker banks will become a smaller portion of the market.\" Public sector banks are already losing market share, particularly the 11 banks that are placed on the Reserve Bank of India's prompt corrective action (PCA) framework, according to Sanjeev Prasad, co-head at Kotak Institutional Equities. That framework is used by the central bank to assess risks associated with banks based on capital, asset quality and profitability. When a bank is placed on the PCA, its ability to lend is restricted. Beyond that, reports have suggested that public sector banks might struggle to hold onto their share of the deposits market. But the question worth asking is whether India's private banks have enough deposits to do the heavy lifting to meet the funding requirements of one of the world's fastest growing major economies, Prasad said. Private banks have expanded their loan books in recent years and many of them have been running at \"really high credit-to-deposit ratios,\" he said. A credit-to-deposit ratio is usually used to measure a bank's liquidity by comparing its total loans to its total deposits. If the ratio is too high, it means the bank is lending out a large share of the deposits it has received. That might suggest potential liquidity problems during a downturn. show chapters A look at India's banking sector 4:27 AM ET Thu, 5 April 2018 | 02:27 India needs to work out a way to move deposits from public sector banks to private lenders, Prasad added. Still, there are alternative means of funding available to satisfy financing demands from companies and individuals. \"My view is that, incrementally, a lot of long-term financing of corporate India can also be met by the corporate bond market, which has developed reasonably well,\" he said. \"Between the corporate bond market and the private banks, I think most of the requirements can be met as far as corporate India is concerned.\" When it comes to lending directly to individuals, Prasad said that is mostly done by the private banks and non-banking financial companies. Why state-lenders are in trouble For years, state-owned banks have funded projects in sectors like steel, power and infrastructure that were not the best in class and they later became non-performing assets when the business cycle turned, Franklin Templeton's Rajah said. But unlike in the past, the current Indian government is a lot less willing to bail out the troubled banks by just recapitalizing them. Instead, it is pushing for greater structural changes. \"This government has taken a harder stance along with the [Reserve Bank of India], saying that 'you know this is a structural issue, we can't keep bailing out these banks.' It's too much of a waste of public money,\" Rajah said. He explained that the government would not allow state lenders to default, but it is also not going to guarantee profitability. Still, in January, the government said it would disburse nearly $14 billion into 20 public banks by March in exchange for them implementing reforms. That was part of a broader undertaking announced last October, where the government said it would inject about $33 billion into its state-run lenders over two years. Following that, the Reserve Bank of India tightened guidelines for banks to resolve bad assets in February. Under the new rules, banks are not able to use loan restructuring schemes to delay recognizing bad debt. As a result, banks' profitability took a hit as they had to declare many existing loans as non-performing assets and required higher loan loss provisions — they are counted as expenses that banks set aside as allowance for uncollected loans and loan payments. State lenders have also been plagued by fraud. For example, India's second-largest state lender Punjab National Bank said rogue employees orchestrated a massive $2 billion fraud over several years. The real challenge Experts agreed that declaration of non-performing assets by the banks was coming to an end over the next few quarters. But there are challenges ahead as banks begin to recover bad loans. Earlier this year, Tata Steel bought the insolvent Bhushan Steel for 352 billion rupees ($5.14 billion), which reportedly was nearly two-thirds of the loans the company owed to its lenders. \"So far, it seems to be going ahead,\" Prasad said. \"Real challenge will come when it comes to the next lot of the assets, which are the power companies and also the smaller [small-medium enterprise]-type businesses.\" He explained that it's unlikely that the troubled power companies are going to find willing buyers because the sector still has issues around distribution. Smaller companies are going to face the same problem and the only willing buyers are likely to be the current owners of the businesses, he added. Last year, India amended its insolvency and bankruptcy code, preventing willful defaulters from buying up any of their own troubled assets at discounted rates. show chapters The NPL issues are still 'dogging' India's banks: Economist 3:16 AM ET Fri, 1 June 2018 | 02:39 \"The problem is, if they don't amend the law, which currently bars promoters [company leaders] from putting in a bid for that asset, then many of these smaller companies will have to be liquidated,\" Prasad said, adding that would have socioeconomic implications in terms of job losses. \"The government will have to think through some of the issues,\" he added. \"They will have to strike some balance, in terms of maybe allowing the smaller companies or promoters to also bid for the same asset.\" Outlook for the banking sector The recognition of and the quick pace of resolution for non-performing assets will strengthen Indian banks over the next few years, according to Geeta Chugh, a senior director at S&P. \"Before the new bankruptcy code, the recovery rates in India were low at around 26 [percent] and it took over 4 years to recover,\" she told CNBC, referring to the portion of defaulted debt and interest that lenders could get back when a borrower became insolvent. She added that recovery in hard asset-backed sectors like steel would be much higher compared to companies in the engineering, procurement and construction industries. Harsh Modi, J.P. Morgan's co-head of Asia ex Japan banks equity research, explained that the retail-focused part of the banking system will likely continue to do well given that the credit penetration in Indian households is still very low and the growing economy will create a \"structural tailwind to the retail business.\" But the corporate lending business — that is, dealing with the bad loans — will be more event driven, Modi told CNBC. He explained that many of the non-performing assets have been recognized, but resolution will take time. It could take between 12 to 18 months to fully clean up India's banking sector, he added. Modi also explained that India's new bankruptcy laws remove subjectivity in the resolution process. \"It's as institutional and objective as it can get. That's the reason why we're reasonably hopeful that ... once it gets done, we can move on to the next phase of growth,\" he said. — Reuters contributed to this report. "}, {"urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/07/02/105306790-1530543219562gettyimages-930174444.jpeg?v=1530543259", "time": "2018-07-02T15:37:09-0400", "author": "David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "description": "Dell Technologies owners Michael Dell and Silver Lake get some benefits out of Monday's deal to buy back Dell's tracking stock, but the real goal -- owning all of WMware -- remains elusive.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/07/02/michael-dell-did-not-get-all-of-vmware.html", "title": "Michael Dell did not get what he really wanted: All of VMware", "keywords": [{"term": "David Paul Morris", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images Michael Dell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dell Inc.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "South", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Southwest", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "SXSW", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Austin", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Texas", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Saturday, March 10, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Dell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "VMware", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Dell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "82 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "VMware", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "50 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "32 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Michael Dell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Silver Lake", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Dell's DHI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The remaining 18 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "VMware", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "82 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "VMware", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Michael Dell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "VMware 10:56 AM ET Mon", "category"