[{"time": "2018-05-14T07:41:40-0400", "body": " Giulia Marchi | Bloomberg | Getty Images Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase & Co., sits ahead of a Bloomberg Television interview on the sidelines of the JP Morgan Global China Summit in Beijing, China, on Tuesday, May 8, 2018. J.P. Morgan Chase & Co said on Monday it had appointed Mark Leung as the chief executive of its China business. A veteran who's been with the bank for 21 years, Leung will manage onshore and offshore activities in the country. He started his career in rates derivatives trading and has held trading roles in emerging Markets, credit hybrids and equity derivatives. Additionally, JPMorgan announced it had submitted an application to the Chinese securities regulator for setting up a new onshore securities business in which the U.S. bank would own a 51 percent stake. It's also looking to double its research coverage of China-listed companies across all sectors, the bank said. The bank's asset and wealth management unit is working on increasing its current joint venture stake to a majority interest, subject to an agreement with its joint venture partner and the relevant authorities, it said in a statement. The submission of the application to the regulator marks a step towards JPMorgan's return to China securities business after 2016 when it sold its 33 percent holding in a similar venture to its local partner. — Reuters contributed reporting. ", "author": "Giulia Marchi | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/jp-morgan-submits-application-for-majority-owned-china-securities-business.html", "keywords": [{"term": " Giulia Marchi", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images Jamie Dimon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bloomberg Television", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the JP Morgan Global China Summit", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Beijing", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tuesday, May 8, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan Chase & Co", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Mark Leung", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "21 years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Leung", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Markets", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JPMorgan", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "51 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "JPMorgan", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "2016", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "33 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "JPMorgan Chase on Monday announced it has appointed Mark Leung as its new China CEO.", "title": "JPMorgan Chase names a new China CEO", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/08/105192955-GettyImages-955782672.jpg?v=1536750440"}, {"time": "2018-05-12T03:49:13-0400", "body": " AFP | Getty Images Walmart CEO Doug McMillon (R) speaking next to Flipkart co-founder and CEO Binny Bansal at an event in Bangalore, as a deal was announced for Walmart to buy a stake in Flipkart. - US retail behemoth Walmart will buy a 77 percent stake in Indian e-commerce giant Flipkart for $16 billion, Walmart said in a statement May 9. Walmart said on Saturday in a filing with a U.S. regulator that it may take India's Flipkart public in as early as four years, detailing for the first time a potential listing timeline for Walmart's largest-ever acquisition. Minority investors holding 60 percent of Flipkart's shares \"acting together, may require Flipkart to effect an initial public offering\" (IPO) four years after the close of the Walmart-Flipkart transaction, the Bentonville, Arkansas-based retailer said in a May 11 filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. The IPO should be done at no less a valuation than that at which Walmart invested in the Indian e-commerce firm, the filing said. Walmart announced earlier this week that it will pay $16 billion for a roughly 77 percent stake in Flipkart in what is the U.S. retail giant's largest-ever deal and a move to take on arch rival Amazon in a key growth market. The investment implies a valuation of nearly $21 billion for Bengaluru-headquartered Flipkart. Minority shareholders after the deal include co-founder Binny Bansal, China's Tencent Holdings, U.S. hedge fund Tiger Global Management and Microsoft. The deal now awaits clearance from India's anti-trust regulator and is expected to close later this year. show chapters What is Flipkart? 8:01 PM ET Wed, 4 April 2018 | 00:56 As part of the deal, Walmart will initially appoint five directors to Flipkart's board, two directors will be named by minority shareholders while Bansal will take one board seat, according to the filing. Walmart said it may, in future, appoint a sixth board member with the approval of the majority of the Flipkart directors. It also said it could appoint or replace Flipkart's chief executive and other key executives of group companies in consultation with Bansal and the board. Walmart or its units could ask Flipkart to issue new ordinary shares of up to $3 billion before the close of the \"transactions and on or before the first anniversary of the closing\", it said. Reuters previously reported that Google-parent Alphabet was in talks to invest about $3 billion for a roughly 15 percent stake in Flipkart. That deal could be sealed before the close of the Walmart-Flipkart transaction or immediately after, a source told Reuters, declining to be named as the talks are private. Walmart also said no party would be liable to pay a termination fee if a share issuance or purchase agreement with Flipkart were terminated. The Economic Times newspaper reported on Friday, citing unnamed sources, that Japan's SoftBank Group, which owns a roughly 20 percent stake in Flipkart, was rethinking its exit due to tax liabilities and because it saw further value in Flipkart. SoftBank Chief Executive Masayoshi Son has said that their investment in Flipkart had grown to almost $4 billion. That growth came just 9 months after SoftBank used its Vision Fund to invest about $2.5 billion in Flipkart. A spokeswoman for SoftBank in India declined comment. Former Amazon employees Sachin and Binny Bansal founded Flipkart in 2007 and, just like Amazon, began by selling books. ", "author": "AFP | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/12/walmart-may-launch-ipo-for-indias-flipkart.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Getty Images Walmart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Doug McMillon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Binny Bansal", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bangalore", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "77 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Indian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$16 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "May 9", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Saturday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "as early as four years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "60 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "four years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Bentonville", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Arkansas", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "May 11", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Indian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "earlier this week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "$16 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "roughly 77 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Amazon", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "nearly $21 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Bengaluru", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Binny Bansal", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tencent Holdings", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tiger Global Management", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Microsoft", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "later this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "8:01 PM ET", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "4", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "April 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "00:56", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "five", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Bansal", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "sixth", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bansal", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "up to $3 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Google-parent Alphabet", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about $3 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "roughly 15 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Walmart-Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Walmart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Economic Times", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Japan", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "SoftBank Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "roughly 20 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SoftBank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Masayoshi Son", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "almost $4 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "just 9 months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "SoftBank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Vision Fund", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about $2.5 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SoftBank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Amazon", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Sachin", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Binny Bansal", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Flipkart", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2007", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Amazon", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "The IPO should be done at no less a valuation than that at which Walmart invested in the Indian e-commerce firm, the retailer said in a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. ", "title": "Walmart may launch IPO for India's Flipkart in as early as four years", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/10/105200497-GettyImages-956707538.jpg?v=1525988364"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T16:04:41-0400", "body": " Simon Dawson | Bloomberg | Getty Images Microprocessors on a circuit board displayed at the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona, Spain, March 2, 2015. Shares of NXP Semiconductors jumped about 12 percent Monday on a report that Chinese regulators will restart a review of Qualcomm's takeover bid for the company. Bloomberg News, citing people familiar with the matter, reported that China's Ministry of Commerce has been asked to hasten the deal's review as well as Qualcomm's plans to protect local companies. Qualcomm's share price gained 2.5 percent on the report. Qualcomm is proposing to buy NXP for $127.50 a share, or $44 billion. The deal has received approval from eight of nine global regulators. Chinese regulators have said the deal could hurt competition within the chipmaker sector. The new report is another indication that U.S.-China trade relations appear to be thawing. On Sunday, President Donald Trump said he would help Chinese cellphone maker ZTE \"get back into business, fast.\" This comes after the U.S. imposed a ban on exports from U.S. companies to ZTE earlier this year. In a tweet, the president said: \"President Xi of China, and I, are working together to give massive Chinese phone company, ZTE, a way to get back into business, fast. Too many jobs in China lost. Commerce Department has been instructed to get it done!\" Tweet A spokesperson for NXP told CNBC in an email that the company \"has a policy to not comment on rumors, speculation or ongoing regulatory matters.\" Qualcomm did not respond to CNBC's request for comment. Click here to read Bloomberg's full report. ", "author": "Simon Dawson | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/nxp-up-on-report-chinese-regulators-to-restart-review-of-qualcomm-bid.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Simon Dawson", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images Microprocessors", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Mobile World Congress", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Barcelona", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Spain", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "March 2, 2015", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "NXP Semiconductors", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about 12 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg News", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Ministry of Commerce", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "NXP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "127.50", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "$44 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "eight of nine", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "U.S", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "earlier this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Xi", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Commerce Department", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "NXP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}], "description": "Shares of NXP Semiconductors jump after news that Chinese regulators will restart a review of Qualcomm's takeover bid for the company.", "title": "Chipmaker NXP surges 10% on report Chinese regulators to restart review of Qualcomm bid", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/10/27/104056775-GettyImages-464955384.jpg?v=1477596841"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T16:53:27-0400", "body": " Xavier Garcia | Bloomberg | Getty Images A demonstrator holds a Puerto Rican flag while being confronted by riot police officers during a protest against austerity measures in the Hato Rey neighborhood of San Juan, Puerto Rico, on Tuesday, May 1, 2018. Warring creditor groups in Puerto Rico's ongoing debt restructuring have reached an agreement that could resolve one of the most contentious disputes in the more than $70 billion bankruptcy case. A proposed settlement would provide approximately $10 billion of debt relief and would resolve substantial risks to the Commonwealth, according to the executive summary. It would also end a more than yearlong court battle between two top tier creditor groups, which have been fighting over who has first rights to the island's sales-tax revenue for bond payments. Those groups are the owners of general obligation bonds and owners of bonds issued by Cofina, which are supported by sales tax revenue. The groups announced the plan in separate statements on Monday. The two have agreed to set up a trust that would take in Puerto Rico's 5.5 percent sales and use tax for 40 years and then pay out to the separate bondholder groups, Mark Palmer, a BTIG analyst who covers bond insurers, wrote in a note on Monday. \"The trust would then make an exchange offer for all GO bonds and allowed general unsecured claims (GUCs),\" the note said. Cofina bondholders would receive 52.5 percent of the sales tax revenue, while general obligation bondholders would get 46.2 percent. \"The supporting parties have come together for the first time in years to forge an agreement on a settlement framework that provides for a consensual path to a successful restructuring. The settlement framework reached by this diverse group of stakeholders would significantly decrease the duration and cost of Puerto Rico's bankruptcy, while also providing for substantial deleveraging,\" the Ad Hoc Group of General Obligation Bondholders said in a statement. Other supporting parties in the settlement are the Bonistas del Patio, which represents island residents who own bonds, and the bond insurers Assured Guaranty, Ambac and MBIA. In total, the supporting parties hold more than $11 billion of Puerto Rico's debt. Cofina's bondholders would share $12.1 billion, which amounts to recoveries of 93 percent to 95 percent for the senior bondholders and 42.2 percent to 43.2 percent for the subordinate bondholders, or about 64 percent combined. General obligation bondholders would get $10.7 billion, a recovery for them of 58.6 percent. Sources familiar with the matter told CNBC that the general obligation creditors would be able to pursue additional claims from the Commonwealth for the amount not covered by the payments from the trust. The government of Puerto Rico and Puerto Rico's Financial Oversight and Management Board were not part of the talks, and both parties rejected the terms. The seven-member Oversight Board, which oversees the beleaguered island's finances, said the economic terms of the creditor proposal did not align with the fiscal plan it certified on April 19, calling it \"completely unaffordable\". \"In the Board's view, the proposed terms would create large and recurring structural deficits over the long-run as compared to the long-term primary surpluses projected in the certified New Fiscal Plan, which are highly dependent on the Government's full implementation of said Fiscal Plan, with no aspect as critical to long-term economic growth as prompt enactment of the proposed labor reform,\" the Board said in a written statement. The Cofina Coalition, made up of those who hold approximately $4 billion of senior and subordinate Cofina bonds, supports the proposed settlement but said it also believes that there are other avenues for an agreement to be reached. \"While members of the Coalition support the COFINA-GO settlement framework, the group also proposed alternative settlement terms – again with significant principal haircuts to COFINA – in mid-April to other constituencies that include the Commonwealth Agent and the Official Committee of Retirees,\" a written statement from the Coalition said. ", "author": "Xavier Garcia | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/warring-puerto-rico-bondholders-pitch-a-deal-over-sales-tax.html", "keywords": [{"term": " ", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Xavier Garcia", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Puerto Rican", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Hato Rey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "San Juan", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "May 1, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico's", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "more than $70 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "approximately $10 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Commonwealth", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "between two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Cofina", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico's", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "5.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "40 years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Mark Palmer", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "BTIG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "GO", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Cofina", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "52.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "46.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico's", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the Ad Hoc Group of General Obligation Bondholders", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bonistas", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Assured Guaranty", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ambac", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "MBIA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "more than $11 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico's", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Cofina", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$12.1 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "93 percent to 95 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "42.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "43.2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "about 64 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "$10.7 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "58.6 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Commonwealth", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Puerto Rico's", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Financial Oversight and Management Board", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "seven", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Oversight Board", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "April 19", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Board", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "New Fiscal Plan", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "Government", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Board", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The Cofina Coalition", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "approximately $4 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Cofina", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "COFINA-GO", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "COFINA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "mid-April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Commonwealth Agent", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Official Committee of Retirees", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "Two big creditor groups have agreed to a deal that creates a trust to receive the island's sales tax receipts and pay them out to the bondholders", "title": "Puerto Rico bondholders pitch deal that could resolve a big dispute in island's debt restructuring", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/14/105206771-GettyImages-953563294.jpg?v=1526323023"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T13:34:09-0400", "body": " Michael Nagle | Bloomberg | Getty Images Bill Barhydt, founder and chief executive officer of Abra, speaks during the Consensus: Invest event in New York, U.S., on Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2017. Cryptocurrency conferences are still a massive business, even if bitcoin's price has plunged this year. When it kicks off this week, one ticket to CoinDesk's Consensus three-day conference in New York City can cost roughly $2,000. Well over 4,000 are expected to attend, up from 2,700 attendees last year. So at a minimum, the conference is likely bringing in $8 million. More than 20 other events, some with similarly high entrance fees, are also scheduled during the days around Consensus. The bitcoin conference that began with 400 attendees three years ago is now the centerpiece of a full-blown \"Blockchain Week NYC,\" an event run in partnership with the New York Economic Development Corporation. Consensus conference attendance growth over the years Source: CoinDesk Last year's conferences helped drive the surge of attention on cryptocurrencies. Around Consensus 2017 last May, Bitcoin accelerated its gains above $2,000, and was bolstered by the first TokenSummit and Ethereal Summit. Prices then skyrocketed over the rest of the year, drawing Wall Street's interest and topping $10,000 for the first time after the \"Consensus Invest\" conference in November. Since then, however, Bitcoin has lost more than half its value since topping $19,000 in December, but it remains more than 4 times above where it was last May. This year's speaker lineup also reflects significant inroads made by the cryptocurrency industry into the mainstream. Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey, whose mobile payments company Square launched bitcoin trading this year, is set to speak at Consensus on Wednesday. Other conference panelists range from government officials to start-up leaders. Consensus \"does have a reputation of, if you speak at that event you're on the map,\" said Michael Oved, co-founder of a token marketplace called AirSwap, and organizer of a blockchain conference called Fluidity, which took place Thursday. He said he purposely under-priced his conference – tickets ran from $150 to $250 – because he saw it as \"an opportunity for us to talk about the things we've been working on.\" About 700 people attended the Brooklyn event, Oved said. That would bring ticket sales to about $140,000. \"Clearly there's a lot of money to be made in the enterprise IT world, and blockchain seems to be the flavor of month.\" -Bill Barhydt, CEO of Abra Other events charge at least several hundred dollars for admission, including: The two-day Ethereal Summit run by ConsenSys sells tickets for $1,300 each; TokenSummit on May 17 is sold out of regular $649 tickets, and a \"very late ticket\" costs $979; The \"Women on the Block\" conference held on Mother's Day charges $299 for general admission, and $599 for VIP access to a reception and a lounge. Childcare for children ages 5 to 11 costs $80; General admission to the May 18 NYC Blockchain Tech & Invest Summit is $899, while investors and VIP tickets are $1,299, according to Eventbrite. The ADI Cryptocurrency Mining Summit charges $499 to $699. \"Clearly there's a lot of money to be made in the enterprise IT world, and blockchain seems to be the flavor of month,\" said Bill Barhydt, CEO of Abra, which runs a mobile-based cryptocurrency storage app. \"This represents an opportunity for companies that are trying to jump on that bandwagon to take advantage of that confluence of factors at the same time,\" he said. \"Obviously there's a lot of money moving around in terms of sponsorships. We're getting requests every day to sponsor.\" Getty Images Founder of Ethereum Vitalik Buterin However, not everyone in the cryptocurrency world is happy about the massive conference industry. Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin tweeted on April 26 that he is boycotting Consensus this year partly because of the high ticket price. \"The conference costs $2-$3k to attend. I refuse to personally contribute to that level of rent seeking,\" Buterin said. He added that CoinDesk \"is recklessly complicit in enabling giveaway scams,\" and called their coverage of an ethereum split \"highly sensationalist.\" Tweet In a statement, CoinDesk responded that it was \"disappointed to learn of Vitalik's tweet today regarding a CoinDesk reporting error, for which we apologize. One of our reporters included an unverified link in an article; we quickly identified the error and fixed it. We strive to maintain the highest level of unbiased, ethical journalism in order to provide the best possible coverage of the blockchain industry.\" Amber Baldet, former head of blockchain at J.P. Morgan, also criticized the increasingly costly cryptocurrency events. \"The irony of high-priced conferences is they're the ones least likely to be paying speakers within the community, who care the most & need the platform to share new work,\" she tweeted on April 28. \"Corporate expense accounts subsidize people who rarely say anything novel, 'celeb keynotes' extract high fees.\" She is a speaker at two of the primary events of the week, Ethereal Summit and Consensus. \"I'm not getting paid for either,\" she said in another tweet, adding that their livestreams \"are a great way to democratize access.\" 'So many conferences...it's crazy' With all the hype and partying that conferences bring, it's also unclear whether they ultimately help start-ups progress along a planned production schedule — especially when many can struggle under inexperienced management. \"There are so many conferences now,\" Oved said. \"It's crazy. In the Bay Area alone, there's a conference every week on blockchain. It's easy to get distracted by conferences.\" However, some are betting that the conferences will be the catalyst for bitcoin prices eventual recovery. \"The rally post-Consensus has been strong and more supportive of our view that bitcoin has already bottomed for the year,\" Tom Lee, co-founder of Fundstrat Global Research said in a May 7 note. \"Bitcoin has rallied 10 to 70 percent during each of these conferences.\" Lee added: \"We think alt-coins could similarly rally given the sizable increase in attendance.\" Clarification: The Fluidity conference took place on Thursday, May 10. ", "author": "Michael Nagle | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/13/bitcoin-conferences-flood-new-york-bringing-millions-in-ticket-sales.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Michael Nagle", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bill Barhydt", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Abra", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "New York", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tuesday, Nov. 28, 2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "this week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "CoinDesk", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "three-day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "New York City", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "roughly $2,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "over 4,000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "2,700", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "$8 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "More than 20", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "400", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "three years ago", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Blockchain Week NYC", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "the New York Economic Development Corporation", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CoinDesk", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Last year's", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "last May", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bitcoin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "above $2,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "TokenSummit", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Ethereal Summit", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the rest of the year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "10,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Consensus Invest", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "November", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bitcoin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "more than half", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "19,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "more than 4", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "last May.", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Jack Dorsey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Square", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Wednesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Michael Oved", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "AirSwap", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Fluidity", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Thursday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "$150 to", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "250", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "About 700", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Brooklyn", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "about $140,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Barhydt", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Abra", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "at least several hundred dollars", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "two-day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Ethereal Summit", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "ConsenSys", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1,300", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "TokenSummit", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "May 17", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "649", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "979", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "299", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "599", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "VIP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ages 5 to 11", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "80", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "May 18", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Summit", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "899", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "1,299", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "The ADI Cryptocurrency Mining Summit", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$499 to $699", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bill Barhydt", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Abra", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "every day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Vitalik Buterin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "April 26", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2-$3k", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Buterin", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CoinDesk", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CoinDesk", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Vitalik", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "today", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CoinDesk", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "One", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Amber Baldet", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "J.P. Morgan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "April 28", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Ethereal Summit", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Bay Area", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "every week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Consensus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tom Lee", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Fundstrat Global Research", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "May 7", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Bitcoin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "10 to 70 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Lee", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Thursday, May 10", "category": "DATE"}], "description": "One ticket to CoinDesk's Consensus three-day conference in New York City in the coming week can cost roughly $2,000, and with well over 4,000 are expected to attend the conference is likely bringing in at least $8 million.", "title": "Bitcoin conferences flood New York, and bring millions in ticket sales with them", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/11/105203000-GettyImages-881226520.jpg?v=1526068206"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T07:51:10-0400", "body": " Cadence Bancorp said on Sunday it had agreed to buy State Bank Financial in an all-stock deal valued at about $1.4 billion, signaling a potential rise in regional bank consolidation in the United States. The agreement, approved by the boards of both banks, will create an entity with $16 billion in assets and about 100 branches in Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Mississippi, Tennessee, and Texas, the banks said in a press release. Investors expect a wave of mergers among mid-sized banks as U.S. lawmakers work to rewrite banking rules enacted after the 2007-2009 financial crisis. These changes would likely raise the limit on what is considered a systemically important financial institution, which had hampered some banks from merging. Lawmakers also are tinkering with older bank rules, emboldened by President Donald Trump's vow to loosen banking restrictions. State Bank shareholders will receive 1.160 shares of Cadence class A common stock for each State Bank share, Cadence said in a statement. Cadence shares closed at $30.23 on Friday, while State Bank shares closed at $33.08. Cadence and State Bank shareholders will collectively own about 65 percent and 35 percent of the combined company, respectively, after the deal is closed. ", "author": "Robert Daly | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/cadence-agrees-to-buy-state-bank-in-1-point-4-billion-all-stock-deal.html", "keywords": [{"term": " Cadence Bancorp", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "State Bank Financial", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about $1.4 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "the United States", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "$16 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "about 100", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Alabama", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Florida", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Georgia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Mississippi", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tennessee", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Texas", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "2007-2009", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "State Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1.160", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "State Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Cadence", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "30.23", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "State Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "33.08", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "State Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "about 65 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "35 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}], "description": "Cadence Bancorp agreed to buy State Bank Financial in an all-stock deal valued at about $1.4 billion.", "title": "Cadence agrees to buy State Bank in $1.4 billion all-stock deal", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/11/20/104852592-GettyImages-147205360.jpg?v=1511157989"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T11:35:29-0400", "body": " show chapters 'Big Short' investor Steve Eisman blasts cryptocurrencies 10:53 AM ET Mon, 14 May 2018 | 01:23 Steve Eisman, the investor whose forecast of the financial crisis was depicted in \"The Big Short,\" is still finding problematic stocks and investing manias in the financial markets. The Neuberger Berman portfolio manager confirmed his fund is short Canadian financials, Deutsche Bank and Wells Fargo. He spoke in a Bloomberg Television interview that aired on Sunday from the CFA Institute's annual conference in Hong Kong. \"Deutsche Bank has real profitability issues. They haven't spent money on technology in a very very long time. They're probably under-capitalized,\" he said. \"I think they'll probably raise capital again next year. Deutsche Bank is a problem bank. I think it has to shrink dramatically.\" show chapters Michael Lewis: Still believe markets are rigged 2:13 PM ET Mon, 23 March 2015 | 08:35 Eisman is known for being one of the few investors to profitably bet against subprime mortgage securities during the financial crisis. He was a key character in Michael Lewis' best-selling book \"The Big Short\" and was depicted by actor Steve Carell in the movie based on the book. On stage Monday at the CFA Institute's annual conference in Hong Kong, Eisman expressed skepticism over cryptocurrencies. \"I don't see the purpose of it,\" he said, according to The Wall Street Journal. \"What value does cryptocurrency actually add? No one's been able to answer that question for me.\" Eisman also said digital currency prices are rising due to speculation and money laundering, according to the Journal. Despite his negative views on certain bank stocks, the investor is generally optimistic on the environment for the U.S. banking sector. \"The financial system in the United States has changed radically. Leverage has been reduced enormously,\" he said on Bloomberg Television. \"For the first time in all the years I've covered bank stocks, I can honestly say the financial system in the United States is safe.\" Deutsche Bank declined to comment for this story. Wells Fargo did not immediately respond to a CNBC request for comment. Disclaimer ", "author": "Katie Rooney | CNBC", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/big-short-steve-eisman-blasts-cryptocurrencies-bets-against-deutsche-bank.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Steve Eisman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "10:53 AM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "14", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "May 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Steve Eisman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "The Big Short", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Neuberger Berman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Canadian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Deutsche Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bloomberg Television", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the CFA Institute's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "annual", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Hong Kong", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Deutsche Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "next year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Deutsche Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Michael Lewis", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2:13 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "23 March 2015", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "08:35 Eisman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Michael Lewis'", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "The Big Short", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Steve Carell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the CFA Institute's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "annual", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Hong Kong", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Eisman", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The Wall Street Journal", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Eisman", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Journal", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the United States", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Bloomberg Television", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "all the years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the United States", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Deutsche Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "Neuberger Berman portfolio manager Steve Eisman is betting against Canadian financials, Deutsche Bank and Wells Fargo.", "title": "'Big Short' Steve Eisman blasts cryptocurrencies, bets against Deutsche Bank", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/12/19/104175225-IMG_9844.JPG?v=1519832187"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T14:07:35-0400", "body": " Scott Eells | Bloomberg | Getty Images JPMorgan Chase & Co. The nation's largest banks — and public companies, for that matter — are preparing for a timeout from the courtroom following years of being pummeled by shareholder and investor lawsuits in the wake of the Great Recession. At the end of 2017, the country's largest banks collectively decreased their estimates for future legal costs to their lowest levels since 2012, and legal experts predict the move is a harbinger of what's to come for Corporate America in an era of strong job growth and loosening regulations at the federal level. Between 2012 and the end of 2017, the nation's 10 biggest banks by assets saw a 56 percent decline in their anticipated litigation expenses beyond their required cash reserves, according to financial statements filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. The estimates signify the amounts banks expect to pay in litigation and legal costs beyond what they are required to set aside as emergency legal funds. The estimates are published each quarter with the SEC. More from The American City Business Journals: Tesla loses top safety executive to rival Waymo Intel reassigns marketing chief In the money May 14: Nearly $15M raised by Austin startups fighting cancer and simplifying road toll payments Leading the way was Regions Financial Corp., which saw a 100 percent reduction in its anticipated legal costs in excess of reserves over the past five years, indicating the bank isn't expecting any major settlements in the coming months. Regions did not respond to requests for comment on its legal position. Likewise, Citigroup reduced its estimate by 80 percent while both JPMorgan Chase & Co. and PNC Financial Services Group both lowered their estimates by more than 70 percent. LET THE GOOD TIMES ROLL The downturn in litigation is not limited to the banking sector, said Dennis Tracey, chair of Hogan Lovells' litigation practice in New York. Recent U.S. Supreme Court cases tightening personal jurisdiction rules have made it much harder to file suit against a company outside of the state where it is domiciled or has its principle place of business. Tracy said that has helped to limit the number of lawsuits across all industries. Another plus for corporations: The Supreme Court recently handed down decisions reining in intellectual property cases and making it harder for so-called patent trolls to advance legal claims. Tracey also pointed to the election of President Donald Trump, whose administration has made it a priority to loosen the regulatory climate for corporations. \"There has really been a decline in litigation since the financial crisis, when many companies began to rethink their legal spending,\" Tracey said. \"I don't know if it's permanent or temporary.\" Which is not to say companies were without significant legal costs in 2017. Wells Fargo topped all U.S. companies with some $2.1 billion in after-tax legal and settlement costs, followed by Alphabet at $1.8 billion and drug maker Johnson & Johnson at $955 million, according to regulatory filings. CALM AFTER THE STORM Tracey said the reductions in bank-litigation costs are partly due to the fact that many lawsuits filed in the wake of the financial crisis are winding down. Banks were in many cases required to pay multimillion-dollar — even multibillion-dollar — settlements to resolve a wave of litigation stemming from last decade's financial and housing crises. \"The financial crisis spawned a huge amount of very high stakes litigation and regulatory actions,\" Tracey said. \"There are some remaining large matters, but among our clients that happen to be large banks, most believe the worst is behind them.\" Wells Fargo is one major exception. The banking giant has faced a raft of lawsuits in recent years, with claims ranging from allegations over unauthorized accounts to discriminatory mortgage practices to fraud affecting retail clients. Regulatory filings highlight the company's legal challenges, as Wells Fargo increased its estimate for litigation costs in excess of reserves to $2.7 billion in 2017's fourth quarter, roughly double where it was in 2012. Wells Fargo is a Hogan Lovells client. Tracey said a strong economy also is contributing to the decline in legal challenges for banks, as low unemployment and rising wages have sapped some of the motivation that's driven prior shareholder lawsuits. ", "author": "David A. Grogan | CNBC", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/big-banks-say-their-legal-costs-are-tumbling.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Scott Eells", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Great Recession", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the end of 2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2012", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Corporate America", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Between 2012", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the end of 2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "56 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "each quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "SEC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The American City Business Journals", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Waymo Intel", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "May 14", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Nearly $15M", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Austin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Regions Financial Corp.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "100 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the past five years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the coming months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Regions", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Citigroup", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "80 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "JPMorgan Chase & Co.", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PNC Financial Services Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "more than 70 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "THE GOOD TIMES ROLL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dennis Tracey", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Hogan Lovells'", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "New York", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Recent U.S. Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tracy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "The Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Tracey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tracey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "some $2.1 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Alphabet", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$1.8 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Johnson & Johnson", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$955 million", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "THE STORM Tracey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "multimillion-dollar", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "multibillion-dollar", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "last decade's", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Tracey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "recent years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$2.7 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "fourth quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2012", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Wells Fargo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Hogan Lovells", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tracey", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "Big banks have been pummeled by investor lawsuits since the Great Recession but they're finally starting to see that subside, Jeff Jeffrey reports in the Business Journals.", "title": "Big banks say their legal costs are tumbling", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/09/12/104705632-20170912-8453-2447.jpg?v=1530797180"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T09:22:14-0400", "body": " Getty Images Chipotle restaurant workers fill orders for customers in Miami, Florida. Chipotle Mexican Grill's recovery efforts, including the appointment of a new chief executive and a new delivery partnership, represent steps in the right direction, according to Piper Jaffray. The firm reiterated its overweight rating on the restaurant company's shares, predicting Chipotle's stock price could top $530 in 12 months, the highest target on Wall Street and implying 25 percent upside from Friday's close. Piper's previous target was $420. \"Chipotle shares remain a top recovery pick. When, and as (not \"if\") the recovery unfolds, meaningful leverage exists,\" analyst Nicole Regan said in a note Sunday. \"Our positive bias is based on culture change, strong unit-level economics and solid balance sheet. Catalysts include operational excellence, brand remodeling, and capital deployment.\" The appointment of Brian Niccol as chief executive officer — who arrived with a successful track record at Taco Bell — as well as a new delivery partnership with DoorDash have supported the stock and sales, Regan said, and justify same-store sales expectations in excess of 2 percent. Shares of Chipotle rose 0.7 percent in premarket trading following Piper Jaffray's optimistic call. The shares are up 47 percent this year. While Niccol built a reputation for menu innovation at Taco Bell, he recently told CNBC's \"Squawk on the Street\" that while investors shouldn't expect major changes to the company's offerings, items like breakfast burritos aren't out of the question. \"Job No. 1 is to remind people why they love Chipotle,\" Niccol told CNBC in March. \"I think there [are] opportunities to use what we have and present it in new forms, new varieties, to get people re-engaged with what they love about Chipotle.\" Such initiatives are likely welcome news to investors like Pershing Square activist Bill Ackman, who has leveraged a 10 percent stake in the company to encourage ideas like drive-thrus and breakfast offerings to reignite the beleaguered shares following a series of food safety issues. \"We're not just betting on a recovery from the food safety issue,\" Ackman told CNBC in November. \"This is one of the least optimized of thequick-servicee restaurants.\" It appears Ackman isn't the only investor willing to give Chipotle another chance. Shares of the casual Mexican eatery are up roughly 70 percent since the Chipotle board announced Niccol's appointment on Feb. 13, while a recent hike to menu prices helped the Mexican eatery post better-than-expected earnings last month. The improved performance announced April 25 sent shares soaring 24 percent the next day, their best day since the company went public in 2006, when its share price doubled. Disclaimer ", "author": "Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/chipotle-gets-a-big-bullish-analyst-call-as-piper-jaffray-sees-25-percent-rally-from-here.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Getty Images Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Miami", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Florida", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Chipotle Mexican Grill's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Piper Jaffray", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "530", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "12 months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "25 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Piper", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "420", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Nicole Regan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Brian Niccol", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Taco Bell —", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Regan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "0.7 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Piper Jaffray's", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "47 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Niccol", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Taco Bell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Squawk on the Street", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Job No. 1", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Niccol", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "March", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Pershing Square", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "Bill Ackman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "10 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Ackman told CNBC in November", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Ackman", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Mexican", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "roughly 70 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Chipotle", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Niccol", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Feb. 13", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Mexican", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "last month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "April 25", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "24 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the next day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "their best day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2006", "category": "DATE"}], "description": "Chipotle Mexican Grill's recovery efforts, including the appointment of CEO Brian Niccol, represent steps in the right direction, according to Piper Jaffray.", "title": "Chipotle gets a big bullish call from an analyst: Piper Jaffray sees 25% rally", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/11/10/104097944-GettyImages-471371494.jpg?v=1532637905"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T21:41:53-0400", "body": " Jonathan Ernst | Reuters President Donald Trump displays a presidential memorandum after announcing his intent to withdraw from the JCPOA Iran nuclear agreement in the Diplomatic Room at the White House in Washington, May 8, 2018. Germany does not want to finance the budget to support reforms in a French proposal to \"refound\" the European economic and political integration (aka \"the European project\"). At the same time, the presumption of European unity is being severely tested by the extraterritorial impact of President Donald Trump's unilateral sanctions on Iran. Ironically, the money is the least of the problems in a quasi-permanent state of unease in French-German relations. Against that background, displays of bonhomie on official occasions look like a polite gloss of convenience on a centuries-old hostility of neighbors living the illusion of harmony and cooperation. After a decade of taking a back seat to Germany in economic policy and European affairs, France is now moving center stage in denouncing what it calls the German \"fetishism of trade and budget surpluses\" at the expense of the rest of Europe and a wider world. France, correctly, sees these policies as a serious obstacle to its proposals to strengthen the European project. Predictably, Germany is stalling, while the hostility of the German media sounds like an intention to bring the young French upstart — President Emmanuel Macron — down to the real world by showing him who's the boss. \"Don't be afraid,\" says Macron Paris, however, is neither fooled nor intimidated. The highly educated French president is no shrinking violet, as he showed in his frontal attack on Trump's policies during his address to the joint session of the U.S. Congress last month. He knows that his ideas about the future of Europe and the French-German relations are issues for serious debate. He also knows that Germany's peremptory dismissal of his reform proposals are signs of vulnerability because he is pressing the right buttons. Here is what's at stake. In several of his speeches last year, Macron proposed measures mostly focused on the 19-nation monetary union that should serve as a strong core of the European Union consisting of 28 member states (or 27 if the UK concludes the separation agreement by the spring 2019). Among the key proposals are a common euro area finance minister, a legislative and executive authority and a budget to finance the euro area's economic, social and fiscal convergence. Suffering from a protracted interregnum last year, Germany took all that as an affront. Macron's pIan was dead on arrival in Berlin, shot to pieces well in advance in a typical NIH (not invented here) manner. The whole thing was ridiculed as an exercise in building unnecessary bureaucracy and imposing new financial burdens. Berlin prefers to talk about its own priorities, such as the mandatory EU quotas for taking migrants that Germany invited and could no longer manage, digital economy and the completion of the euro area banking union. True to form, the German \"down-to-earth\" talk is also accompanied by the usual violins about staying competitive to push exports. Make no mistake, this French-German kabuki show is a deadly serious power play. As a well-informed analyst of the European political scene, Macron is moved by a number of fundamental factors underlying the future of the European project. Macron again: \"The time to act is now!\" One, his plan for a complete federal structure of the monetary and fiscal union is meant to guarantee the strength and the finality of the European project and its legal tender. Two, such a structure would be impossible to deconstruct by nationalists, populists and similar constituencies blaming all sorts of socio-economic problems on the EU's single market and the common currency. Three, I'll take the liberty of ascribing to Macron this unstated thought: His euro area reform program would also make it impossible for Germany to boss people around; the administrative setup he proposes would unfailingly and routinely enforce the rules of the monetary and fiscal union. The focus is now on the meeting of the European Council — a forum of EU heads of state and government — on June 28-29, where France and Germany are supposed to present a joint \"road map\" of European reforms. French commentators of all stripes expect a damp squib, accusing Macron of talking too much instead of \"banging his fist on the table.\" Responding to that criticism, the French presidency announced last week that it was looking for substantive decisions next month. Wish them luck, because Germany does not seem ready for substantive decisions on anything. In her speech last week to celebrate Macron's Charlemagne Prize (for contributions to the cause of the European Union), German Chancellor Angela Merkel spoke mainly of the problems the U.S. was creating for the German economy with its unilateral sanctions on Iran. Macron, in her words, was \"bubbling with ideas,\" but said nothing about Germany's response, or what Germany was prepared to do to help \"Europe take its destiny in its own hands.\" The reaction to the fallout from Washington's Iran sanctions is characteristic of ambiguity in French-German relations. In spite of statements that the two countries wanted to stay in Iran's nuclear agreement, Paris and Berlin are working on separate tracks to get exemptions from the U.S.-imposed sanctions on their companies involved in multi-year and multi-billion deals with Tehran. France says that the extraterritorial reach of Trump's Iran sanctions is \"unacceptable,\" while Germany remains resigned that \"nothing can be done about it.\" Following that conclusion, Germany is talking about post-Trump policies, because Berlin presumably expects that next November's mid-term Congressional elections can cripple what they apparently believe will be a one-term presidency. More realistically, Germany seems to be counting on China and Russia (and perhaps India) to reject Washington's unilateral sanctions on Iran — offering a way out the German-led Europe is unable to find on its own. All eyes are now on Iran's ongoing talks in Beijing and Moscow, and a visit of Tehran's delegation to Brussels next Tuesday. Investment thoughts Investors voting with their savings on euro-denominated assets may wish to follow closely the French-German clash about measures that are necessary to strengthen the European project. These are crucially important steps to make irrevocable the EU's single market and the euro as a legal tender. France has posed that question in the form of far-reaching reforms to mend Europe's dangerous fault lines and set the famously fractious continent on a path to peace, harmony and prosperity. So far, Germany has shown no interest to cooperate, but France, apparently, won't give up. A prominent French philosopher reminded the body politic last week that \"article one of Macronist doctrine is attachment to the idea of a united Europe.\" Trump has made this intra-European discord more difficult with extraterritorial economic and financial implications of his wide-ranging sanctions. By withdrawing from the Iran nuclear agreement, and threatening sanctions on any company working with Iranian counterparts, Trump could potentially tear up the fragile European project. I am not betting on that, but those who argue that Trump's disruptions could achieve the opposite result ignore deeply entrenched divisions and outright hostilities plaguing what people still hopefully call the European Union. You want to take a bet? Here is mine: Macron will win and Italy will soon get a pro-European prime minister with little patience for Germany. The fiercely independent and highly professional European Central Bank will remain a pillar of the steadily growing euro area economy. Trump will be \"convinced\" by China, Russia and India — all actively trading with Tehran as an ally — to scale back his Iranian hostilities. Commentary by Michael Ivanovitch, an independent analyst focusing on world economy, geopolitics and investment strategy. He served as a senior economist at the OECD in Paris, international economist at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, and taught economics at Columbia Business School. ", "author": "Jonathan Ernst | Reuters", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/13/iran-sanctions-will-aggravate-discord-on-eu-reforms--commentary.html", "keywords": [{"term": " ", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Jonathan Ernst", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Reuters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "JCPOA Iran", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Diplomatic Room", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "the White House", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "Washington", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "May 8, 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "centuries-old", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "a decade", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Emmanuel Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Macron Paris", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Trump's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the U.S. Congress", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "last month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "19-nation", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the European Union", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "28", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "27", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "UK", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the spring 2019", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "pIan", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Berlin", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "NIH", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Berlin", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "One", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the European Council — a forum", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "June 28-29", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "next month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Wish", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Charlemagne Prize", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "the European Union", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Angela Merkel", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Washington", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "French", "category": "LANGUAGE"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Paris", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Berlin", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tehran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Trump's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Berlin", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "next November's", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Congressional", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Russia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Washington", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "German", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Beijing", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Moscow", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tehran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Brussels", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "next Tuesday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "EU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "France", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "French", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Macronist", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Europe", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Iranian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Trump's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the European Union", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Macron", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Italy", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "European", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Germany", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "European Central Bank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Russia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "India", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Tehran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Iranian", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Michael Ivanovitch", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "OECD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Paris", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve Bank of New York", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Columbia Business School", "category": "ORG"}], "description": "After a decade of taking a back seat to Germany, France is now moving center stage in denouncing what it calls the German \"fetishism of trade and budget surpluses\" at the expense of the rest of Europe and a wider world, Michael Ivanovitch writes.", "title": "Trump’s Iran sanctions will aggravate the French-German discord on EU reforms", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/08/105193532-RTS1QGNY.jpg?v=1525806285"}, {"time": "2018-06-01T08:29:26-0400", "body": " Dhiraj Singh | Bloomberg via Getty Images HSBC claimed on Monday it had performed the world's first commercially viable trade finance transaction using blockchain technology. The bank issued a letter of credit for U.S. food and agriculture firm Cargill. The trade finance transaction involved a bulk shipment of soybeans from Argentina to Malaysia. The letter of credit was issued from HSBC to Dutch lender ING. Letters of credit are issued by one bank to another to guarantee that a payment will be received by a seller under a set of conditions. Traditionally this process would take a large amount of time, numerous paper records, and a lot of back and forth between the various parties involved. Blockchain technology promises to change that. Blockchain, the technology that underpins bitcoin, enables transactions to be recorded across a vast network of computers. In the case of bitcoin, it records all of the transactions that happen on the network, creating a public ledger. Banks have taken the principles behind bitcoin's blockchain – such as the idea of decentralized ledger – and tried to apply it to processes that they are carrying out. For this transaction, HSBC used a platform developed by blockchain start-up R3 called Corda. R3 works with a consortium of banks to come up with blockchain solutions to a variety of problems. show chapters What is Blockchain? 9:08 AM ET Mon, 4 June 2018 | 04:44 \"The need for paper reconciliation is removed because all parties are linked on the platform and updates are instantaneous,\" Vivek Ramachandran, head of growth and innovation at HSBC, said in a statement. \"The quick turnaround could mean unlocking liquidity for businesses.\" HSBC and ING said that the exchange was performed in 24 hours, compared to the five-to-10 days it normally takes to complete such exchanges through a paper-based system. Proponents of blockchain claim it has the potential to upend various industries. Sectors like trade finance, health care and insurance are thought of as good targets for the use the technology as they rely on long paper trails. While there have been proof-of-concept transactions performed using blockchain technology, HSBC's was the first that could have commercial applications, a spokesman for the company told CNBC. Banks have been pouring money into blockchain projects as it is thought that the technology will significantly disrupt the financial services. While lenders are not fond of the original use case of blockchain — to underpin cryptocurrency transactions — many see practical use for the technology because of its ability to handle massive amounts of data within a transparent, immutable network. Last month, Santander teamed up with blockchain firm Ripple to create a foreign exchange service that enables same-day international money transfers. ", "author": "Dhiraj Singh | Bloomberg via Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/hsbc-makes-worlds-first-trade-finance-transaction-using-blockchain.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Dhiraj Singh", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Bloomberg", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Getty Images HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Cargill", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Argentina", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Malaysia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dutch", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "ING", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "R3", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Corda", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "R3", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Blockchain", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "9:08 AM ET Mon,", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "4 June 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Vivek Ramachandran", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ING", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "24 hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "the five-to-10 days", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "HSBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Last month", "category": "DATE"}], "description": "HSBC and ING said that the exchange was performed in 24 hours, compared to the five-to-10 days it normally takes through a paper-based system.", "title": "HSBC says it’s made the world's first trade finance transaction using blockchain", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/14/105205427-GettyImages-911643174.jpg?v=1526292196"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T19:20:13-0400", "body": " Ting Shen | Xinhua | Getty Images Jerome Powell, Chairman of the Federal Reserve Markets are becoming more convinced that the Federal Reserve is about to get more aggressive on interest rates. The probability that the central bank will raise its benchmark rate a fourth time this year went above 50 percent for the first time, according to the CME's FedWatch tracking tool for the fed funds futures market. Futures contracts are currently implying a funds rate of 2.21 percent from the current range of 1.5 percent to 1.75 percent. According to the CME, that translates into a 51 percent chance of a December rate hike, which would be the fourth of the year. The Fed already approved one quarter-point hike, in March. Futures trading indicates a 95 percent chance of a June increase — the probability had been 100 percent as recently as last week — and an 81.4 percent likelihood of another move in September. show chapters Interest rate move will be less important this year than the rate path, says expert 8:11 AM ET Fri, 11 May 2018 | 03:38 As things stand, Fed officials currently are indicating a total of three hikes this year. However, the Federal Open Market Committee meets in June, during which members will get a chance to update their forecasts. Hawkish expectations are rising even though inflation pressures have been held at bay. The personal consumption expenditures index excluding food and energy is at 1.9 percent, and the Dallas Fed's inflation gauge is at 1.8 percent, both narrowly below the Fed's 2 percent inflation target. In addition, wage pressures have been low, with average annual earnings rising a less-than-expected 2.6 percent annualized for April. However, Fed officials, led by Chairman Jerome Powell, have been expressing concern about the effects that loose monetary policy can have on asset valuations. Also, the unemployment rate's drop to 3.9 percent could weigh on Fed officials who follow the Phillips Curve, an economic model that indicates wage pressures will rise as the jobless level falls. Recently enacted fiscal stimulus in the form of lower taxes and higher spending levels also could prove inflationary. \"Now, with fiscal policy turning from restrictive to stimulative, the economy growing above trend, and investment rising, the short-term equilibrium interest rate is rising, too,\" Cleveland Fed President Loretta Mester said in a speech Monday in Paris. \"As the expansion continues, it could be that in order to maintain our policy goals, we may need to move the fed funds rate, for a time, a bit above the level of the funds rate that is expected to prevail over the longer run.\" Mester is considered one of the Fed's more hawkish members. WATCH: Something strange that could boost interest rates show chapters Goldman Sachs says there could be a significant jump in interest rates 4:23 PM ET Mon, 14 May 2018 | 01:00 ", "author": "Ting Shen | Xinhua | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/market-now-pricing-in-four-interest-rate-hikes-this-year.html", "keywords": [{"term": " ", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Ting Shen", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Xinhua | Getty Images Jerome Powell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve Markets", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Federal Reserve", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "fourth", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "above 50 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "CME", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FedWatch", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2.21 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "1.5 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "1.75 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "CME", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "51 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the fourth of the year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one quarter", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "March", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "95 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "June", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "100 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "81.4 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "September", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "8:11 AM ET Fri", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "May 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Federal Open Market Committee", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "June", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Hawkish", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "1.9 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "the Dallas Fed's", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1.8 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "annual", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2.6 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Jerome Powell", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "3.9 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Phillips Curve", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Cleveland Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Loretta Mester", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Paris", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Fed", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Goldman Sachs", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PM ET Mon", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "14 May 2018", "category": "DATE"}], "description": "Markets are becoming more convinced that the Federal Reserve is about to get more aggressive on interest rates. The probability that the central bank will raise its benchmark rate a fourth time this year went above 50 percent for the first time.", "title": "Market now pricing in four interest rate hikes this year", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/02/13/105005641-GettyImages-881789270.jpg?v=1528818469"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T16:04:23-0400", "body": " show chapters American tech companies have up to $150 billion at stake in the China-US trade fight 1:25 PM ET Mon, 14 May 2018 | 00:50 U.S. technology companies generate roughly $100 billion to $150 billion in revenues from China annually, Jefferies analysts estimate. As a result, the Trump administration will likely pursue concessions from Beijing, rather than cut off all tech trade, analysts Edison Lee and Timothy Chau said in a note Monday. \" We continue to believe the US will make only highly calculated moves, by factoring in the commercial interest of US tech firms.\" Apple and Intel are on a list of 16 U.S. companies that made a total $105.5 billion from China last year, or 23 percent of overall revenues, the analysts said. #dw-chart{width: 100%;height: 500px;border: none;padding-top: 32px;box-sizing: border-box;-moz-box-sizing: border-box;-webkit-box-sizing: border-box;}jQuery(document).ready(function($){var iframe=document.getElementById(\"dw-chart\");$(window).on(\"orientationchange\",function(){iframe.src=iframe.src;});}); Other names include Microsoft and Qualcomm. Including HP, Dell and other companies that don't break out their China revenues brings the total estimate to around $150 billion, the analysts said. The U.S.-China trade dispute has increasingly focused on technology and intellectual property rights. In mid-April, the U.S. Commerce Department banned American companies from selling components to Chinese telecom equipment giant ZTE for seven years. The decision was a response to ZTE's violation of U.S. sanctions against Iran and North Korea, to which the Chinese company pleaded guilty last year. Trading in its Hong Kong and Shenzhen-listed shares was halted after the ban, and last week the company said its main business operations have ceased. However, President Donald Trump unexpectedly said Sunday that he is working with Chinese President Xi Jinping to help ZTE \"get back into business, fast.\" Shares of optical component makers working directly or indirectly with ZTE rose in Monday morning trading: Acacia Communications received 30 percent of 2017 total revenue from the Chinese telecom company. Shares closed up 8.7 percent. Oclaro generated 18 percent of fiscal year 2017 revenue from ZTE. Shares closed up 2.9 percent. Lumentum, which has agreed to acquire Oclaro for $1.8 billion, saw its shares rise more than 2 percent. Finisar also counts ZTE as a customer. Its shares gained 1 percent. All four stocks are on the Jefferies analysts' list. ", "author": "ChinaFotoPress | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/14/as-much-as-150-billion-annually-at-stake-us-tech-in-china-us-fight.html", "keywords": [{"term": "American", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "up to $150 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "1:25 PM ET Mon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "14", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "May 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "00:50", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "roughly $100 billion to $150 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Jefferies", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Trump", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Beijing", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Edison Lee", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Timothy Chau", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "a note Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Apple", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Intel", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "16", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "$105.5 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "23 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "500px;border", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Microsoft", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Qualcomm", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dell", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "China", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "around $150 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "U.S", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "mid-April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the U.S. Commerce Department", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "American", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "seven years", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "U.S.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Iran", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "North Korea", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "last year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Hong Kong", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Shenzhen", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "last week", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Donald Trump", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Sunday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Xi Jinping", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "morning", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Acacia Communications", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "30 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Chinese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "8.7 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Oclaro", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "18 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "fiscal year 2017", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "2.9 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Lumentum", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Oclaro", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "$1.8 billion", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "more than 2 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "Finisar", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ZTE", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1 percent", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "four", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Jefferies", "category": "PERSON"}], "description": "U.S. technology companies generate roughly $100 billion to $150 billion in revenues from China, Jefferies analysts estimate.", "title": "Apple, Intel and these other US tech companies have the most at stake in China-US trade fight", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/01/26/103334677-GettyImages-489940282.jpg?v=1526311456"}, {"time": "2018-05-12T11:00:09-0400", "body": " show chapters Blockchain will help ‘drive this next industrial revolution,’ Wall Street bull predicts 6:13 PM ET Fri, 11 May 2018 | 01:45 One of Wall Street's biggest bulls sees blockchain playing a big role as an economic growth driver. It still may be considered an emerging technology, but Federated Investors portfolio manager Steve Chiavarone is folding the electronic system, which records cryptocurrency transactions, into his stock market forecast. \"This is going to be one of five key technologies — along with automation, robotics, A.I. [artificial intelligence] and the Internet of things that drive this next industrial revolution,\" he said Friday on CNBC's \"Trading Nation.\" He's not letting the growing pains currently gripping the cryptocurrency market affect his bullish view. Bitcoin, which has been referred to as the FANG stock of the crypto world, has been struggling to break $10,000 — just months after hitting a record price just shy of $20,000 last December. In fact, Chiavarone sees FANG stocks, which include top tech names Facebook, Amazon, Netflix and Google [Alphabet], as ultimately reaping benefits from blockchain's processing power — as well as areas from health care to financials. \"A lot of investors went to bitcoin first because it was the first way to access blockchain,\" added Chiavarone. \"Look, big banks are investing in this heavily. Bank of America boasted at Davos earlier this year that they're investing the most.\" Vote Vote to see results Total Votes: Not a Scientific Survey. Results may not total 100% due to rounding. Chiavarone believes blockchain technology is valuable because it could potentially transform reconciliation, the action of verifying account balances in corporate America. \"It has an ability to replace reconciliation, which is expensive and requires back office and time and paperwork with more instantaneous verification,\" he said. \"What that means is companies can have more efficient supply chains. They can cut their back and middle office costs,\" Chiavarone said. \"And, that will allow business to flow more efficiently and it'll allow costs to be cut and net savings to be passed along.\" show chapters From earnings to the crypto space, one of Wall Street’s biggest bulls makes case for new highs 6:13 PM ET Fri, 11 May 2018 | 04:57 Disclaimer ", "author": "Alexander Demianchuk | TASS | Getty Images", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/11/blockchain-to-help-drive-next-industrial-revolution-federated.html", "keywords": [{"term": "Blockchain", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "6:13 PM ET Fri", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "May 2018", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "01:45 One of Wall Street's", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Federated Investors", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Steve Chiavarone", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "five", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "A.I.", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Friday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Trading Nation", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Bitcoin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FANG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "just months", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "20,000", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "last December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Chiavarone", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FANG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Facebook", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Amazon", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Netflix", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Google [Alphabet", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Chiavarone", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bank of America", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Davos", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "earlier this year", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Vote Vote", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "a Scientific Survey", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "100%", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "America", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Chiavarone", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "6:13 PM ET Fri", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "May 2018", "category": "DATE"}], "description": "Federated Investors’ Steve Chiavarone believes blockchain will ultimately play a major role in economic growth.", "title": "Blockchain will help ‘drive the next industrial revolution,’ a Wall Street bull predicts", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/10/26/104799506-GettyImages-854047464.jpg?v=1526076019"}, {"time": "2018-05-15T14:50:02-0400", "body": " David A. Grogan | CNBC Warren Buffett Warren Buffett once installed a slot machine on the third floor of his home, and his children learned pretty quickly it was a good way to say goodbye to their money. \"I could give my kids any allowance they wanted as long as it was in dimes. I mean, I had it all back by nightfall,\" he told shareholders at Berkshire Hathaway's 2007 annual meeting, according to CNBC's Warren Buffett Archive. The room rocked with laughter. \"I thought it would be a good lesson for them.\" Sports gambling is coming soon to several states after the Supreme Court cleared the way on Monday, but not everyone agrees it's the best way to raise state tax revenue. Buffett called gambling a \"tax on ignorance\" in response to a question at that 2007 shareholder meeting. When legal gambling was strictly limited to casinos in Las Vegas, that was one thing, he said. But making it more widely available just encouraged ... more gambling. \"The easier it's made, the more people will gamble,\" Buffett said. \"When a government makes it easy for people to take their Social Security checks and start pulling handles or participating in lotteries or whatever it may be, it's a pretty cynical act.\" Humans have a natural tendency for thrill-seeking, and that may be why gambling appeals to many, the Oracle of Omaha acknowledged. Buffett joked that he isn't immune to this human weakness. His company insures hurricanes, so he likes to watch the Weather Channel. \"It can be exciting.\" ", "author": "David A. Grogan | CNBC", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/15/warren-buffett-once-tested-his-kids-with-a-slot-machine-and-he-won.html", "keywords": [{"term": "David A. Grogan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Warren Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Warren Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Berkshire Hathaway's", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "2007", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "annual", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CNBC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Warren Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Supreme Court", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Monday", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2007", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Las Vegas", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Social Security", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Omaha", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Buffett", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Weather Channel", "category": "PERSON"}], "description": "Warren Buffett's children learned pretty quickly that gambling was a good way to say goodbye to their money.", "title": "Warren Buffett once tested his kids with a slot machine, and he won", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/07/105189672-_Y2A2288.JPG?v=1525707240"}, {"time": "2018-05-14T21:52:49-0400", "body": " Roslan Rahman | AFP | Getty Images Australia's central bank saw little reason to lift rates this month as inflation remained below target and likely to remain subdued in the face of sluggish wage growth, minutes of its May policy meeting showed. The Reserve Bank of Australia's (RBA) Board agreed there was not a \"strong case\" for a near-term adjustment in monetary policy, Tuesday's six-page minutes showed. The Board still agrees the next move was more likely up than down, assuming the economy gathered momentum as expected. The RBA last cut rates to 1.5 percent in August 2016, notching up the longest period without a change in modern history. Financial markets are wagering this steady spell could last well into 2019. Crucially, wage growth and inflation has undershot expectations for some years and showed little sign of heating up soon. Data due Wednesday is likely to show wage growth stayed near all-time lows at an annual 2.1 percent in the quarter-ended March, even as brisk job gains are expected on Thursday. RBA Deputy Governor Guy Debelle said in a speech ahead of Tuesday's minutes that Australia's wage growth has \"troughed\" and there are some tentative signs of pressure emerging. However, there is a risk it may take a lower unemployment rate than currently expected to generate a sustained move higher, he added. Australia's jobless rate has remained stubbornly stuck around 5.5 percent and levels of underemployment — those already working but wanting more hours — are