[{"mentions":"CityOfBurnet","time":"1483025402","body":"Attend financial assistance workshop Jan.10 at 9am at the Burnet Comm. Cntr, 401 E. Jackson St., @CityofBurnet. http://bit.ly/29bqhKg .","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Czzy4RxUQAAtqbx.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"9am"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the Burnet Comm"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Cntr"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"401"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"E. Jackson St."},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/814493688957177857","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1482939002","body":"Regional planning groups submit plans that provide valuable input abt their local #txwater issues. Read why we plan http://bit.ly/2hiRJnN .","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cz0CsoJUsAAJ2Y3.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/814131299610927105","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1482867003","body":"The #2017StateWaterPlan projects a 30% increase in population by 2040. Find out more about your region at http://www.texasstatewaterplan.org .","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0XfkaWUQAAraZP.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"30%"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2040"}],"link":"/twdb/status/813829313543798790","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan"]},{"mentions":"TexasSierraClub lukemetzger laurajhuffman TCEQNews","time":"1482852602","body":"Join panel abt protecting #txwater at #WaterForTX2017 w/ @TexasSierraClub @lukemetzger @laurajhuffman @TCEQNews. http://bit.ly/TX_agenda ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0JhZgbUQAAoLUj.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/813768911506141186","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1482519602","body":"Happy Holidays! Our offices will be closed December 26, 2016.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzqY4SEVEAA1iZl.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"December 26, 2016"}],"link":"/twdb/status/812372208626630656","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1482505202","body":"The #2017StateWaterPlan includes water mgmt. strategies to help meet future demand w/ conservation & reuse strategies freq. recommended.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0XeckOUQAA81A4.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"}],"link":"/twdb/status/812311812595073026","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan"]},{"time":"1482420757","body":"Are you a rainwater harvester? There's still time to apply for our Texas Rain Catcher Award! Apps due by Dec. 31. http://bit.ly/V8KfBf ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0SmveuUAAAGU5G.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 31"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811957622828048388","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1482346804","body":"The full #WaterforTX2017 conference schedule is now posted! View times, sessions, presenters, & featured speakers. http://bit.ly/TX_agenda .","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0OFPpCUcAA_arp.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"&"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811647441086844928","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterforTX2017"]},{"time":"1482334201","body":"In response to 2011 drought, the 2016 regional water plans had info abt #txdrought response. Read why we plan at http://bit.ly/2hiRJnN .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Czz-OgTUQAAC8pm.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"2011"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2016"},{"category":"FAC","term":"http://bit.ly/2hiRJnN "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811594582333018113","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txdrought"]},{"time":"1482332290","body":"TWDB opens applications for Agricultural Water Conservation Grants | Texas Water Resources Institute http://twri.tamu.edu/publications/conservation-matters/2016/december/twdb-opens-applications-for-agricultural-water-conservation-grants/#.WFqYgKh_5vs.twitter …","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"TWDB"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Agricultural Water Conservation Grants | Texas Water Resources Institute"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811586566527320064","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"evanasmith electcharles RepLyleLarson TxChuy","time":"1482267600","body":".@evanasmith moderating panel abt policy issues at #WaterForTX2017 w/ @electcharles @RepLyleLarson @TxChuy @TXRepE3. http://bit.ly/TX_agenda ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0JdwZaUQAEDGWl.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TXRepE3"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811315237806751744","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1482197401","body":"We have a number of job openings. Learn more at http://bit.ly/12yQY1o . #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C0DWh0qUAAAef1J.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/811020800991997952","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1482161400","body":"This digital image features Smith Co. and Lake Palestine and was taken as part of our strategic mapping program @TNRIS. #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Czz_DSlUkAAHnSU.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Smith Co."},{"category":"LOC","term":"Lake Palestine"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/810869802382147585","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday"]},{"mentions":"darwinarcher","time":"1481922886","body":"We look forward to hearing from you!","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/809869402762080256","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"royspence","time":"1481922816","body":"We're looking forward to your keynote speech at the awards banquet!","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/809869109001420801","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481902202","body":"The #2017StateWaterPlan recommends 5,500 #txwater management strategies. This includes conservation & reuse. http://bit.ly/2h0aDTL .","action":{"retweet":11,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzqXTOpUAAAJLCs.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"5,500"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809782647111241728","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan","txwater"]},{"mentions":"DanPatrick Glenn_Hegar AstroDude royspence","time":"1481851801","body":"Hear keynote speakers @DanPatrick, @Glenn_Hegar, @AstroDude, and @RoySpence at #WaterForTX2017 in January. http://bit.ly/TX_agenda ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzvrGzgUsAA1hYl.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@DanPatrick"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@Glenn_Hegar"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@AstroDude"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@RoySpence"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"DATE","term":"January"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809571250217644032","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1481822654","body":"Today we approved financial assistance totaling $883,557 for rural #txwater projects. http://bit.ly/2hSv2qK ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Today"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"883,557"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809448997597356033","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481820336","body":"Our Board meeting has concluded. Thanks to all participants!","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/809439275737616384","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481819975","body":"Dr. Wentzel with our staff provides water conditions update. This October was driest on record since 1952.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Wentzel"},{"category":"DATE","term":"October"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1952"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809437762860490752","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481816661","body":"We approved $483,557 to the City of Lueders for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"483,557"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Lueders"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809423859120218112","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481816407","body":"We approved $200,000 to the Loop Water Supply Corporation for #txwater treatment plant improvements.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"200,000"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Loop Water Supply Corporation"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809422794937298945","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481816250","body":"We approved $200,000 to the Commodore Cove Improvement District for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"200,000"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Commodore Cove Improvement District"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809422136444153856","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1481815840","body":"Board meeting has started. @twdb_bech @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter provide updates regarding outreach efforts.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Czujkl4VQAEWsV6.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/809420415865122816","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481815008","body":"Board meeting starting soon today at the Stephen F. Austin Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170 in Austin. Join us!","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the Stephen F. Austin Bldg"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809416926841675776","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481814003","body":"Explore the #2017StateWaterPlan for in-depth info abt #txwater planning at http://texasstatewaterplan.org .","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzqX7eqUUAAgizE.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"2017StateWaterPlan"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809412710609940481","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan","txwater"]},{"time":"1481806801","body":"Reminder: Board meeting today at the Stephen F. Austin Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170 at 9:30 a.m. in Austin.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the Stephen F. Austin Bldg"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809382505979592704","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481744701","body":"Regional planning groups submit comprehensive plans that provide valuable input abt their local #txwater issues. http://bit.ly/1gJ8h71 ","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzqQOo-VEAAl29X.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"http://bit.ly/1gJ8h71"}],"link":"/twdb/status/809122039701401600","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481729061","body":"Recent rains brought some relief, w/ about 5% of the state now impacted by drought. Read Robert's Water Weekly at http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly .","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"PERCENT","term":"about 5%"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Read Robert's"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809056438165315584","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481725801","body":"Join us at the N. Austin Job Fair today from 11am - 2pm at the Marriott N., 2600 La Frontera Blvd., Round Rock. http://bit.ly/2hJoVoV ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"FAC","term":"the N. Austin Job Fair"},{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"TIME","term":"11am - 2pm"},{"category":"LOC","term":"the Marriott N."},{"category":"DATE","term":"2600"},{"category":"FAC","term":"La Frontera Blvd"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Round Rock"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/809042765829042177","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TheBondBuyer","time":"1481655802","body":".@twdb_bech receives @TheBondBuyer award for the Southwest Region's Deal of the Year. #SWIFT #txwater","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"the Southwest Region's"},{"category":"DATE","term":"the Year"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"#SWIFT #"}],"link":"/twdb/status/808749168059617280","source":"twitter","hashTag":["SWIFT","txwater"]},{"time":"1481643000","body":"Next Board meeting is Dec. 15 at the Stephen F. Austin Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170 at 9:30 a.m. Agenda at http://bit.ly/2gHaLXM .","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Next Board"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 15"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the Stephen F. Austin Bldg"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Agenda"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/808695475855622144","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481561640","body":"Want to help us name a proposed new minor aquifer in north-central TX? Take a look & choose your favorite! http://svy.mk/2hFoThN ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzfZgZqVEAA21SQ.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/808354224916594688","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481482802","body":"Register for the #WaterForTX2017 conference Jan 23-25, 2017. Don’t miss a chance to hear from prominent speakers! http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzLg_9nUcAAtFr4.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Jan 23-25, 2017"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/808023555455807488","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1481396402","body":"Water Data for Texas has been updated w/ coastal data that helps with #txwater planning. http://bit.ly/2h7jqRv ","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzKwSA9UUAAzH2q.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/807661165195251712","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen","time":"1481236524","body":"Send an email with contact info to TWDBCommunications@twdb.texas.gov & we'll have staff contact you","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TWDBCommunications@twdb.texas.gov &"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806990591519178752","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TAWC_TTU irrigationassoc twdb","time":"1481228879","body":".@TAWC_TTU team members Phil Brown, Rick Kellison, and Jeff Pate accept @IrrigationAssoc award for project funded by @twdb.","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzLkewjUsAAcyJL.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Phil Brown"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rick Kellison"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Jeff Pate"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"@IrrigationAssoc"},{"category":"GPE","term":"@twdb"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806958523338735616","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TAWC_TTU irrigationassoc","time":"1481226025","body":"Congrats @TAWC_TTU for winning the @IrrigationAssoc 2016 National Water & Energy Conservation Award! #txwater","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzLZkDiUQAIjWHk.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"2016"},{"category":"ORG","term":"National Water & Energy Conservation Award"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806946552069517312","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481212803","body":"We plan over a 50 year period to make sure we have enough #txwater. Full infographic at http://bit.ly/2h0aDTL .","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzKiexjVIAAJ0rk.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"a 50 year period"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"txwater"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806891095871266817","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481149573","body":"Work session has concluded. Thanks to all who joined us today to talk about rural & ag #txwater issues","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"FAC","term":"& ag"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806625889152880649","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"electcharles","time":"1481145481","body":".@electcharles: we need to change attitudes about cost of water.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/806608729240195074","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"robertleetx","time":"1481144738","body":"Mayor of @robertleetx recounts the city's work to find water","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"@robertleetx"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806605611135827968","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481143254","body":".@twdb_bech: more than half our financial commitments in last 10 yrs for communities smaller than 10,000. But more needs to be done","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"more than half"},{"category":"DATE","term":"last 10 yrs"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"10,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806599386235097092","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TexasDeptofAg","time":"1481142849","body":".@TexasDeptofAg: Tx water Infrastructure Committee helps agencies collaborate to provide best funding to communities","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Infrastructure Committee"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806597687726526466","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481142144","body":"Staff: we offer funding for rural communities through several programs","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/806594730847047681","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481141463","body":"We are working on the farm and with universities and groundwater conservation districts to help improve ag efficiency-TWDB staff","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"TWDB"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806591875385872388","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TexasRuralWater","time":"1481141197","body":"Small communities are heart and soul of TX. Water is critical to sustaining them-Erin Selvera @TexasRuralWater","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Erin Selvera"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806590760200142848","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TexasFarmBureau","time":"1481140496","body":"Dan Smith of @TexasFarmBureau says ag community took initiative to become more water efficient.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Dan Smith"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806587819267342338","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1481140247","body":"Kelly Davila w/S Plains COG 'we're excited when folks from Austin can come out and hear from us.'","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Kelly Davila w/S Plains COG '"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806586775208607745","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TexasTech","time":"1481139587","body":"Great turnout for work session on #txwater and rural and ag @TexasTech","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzGP30XUkAAL5lT.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TexasTech"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806584005332258817","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"electcharles cityoflubbock","time":"1481139461","body":"Work session w/ @electcharles in @cityoflubbock underway","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzGPZcMWgAAaLy0.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"@cityoflubbock"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806583477101531137","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"lubbockonline cityoflubbock","time":"1481129472","body":"Sarah Rafique w/ @lubbockonline interviews @twdb_bech prior to @cityoflubbock 1:30pm work session abt #txwater issues for rural & ag. – at TTU - McKenzie-Merket Alumni Center","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzFpScsUUAAAqKi.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Sarah Rafique w/"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"1:30pm"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TTU"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806541582979760128","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1481125871","body":"Info in the #2017StateWaterPlan shows how Texas can ensure adequate water supplies now and in the future. More at http://bit.ly/2hiRJnN ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CzFbNUVUcAA2xjr.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806526477843959808","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan"]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock TexasTech","time":"1481117401","body":"Reminder: Work session today @cityoflubbock @TexasTech McKenzie-Merket Alum Cntr to talk #txrural & ag at 1:30pm.  Join us!","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Alum Cntr"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1:30pm"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806490951019413504","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txrural"]},{"time":"1481038202","body":"Water planning in TX is a full-time job. Chk out our interactive #2017StateWaterPlan site to find info in your area. https://2017.texasstatewaterplan.org/statewide ","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cy8P5jEUUAASfuv.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/806158767624781824","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan"]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock TexasTech","time":"1481036404","body":"Reminder: Work session @cityoflubbock @TexasTech McKenzie-Merket Alum Cntr to talk #txrural & ag at 1:30pm. Join us! #txwater","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cy68ufcWQAAmKvs.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Alum Cntr"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1:30pm"}],"link":"/twdb/status/806151225565511680","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txrural","txwater"]},{"time":"1480973850","body":"Recent rains reduced #txdrought in East TX, but moderate drought conditions deepened in the Panhandle. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"LOC","term":"East"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/805888856021204993","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txdrought"]},{"time":"1480964292","body":"Along w/ cooperators, we measured almost 7,000 wells. We use this info to support #txwater planning. http://bit.ly/16jjmCT  #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cy7zCE6UsAAb-Vd.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"almost 7,000"},{"category":"ORG","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/805848768000196610","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","MapMonday"]},{"time":"1480791603","body":"Interested in financial assistance for #txwater programs? Contact Jerry Millsaps or our regional outreach team at http://bit.ly/regteams .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx9W7lZVQAA5TaI.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Jerry Millsaps"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/805124455395532800","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock TexasTech","time":"1480692001","body":"Work session @cityoflubbock @TexasTech McKenzie-Merket Alum Cntr to talk #txrural & ag at 1:30pm. Agenda http://bit.ly/2gZUNcE . Join us!","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyrbLUTXgAAtKWy.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"@TexasTech"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"McKenzie-Merket"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Alum Cntr"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1:30pm"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804706693577703424","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txrural"]},{"mentions":"TheBondBuyer","time":"1480687083","body":"Chm @twdb_bech receiving @TheBondBuyer Southwest Deal of the Year for #SWIFT #txwater","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyrRlvgUsAAKhTs.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"LOC","term":"Southwest"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"#SWIFT #"}],"link":"/twdb/status/804686068767477760","source":"twitter","hashTag":["SWIFT","txwater"]},{"time":"1480644001","body":"Early registration for #WaterForTX2017 extended until Dec. 2! Take advantage of our lowest registration fees! http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyneeCaWIAAD8VV.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 2"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804505367535194112","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1480623111","body":"It’s official! The #2017StateWaterPlan is here & we couldn’t be more proud of all the Texans that helped. Learn abt the process this month.","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyndYTdXgAEnxT7.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"2017StateWaterPlan"},{"category":"NORP","term":"Texans"},{"category":"DATE","term":"this month"}],"link":"/twdb/status/804417751255130113","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan"]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock TexasTech","time":"1480609586","body":"We're holding a work session on December 7 at 1:30pm @cityoflubbock @TexasTech McKenzie-Merket Alumni Center. http://bit.ly/2fJFuEv ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"December 7"},{"category":"ORG","term":"1:30pm @cityoflubbock @TexasTech"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804361020131147776","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1480605580","body":"The application period for 2017 #SWIFT funding cycle is now open for #txwater projects. http://bit.ly/2gc1NPy ","action":{"retweet":8,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"2017"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"http://bit.ly/2gc1NPy "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804344220760686592","source":"twitter","hashTag":["SWIFT","txwater"]},{"time":"1480534202","body":"Through outreach across TX, we provide materials abt agriculture efficiency & the programs we offer. Learn more at http://bit.ly/15vHQXx .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx9UVxbUAAAi9-6.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804044839264387084","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1480532525","body":"Last week brought improvement to #txdrought conditions along the southern Gulf Coast but intensified in the NE. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyiEF3VXAAIoftj.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Last week"},{"category":"LOC","term":"Gulf Coast"},{"category":"GPE","term":"NE"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/804037803805966343","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txdrought"]},{"time":"1480521674","body":"We approved $1M to the Jefferson Co. Water Control & Improvement District No. 10 for wastewater treatment plant improvements. #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"$1M"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Jefferson Co. Water Control & Improvement District No"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"10"}],"link":"/twdb/status/803992293015425025","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1480521606","body":"Interested in financial assistance for #txwater programs? Contact Juan Santana or our regional outreach team at http://bit.ly/regteams .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx9Wf0nUAAA5eiH.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Juan Santana"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/803992006380896256","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1480520302","body":"Board members discuss #SWIFT 2017 funding cycle for #txwater.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"SWIFT"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"txwater"}],"link":"/twdb/status/803986536949813248","source":"twitter","hashTag":["SWIFT","txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1480520075","body":"Board meeting has started. @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter @twdb_bech provide updates on outreach efforts. #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyhUnFrVIAEW_CQ.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/803985583353827328","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1480518867","body":"Board meeting starts at 9:30 a.m. in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170. Join us or watch at http://bit.ly/2fqI9mI .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/803980516961746948","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1480514482","body":"Reminder: Board meeting today at 9:30am in the Stephen F. Austin Bldg.,1700 N. Congress, Room 170, Austin. http://bit.ly/2fLg6JR ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Stephen F. Austin Bldg.,1700 N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Austin"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/803962125546848256","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1480469400","body":"Another ag demo project we've helped fund is the TX Project for Ag Water Efficiency in the Lower Rio Grande Valley. http://bit.ly/1UwU8ej ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"the TX Project for Ag Water Efficiency"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Lower Rio Grande Valley"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/803773040815460352","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1480433932","body":"We were able to provide funds to the City of Cisco for a new urgent need #txwater treatment plant due to damage from flooding.","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CycLhNjVQAEeCuq.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CycLhN0UcAA8FYI.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CycLhN2VEAAb6Zv.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Cisco"}],"link":"/twdb/status/803624277299761152","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1480359666","body":"Interested in financial assistance for #txwater programs? Contact Scott Galaway or our regional outreach team at http://bit.ly/regteams  .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CyXweIeVEAEQdf6.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Scott Galaway"}],"link":"/twdb/status/803312780468191232","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS USGS","time":"1480347001","body":"One dataset avail. through our mapping services @TNRIS. The Geologic Atlas of TX created w/ @USGS. http://bit.ly/2ghafjG  #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx9ZisDUsAAsCnm.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"One"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"ORG","term":"The Geologic Atlas"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":"w/ @USGS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/803259658483875841","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday"]},{"mentions":"TAWC_TTU","time":"1480089604","body":"Did you know we've funded ag demo projects? @TAWC_TTU demonstrates enhanced irrigation techniques. Learn more. http://bit.ly/1U4Xiaw ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/802180058316230656","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479952800","body":"Have a safe and happy Thanksgiving! Our offices will be closed November 24 and 25.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx0ARr-UAAANE4B.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Thanksgiving"},{"category":"DATE","term":"November 24"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"25"}],"link":"/twdb/status/801606262290952192","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479916803","body":"In last 10 yrs, we’ve made commitments for $11.8B through financial assistance for water projects. Over half to entities w/ pop. <10,000.","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx5G5UpUoAATwRg.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"last 10 yrs"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"11.8B"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"Over half"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"10,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/801455280403976192","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479862802","body":"Early registration for #WaterForTX2017 extended through Dec. 2! Take advantage of our lowest registration fees! http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx3xi17VQAAxCu8.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 2"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/801228782317211648","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1479843002","body":"For the first time since October 2015, severe #TXdrought conditions can be seen in the state. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":9,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx4b6MJVIAAhMz4.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORDINAL","term":"first"},{"category":"DATE","term":"October 2015"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TXdrought"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/801145735295172608","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TXdrought"]},{"mentions":"CityofMcAllen","time":"1479828601","body":"We provide regional financial assistance workshops throughout the year. Next stop @CityofMcAllen on Dec. 6. at 9am. http://bit.ly/29bqhKg ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cx0Ce98VEAANJdN.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"the year"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 6"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9am"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/801085333689409540","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479757768","body":"Interested in financial assistance for #txwater programs? Contact Mark Evans or our regional outreach team at http://bit.ly/regteams .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxzzWZ5UUAEx_7e.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Mark Evans"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/800788238378078209","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1479742200","body":"Got a question about maps? Let @TNRIS assist you w/ physical maps & other datasets. Learn more at http://bit.ly/2gBZgTf . #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cxy4YBjUoAAipfx.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/800722942761967616","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday"]},{"mentions":"CityofAmarillo","time":"1479668403","body":"Join us at the Amarillo Farm Show November 29 – December 1 @CityofAmarillo. \nhttp://www.ideaggroup.com/amarillo ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"EVENT","term":"the Amarillo Farm Show"},{"category":"DATE","term":"November 29 – December 1"},{"category":"GPE","term":"\n"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/800413415407755264","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479582004","body":"The Water Cons. Advisory Council accepting noms until 11-30 for Blue Legacy Awards. See categories at http://www.savetexaswater.org/ .","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxkO339UQAAgzdF.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"The Water Cons."},{"category":"ORG","term":"Advisory Council"},{"category":"DATE","term":"11-30"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Blue Legacy Awards"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"http://www.savetexaswater.org/"}],"link":"/twdb/status/800051030067023872","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"WeslacoCity","time":"1479499200","body":"Join producers & ag experts for a one-day workshop December 7 from 9:30 a.m. to 4 p.m. @WeslacoCity. Register at http://bit.ly/2eUiuhQ .","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxkNF4JUQAAjjty.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"one-day"},{"category":"DATE","term":"December 7"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m. to 4 p.m. @WeslacoCity"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/799703727045308416","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479430830","body":"We provide outreach, support, & funding for communities of all sizes. Got a water project? Find your regional team http://bit.ly/regteams .","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxfmLd3UcAAHDF_.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/799416962380087296","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1479421024","body":"Our work session has ended. Thx to all who spent the afternoon w/ @twdb_bech @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter discussing regional planning","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"the afternoon"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799375833056034817","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479413510","body":"Today we approved financial assistance for 10 #txwater projects w/ 6 of those designated for rural water projects. http://bit.ly/2f4V4oY ","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Today"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"10 #"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"6"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/799344316254654465","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479411472","body":"Work session has started. Members of the 16 regional planning groups meet to discuss group structure and operation. #txwater","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxfPoBQUAAAf1kX.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"16"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799335765603913728","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479410090","body":"Work session to discuss regional water planning group structure starts at 1:30, SFA Bldg., Austin. Join or watch at http://bit.ly/2fqI9mI .","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"1:30"},{"category":"ORG","term":"SFA Bldg"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Austin"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Join"},{"category":"ORG","term":"http://bit.ly/2fqI9mI "}],"link":"/twdb/status/799329969969266692","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479404706","body":"Board meeting has concluded. Join us at 1:30pm for work session in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170. #txwater","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"1:30pm"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799307386855030784","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479404565","body":"#TXwater conditions update: reservoirs have stayed above normal, about 84% across state.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"TXwater"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"about 84%"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799306798570344452","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TXwater"]},{"time":"1479404140","body":"We authorized a request for applications for FY17 #txag water conservation grants for $600,000 from ag water conservation fund.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"FY17 #"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"600,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799305015211020289","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txag"]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock","time":"1479400805","body":"We approved $35 million to @CityofLubbock for a drainage improvement project. #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"$35 million"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799291028159287296","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"ShermanTexas","time":"1479399328","body":"We approved $11,880,000 to the Greater Texoma Utility Authority on behalf of @ShermanTexas for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"11,880,000"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Greater Texoma Utility Authority"},{"category":"GPE","term":"@ShermanTexas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799284829628022784","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479399148","body":"We approved $2,125,000 to the Greater Texoma Utility Authority on behalf of the Lake Kiowa SUD for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"2,125,000"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Greater Texoma Utility Authority"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the Lake Kiowa SUD"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799284077274812417","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479398863","body":"We approved $1,125,000 to the City of West Tawakoni for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"1,125,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of West Tawakoni"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799282880753049600","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479398604","body":"We approved $5,470,000 to the City of Hondo for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"5,470,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Hondo"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799281796936597504","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"CottonwoodShore","time":"1479398447","body":"We approved $1,395,000 to @CottonwoodShore for #txwater treatment plant improvements.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"1,395,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799281136228827136","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479398315","body":"We approved $500,000 to the City of Cisco for a new urgent need #txwater treatment plant due to flooding.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxedctEUAAAmTzL.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"500,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Cisco"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799280581561479172","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"COPearland","time":"1479397719","body":"We approved $159,500,000 to @COPearland for a #txwater treatment plant.","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"159,500,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799278081651314688","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479397569","body":"We approved $11,440,000 to the City of Anahuac for wastewater system improvements. #txwater","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"11,440,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Anahuac"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799277452384235520","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479397395","body":"We approved $5,175,000 to the City of Anahuac for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"5,175,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"the City of Anahuac"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799276725754593281","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1479396896","body":"Board meeting has started. @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter @twdb_bech provide updates on outreach efforts & activities. #txwater – at Stephen F. Austin State Office Building","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxeYCHdUcAAWBAc.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Stephen F. Austin State Office Building"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799274629328080896","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479395894","body":"Board meeting starts at 9:30 a.m. in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170. Join us or watch at http://bit.ly/2fqI9mI .","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/799270427352854528","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TheBondBuyer","time":"1479391818","body":"Our first #SWIFT transaction named @TheBondBuyer's Southwest Deal of the Year. http://bit.ly/2fzRaZb  #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORDINAL","term":"first"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TheBondBuyer"},{"category":"LOC","term":"Southwest"},{"category":"DATE","term":"the Year"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799253333861076992","source":"twitter","hashTag":["SWIFT","txwater"]},{"time":"1479387602","body":"Reminder: Board mting today in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 9:30am w/ work session at 1:30pm. #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1:30pm"}],"link":"/twdb/status/799235649882628097","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1479326401","body":"Meet David, a geologist who helps people locate groundwater resources across the state, among other things. https://youtu.be/Lp-7wFzVdCY ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"David"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798978953356550145","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1479316783","body":"#WaterForTX2017 early reg. ends soon. See @TNRIS reality sandbox at the conference! http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798938612783980544","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017","gisday2016"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1479314161","body":"It’s #GISDay! Looking for maps & data? We’ve got you covered @TNRIS! Map depicts the average precip in Texas. http://bit.ly/2eG4NXJ ","action":{"retweet":11,"reply":0,"like":12},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxZYH_7UoAEeqpV.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798927613913767936","source":"twitter","hashTag":["GISDay"]},{"time":"1479258002","body":"Early registration & Innovative Water Supply Awards close soon! Don’t miss Nov. 18 deadline for #WaterForTX2017. http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxU-AGFVEAALTqj.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 18"},{"category":"ORG","term":"#WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798692066280751104","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1479247201","body":"Due to recent rains, TX drought conditions retreated slightly from 15% to 14% of the state. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":10,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxVV-s4UkAAW3Vz.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"15%"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"14%"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798646765704445952","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479223801","body":"We've provided fin. assistance to many rural areas. San Pedro Water in Val Verde Co. rec'vd a new water well. http://bit.ly/2fE36WG .","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxPJTYLUcAEcw-7.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"San Pedro Water"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Val Verde Co."},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/798548618282237952","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479220201","body":"Reminder: Board mting Nov. 17 in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 9:30am w/ work session at 1:30pm.","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 17"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1:30pm"}],"link":"/twdb/status/798533520222060544","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1479137403","body":"We have historic & current topographic maps which can be used for recreation or measuring distances. http://bit.ly/2fNcF71  #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CxO1Y5LUkAE5ABw.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"http://bit.ly/2fNcF71  "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/798186237878104064","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday"]},{"time":"1478977201","body":"Board mting Nov. 17 in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 9:30am w/ work session at 1:30pm. http://bit.ly/2eFF0d2 ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 17"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1:30pm"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/797514304555655168","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478871000","body":"We'll be closed on Friday, November 11 in observance of Veterans Day.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwxEQHjUUAAeMlf.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Friday, November 11"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Veterans Day"}],"link":"/twdb/status/797068865045991425","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TXScienceSTAT","time":"1478797003","body":"Attending #Cast2016 in San Antonio? Stop by booth 239 & chat w/ staff, win maps, or dress up like Major Rivers! #STATx @TXScienceSTAT","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":13},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cw6nhSiUQAAO250.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"Cast2016"},{"category":"GPE","term":"San Antonio"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"239"}],"link":"/twdb/status/796758498411479040","source":"twitter","hashTag":["Cast2016","STATx"]},{"time":"1478791803","body":"Through financial programs, we assist communities by providing low-cost financing for many #txwater projects. http://bit.ly/2fBY5Os ","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwxDVweUoAAYRMK.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/796736685455396865","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1478718889","body":"We’re two-stepping our way across TX to ensure adequate #txwater supply & infrastructure. Read featured story at http://bit.ly/2fE36WG .","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cw19CtlUAAAPdwZ.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"two"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/796430862229372933","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1478703602","body":"Early registration & Innovative Water Supply Awards close soon! Don’t miss Nov. 18 deadline for #WaterForTX2017. http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwxLgEKUoAA_qUp.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 18"},{"category":"ORG","term":"#WaterForTX2017"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/796366745158225920","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"mentions":"TheBondBuyer","time":"1478703150","body":"Thanks @TheBondBuyer for the honor of winning the Deal of the Year award for the SW region! Full video at http://bit.ly/2fDEQDX . #txwater","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"@TheBondBuyer"},{"category":"ORG","term":"SW"},{"category":"FAC","term":"http://bit.ly/2fDEQDX "}],"link":"/twdb/status/796364848544251904","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1478619004","body":"We have many job openings, including a Director of Accounting & Financial Analyst. Learn more at https://lnkd.in/bjsVerT .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cwv02o5VIAI_QsW.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Accounting & Financial Analyst"}],"link":"/twdb/status/796011915403149314","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478554740","body":"Clocks jump back; drought jumps forward! Yet the recent cold front brought rain to much of TX w/ more expected. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwsKd7cUcAATWwG.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/795742373078827008","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1478532950","body":"Looking to advance your GIS skills? Check out the @TNRIS 2017 course schedule at https://tnris.org/training/ . #MapMonday","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cwq4H6LUoAAsVve.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2017"},{"category":"ORDINAL","term":" "},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMonday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/795650979593158656","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday"]},{"mentions":"TXScienceSTAT","time":"1478368804","body":"Attending #CAST2016? Stop by our booth for #txwater conservation curriculum for all ages!  http://bit.ly/2efNhb3  #STATx @TXScienceSTAT","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMkj7FUMAAUdtV.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"http://bit.ly/2efNhb3  "}],"link":"/twdb/status/794962498810249221","source":"twitter","hashTag":["CAST2016","txwater","STATx"]},{"mentions":"RainwaterRev","time":"1478275206","body":"Reminder: Join us & @twdb_DrMace @RainwaterRev from 10-4 in Dripping Springs. Open to the public. http://bit.ly/1K4k0Vl ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMhuA9UIAAOt1t.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"10-4"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Dripping Springs"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/794569921422163968","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478269802","body":"Read how TX farmers & ranchers lead in #txwater conservation in “How Do Texas Ag Producers Deal with Drought.”  \nhttp://bit.ly/2dZgPeh ","action":{"retweet":11,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMlcWnUMAAGHxS.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Texas Ag Producers"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Drought"}],"link":"/twdb/status/794547255705374720","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1478183402","body":"Enter our Innovative Water Supply Awards! Know some innovators? Nominate by Nov. 18. http://bit.ly/TXawards   #txwater #WaterForTX2017","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMlRchUMAA4Rz-.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 18"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"   "}],"link":"/twdb/status/794184866636111872","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","WaterForTX2017"]},{"mentions":"CityofAmarillo CityofMcAllen","time":"1478102402","body":"Join us at our next 2 workshops for financial assistance. Nov. 9 @CityofAmarillo & Dec. 6 @CityofMcAllen. More at http://bit.ly/29bqhKg ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMloPkUkAAbRIo.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"next 2"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 9"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@CityofAmarillo &"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 6"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/793845131275272196","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"CityofAlamo","time":"1478098824","body":"We approved $1 million to @CityofAlamo for a new wastewater treatment plant. #txwater","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"$1 million"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@CityofAlamo"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793830124260986880","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"PanhandleGCD","time":"1478098513","body":"We approved $1million in financial assistance to @PanhandleGCD for an agricultural conservation loan program. #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"1million"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@PanhandleGCD"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793828819807248384","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1478097137","body":"Board meeting has started. @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter @twdb_bech provide updates on outreach efforts and activities","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwQ511ZUEAAeBOB.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/793823046024830976","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478095393","body":"Board meeting starts at 9:30 a.m. in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave, Rm 170. Join us or watch at http://bit.ly/2fqI9mI ","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793815729967538182","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478088001","body":"Reminder: Board meeting today in Austin at the Stephen F. Austin Building, 1700 N. Congress Avenue, Room 170, at 9:30 a.m.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Stephen F. Austin Building"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress Avenue"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."}],"link":"/twdb/status/793784727014629376","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1478044802","body":"Follow us this month as we two-step our way across Texas to explore ways we ensure we all have adequate #txwater supplies.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwMZaMWUIAQDA-l.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"this month"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"two"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793603539620597763","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"RainwaterRev","time":"1478008801","body":"Don’t miss this year’s @RainwaterRev. Join us from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m. Open to the public and free to attend. http://bit.ly/1K4k0Vl ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwGuGo1VYAA_SGC.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"year"},{"category":"TIME","term":"10 a.m. to 4 p.m."},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/793452538016231426","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477962003","body":"Map developed from a hydrologic data network designed to show all surface water features. #txwater  #MapMonday #TexasMaps @TNRIS","action":{"retweet":9,"reply":0,"like":10},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwHwVUfUsAIRXQt.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"NORP","term":" "},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"TexasMaps @TNRIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793256254017798144","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","MapMonday","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1477944061","body":"Robert's Water Weekly: Drought conditions have expanded. Almost 11% of TX is now in moderate or worse drought.","action":{"retweet":11,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CwHx3cYVIAAx303.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Robert"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"Almost 11%"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793180998464774144","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1477920601","body":"Happy Halloween!","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cv3KMPLVMAAmf6q.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Halloween"}],"link":"/twdb/status/793082598960435200","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1477850403","body":"Join us at the #WaterForTX2017 conference. Early registration is available until November 18. Register at http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 .","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cv4dzr7VYAA2vA2.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"November 18"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/792788167199956993","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1477764003","body":"Board meeting on November 2 in Austin at the Stephen F. Austin Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 9:30 a.m. http://bit.ly/2fnfeiM ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cv3PZxsVYAA8HkA.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"November 2"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the Stephen F. Austin Bldg"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 a.m."},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/792425782345736192","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1477665901","body":"Today, reservoirs are 83.6% full. Check your local reservoir level at Water Data for Texas. http://bit.ly/2dOJKBW  #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cv3JTFpUkAIZomo.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Today"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"83.6%"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Water Data"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/792014311765913600","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1477593002","body":"Know of an innovative #txwater supply project that deserves recognition in tech., cons., or ed.? http://bit.ly/TXawards  #WaterForTX2017","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvohDwhUMAASNfe.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"WaterForTX2017"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791708549286137861","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1477579856","body":"Dr. Bagheri: In conclusion #GIS as a tool empowers us to better understand each other. #txgisforum","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvyElF3VUAAu8Uo.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Bagheri"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"GIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791653414551756800","source":"twitter","hashTag":["GIS","txgisforum"]},{"time":"1477578601","body":"Our major aquifer 3D interactive viewer lets you explore the major aquifers of Texas. Check it out at http://bit.ly/1QmPZnA . #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvob324UEAAQdKA.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791648147705466880","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1477578467","body":"Dr. Bagheri talks about coupling  qualitative methods and #GIS. #txgisforum","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvx_R-hVIAAN3_R.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Bagheri"},{"category":"NORP","term":" "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"GIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791647587979759617","source":"twitter","hashTag":["GIS","txgisforum"]},{"mentions":"UTSA TNRIS","time":"1477577696","body":"Dr. Nazgol Bagheri w/ @UTSA provides keynote at @TNRIS #txgisforum.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvx8VyUUIAQUn_Q.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Nazgol Bagheri"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@UTSA"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS #"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791644354532081664","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txgisforum"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS_Felicia TNRIS","time":"1477576442","body":".@TNRIS_Felicia Retiz provides updates about @TNRIS accomplishments the past year. #Lidar #Orthoimagery #Stratmap #txgisforum","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvx3jgmUsAQX78q.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Retiz"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"DATE","term":"the past year"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"#Lidar #Orthoimagery #"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791639093843152896","source":"twitter","hashTag":["Lidar","Orthoimagery","Stratmap","txgisforum"]},{"time":"1477575708","body":"Reminder to register for our upcoming conference. Join us at the #WaterforTx2017 conference. http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017  #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvx0wRgVMAABV1s.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017  "}],"link":"/twdb/status/791636014972362752","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterforTx2017","txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477575540","body":"Day two of the @TNRIS #txgisforum has begun! Richard Wade welcomes attendees.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvx0HbSUsAAaI8A.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"two"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Richard Wade"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791635311302316032","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txgisforum"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477511428","body":"Great video of our augmented sandbox @TNRIS #txgisforum. Thanks for sharing!","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791366404213579776","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txgisforum","txgisforum","GIS"]},{"mentions":"meaganrenee09","time":"1477508199","body":"The photo on our home page is the Pecos River.","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"LOC","term":"the Pecos River"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791352861489672192","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477498958","body":"Great crowd at @TNRIS #txgisforum!","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvtP-ZUVMAA4GkJ.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvtP-ZVVMAARG07.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvtP-ZUVMAEsoaG.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791314102635208704","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txgisforum"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477497857","body":"Visual Texas on display @TNRIS #texasGISforum. Zooming to actual location of conference at J.J. Pickle Center in Austin.","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Visual Texas"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"texasGISforum"},{"category":"ORG","term":"J.J. Pickle Center"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791309483104317440","source":"twitter","hashTag":["texasGISforum"]},{"time":"1477492775","body":"Ballard discovered RMS Titanic in 1985. #texasgisforum","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvs4Y_oUsAAOgLd.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"RMS Titanic"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1985"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791288168708321281","source":"twitter","hashTag":["texasgisforum"]},{"mentions":"EVNautilus","time":"1477490806","body":"Oceanographer Dr. Robert Ballard w/ @EVNautilus & @GSO_URI keynote speaker at #texasgisforum. Wanted to be Captain Nemo as a kid.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvsw4PRUkAATi0h.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Robert Ballard"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Nemo"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791279912116039684","source":"twitter","hashTag":["texasgisforum"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477490112","body":".@twdb_bech talks about our resources @TNRIS and thanks staff for all they do. #texasgisforum #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvsuO2tVYAQ0swM.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"#texasgisforum"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791277000036016128","source":"twitter","hashTag":["texasgisforum","txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477489865","body":".@TNRIS debuts new video with Geoff Isaac Stewart explaining GIS to @twdb_bech. We'll post full video soon.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvstSh0UkAEekbs.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvstSh3UMAAw6K_.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Geoff Isaac Stewart"},{"category":"ORG","term":"GIS"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791275963560570881","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477488859","body":"Richard Wade @TNRIS kicks off #texasgisforum conference.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvspc6fVMAAPOlg.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Richard Wade @TNRIS"},{"category":"ORG","term":"#"}],"link":"/twdb/status/791271743088320513","source":"twitter","hashTag":["texasgisforum"]},{"mentions":"CityofAmarillo","time":"1477488601","body":"Attend our financial assistance workshop on Nov. 9 at 9am @CityofAmarillo, Panhandle Commission, 415 W. 8th. http://bit.ly/29bqhKg .","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvn3VlwVMAQmP3G.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 9"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9am"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@CityofAmarillo, Panhandle Commission"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"415"},{"category":"DATE","term":"W. 8th"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/791270661326905345","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477418404","body":"Map from 2001 near Harris County using Lidar, which is elevation data collected by @TNRIS. #TexasMaps #MapMadness","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvn1EE5UsAAHhUh.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"2001"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Harris County"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Lidar"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"MapMadness"}],"link":"/twdb/status/790976233966215168","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps","MapMadness"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477406127","body":".@TNRIS #TexasGISForum kicks offs tomorrow featuring @twdb_bech & Geoff Isaac Stewart. Miss last year’s video? http://bit.ly/2eHvt7H ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"#TexasGISForum"},{"category":"DATE","term":"tomorrow"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@twdb_bech & Geoff"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Isaac Stewart"},{"category":"DATE","term":"last year’s"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/790924742546984961","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasGISForum"]},{"time":"1477355401","body":"Do you know the major #txwater resources? You can download this map and others at http://bit.ly/1dHBhsk . #MapMonday #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":12,"reply":0,"like":12},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvjnUbVUMAAfuSZ.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"MapMonday"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/790711979870650368","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","MapMonday","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1477319400","body":"Drought conditions expanded in East TX & Lower Rio Grande Valley & reappeared in Corpus Christi area. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly  #txwater","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cvid6GjUMAAQZ3l.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"East TX & Lower Rio Grande Valley &"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Corpus Christi"}],"link":"/twdb/status/790560982494044160","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1477245600","body":".@TNRIS maintains historic photos & #TexasMaps dating back to the 1800's. Specific request in mind?Contact https://tnris.org/contact/ .","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":7},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvUTbm6VMAAE-va.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"1800"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/790251441474502656","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"mentions":"txst","time":"1477159202","body":"We’ll be at the fall Career & Internship Fair @txst Oct. 25 from noon – 4pm at the LBJ Student Ctr.  in San Marcos. http://bit.ly/2dkW8Jl ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvD6CclUAAATM4B.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"EVENT","term":"Career & Internship Fair"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 25"},{"category":"TIME","term":"noon – 4pm"},{"category":"FAC","term":"the LBJ Student Ctr"},{"category":"GPE","term":"San Marcos"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/789889064157655041","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1477060202","body":"Don't wait! Join us at the Water for Texas 2017 conference. Register at http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvOC2rBVMAAyiom.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"WORK_OF_ART","term":"the Water for Texas"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2017"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/789473827487117312","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"cityoflubbock TNRIS","time":"1476975604","body":"Map from 2005 near @cityoflubbock using orthoimagery, which is digital aerial photography taken from aircraft. @TNRIS  #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvJyZjbVYAAp3um.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"2005"},{"category":"GPE","term":"@cityoflubbock"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789118997144883200","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476973245","body":"The Board meeting has concluded. Thanks to all attendees!","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Board"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789109103746428928","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476973071","body":"Staff provides updates on #txwater conditions. Reservoir levels are at 84%.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvN533UVMAAlNqT.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Reservoir"},{"category":"PERCENT","term":"84%"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789108370150035460","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1476972797","body":"We approved the designation of brackish groundwater production zones in areas of the Carrizo-Wilcox, Gulf Coast, Rustler, & Blaine Aquifers.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvN41ROVMAUjoVz.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"FAC","term":"the Carrizo-Wilcox"},{"category":"LOC","term":"Gulf Coast"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rustler"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789107222387171332","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"fema","time":"1476971251","body":"We approved more than $54 million in @fema flood mitigation grants. #txwater","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"more than $54 million"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789100739314323456","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1476970339","body":"Board meeting has started. @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter @twdb_bech provide updates on outreach efforts & activities. #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvNvdR6VUAAqG4N.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/789096915220606976","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1476969624","body":"Board meeting starts at 8:30 a.m. today in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170. Join us!","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"TIME","term":"8:30 a.m."},{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"}],"link":"/twdb/status/789093916117078016","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476901800","body":"Reminder: We’re holding a Board meeting Oct. 20 in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 8:30 a.m.","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Board"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 20"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"8:30 a.m."}],"link":"/twdb/status/788809440556228609","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476888564","body":"You can also check out http://www.wildflower.org/  to search for native Texas plants!","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"http://www.wildflower.org/"},{"category":"PRODUCT","term":"  "},{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/788753924194836483","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasNativePlantWeek","TXplants","NativePlants","Texas"]},{"time":"1476816262","body":"Mr. Kent Satterwhite w/ Canadian River Muni. Water Authority talks abt response to pipeline leak experienced late 2015/early 2016.","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvEjsxSUAAA4wUC.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvEjsxRUIAUYc8Y.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Kent Satterwhite"},{"category":"NORP","term":"Canadian"},{"category":"DATE","term":"late 2015/early 2016"}],"link":"/twdb/status/788450669237706752","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476801429","body":"Check out the #2017StateWaterPlan interactive site to see how #txwater is being used in your county.  http://bit.ly/2dYnSkZ . #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":18,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvDfU9FUsAEpZQ_.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvDfVmuVYAAu57I.jpg","https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CvDfWfuUsAAjl9x.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"#"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/788388451389276161","source":"twitter","hashTag":["2017StateWaterPlan","txwater","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476750601","body":"We'll be at the South Texas Farm & Ranch show Oct.19-20 in Victoria, TX. Stop by our booth for ag water info. http://bit.ly/2dN4EzU ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"FAC","term":"the South Texas Farm & Ranch"},{"category":"PRODUCT","term":"Oct.19-20"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Victoria"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"http://bit.ly/2dN4EzU"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/788175264454889472","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476738673","body":"Dry conditions expanded this past week; some counties in NE Texas are now in moderate drought. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly  #txwater","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cu_4A57VMAEAYKs.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Dry"},{"category":"DATE","term":"this past week"},{"category":"ORG","term":"NE Texas"}],"link":"/twdb/status/788125237585940480","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1476714603","body":"Digital image created from historical aerial photography taken in 1977 near the coast in Cameron Co. @TNRIS #MapMonday #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cu-Zz0QVUAAuAOC.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Digital"},{"category":"DATE","term":"1977"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Cameron Co."},{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"#"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/788024276880326657","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476640803","body":"Register now for the #WaterForTX2017 Conference. Don’t miss a chance to hear from several prominent speakers! http://bit.ly/WaterTX2017 ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuqxkL7VYAU6ykW.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Register"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/787714738616610816","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"mentions":"EPAwatersense","time":"1476547204","body":"#ShowerBetter with an @EPAwatersense labeled showerhead, and save the electricity to power your home for 13 days a year!","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuqsaTZUAAALhpZ.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"ShowerBetter"},{"category":"DATE","term":"13 days"}],"link":"/twdb/status/787322155998416896","source":"twitter","hashTag":["ShowerBetter"]},{"time":"1476455400","body":"We’re holding a Board meeting Oct. 20 in Austin at the SFA Bldg., 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm 170, at 8:30 a.m. http://bit.ly/2el21qX ","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Board"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 20"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm 170"},{"category":"TIME","term":"8:30 a.m."}],"link":"/twdb/status/786937103678451712","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476374403","body":"On our TX Flood Viewer, you can monitor flood gages, weather radar & alerts, & lake conditions. http://map.texasflood.org/  #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":6,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CupwbffUkAAeK16.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX Flood Viewer"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"  "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/786597377951961094","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476290635","body":"X Marks the Spot. Read how we use maps to share info about #txwater at http://bit.ly/2dXATwZ . #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CulOVpgVIAAYAHp.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"about #"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/786246029800710145","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476209261","body":"A dry 4 weeks results in appearance of moderate drought. Reservoirs are relatively full w/ some exceptions. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CugTbUaUsAE-hHu.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"4 weeks"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Reservoirs"},{"category":"DATE","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/785904721575849984","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TNRIS","time":"1476195720","body":"Do you know about @TNRIS? Get to know your state geography and explore #TexasMaps! http://tnris.org/  #MapMadness","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CufglAcXEAAsvaO.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@TNRIS"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"http://tnris.org/  "}],"link":"/twdb/status/785847926631301120","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps","MapMadness"]},{"time":"1476135191","body":"TWDB Innovative Water Supply Awards are now open!  Learn more on the Water for Texas 2017 website. http://waterfortexas.twdb.texas.gov/awards.asp ","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":7},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Cub2FeOVYAA6NIu.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"TWDB"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Innovative Water Supply Awards"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Learn"},{"category":"WORK_OF_ART","term":"the Water for Texas 2017"}],"link":"/twdb/status/785594050598408192","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476124202","body":"Do you know if you live in a river basin? Or above an aquifer? Chk out our maps to find out! http://bit.ly/1dHBhsk  #MapMonday #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":9,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuMMpxUUEAAK-SW.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/785547956200083457","source":"twitter","hashTag":["MapMonday","TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1476108002","body":"We have a number of positions including a Coastal Scientist & GIS Specialist. Chk out these positions & others at http://bit.ly/12yQY1o .","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuMHyPnUIAASpIn.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"LAW","term":"a Coastal Scientist & GIS Specialist"},{"category":"PRODUCT","term":"Chk"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/785480009720799232","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1476028800","body":"The Water Conservation Advisory Council now accepting nominations for the 2017 Blue Legacy Awards, due Nov. 30. http://www.savetexaswater.org/ ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuG3tujVUAAQNYB.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"The Water Conservation Advisory Council"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2017"},{"category":"EVENT","term":"Blue Legacy Awards"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Nov. 30"}],"link":"/twdb/status/785147813025939456","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"cityofwaco","time":"1475949601","body":"We’ll be @cityofwaco STEAM Day Oct. 11 at the convention center. Join us & learn abt #txwater science & technology! http://bit.ly/2dVSWVe ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"STEAM Day"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 11"}],"link":"/twdb/status/784815626846175232","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1475865000","body":"Attend our regional financial assistance workshop on Oct. 11 at 9am at the public library in  Corsicana. http://bit.ly/29bqhKg . #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuG1w2hUkAAxAK5.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 11"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9am"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Corsicana"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/784460785615372288","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1475850600","body":"Did you know you can use Water Data Interactive to locate water wells? Type in your address  http://bit.ly/GWtxdata . #TexasMaps","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuGyRVXVUAQwucx.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Water Data Interactive"},{"category":"NORP","term":" "},{"category":"ORG","term":" "},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"}],"link":"/twdb/status/784400388044759040","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps"]},{"time":"1475778600","body":"Spread the word! The #WaterForTX2017 Innovative Water Supply Awards open Monday. Learn more at http://bit.ly/TXawards ","action":{"retweet":4,"reply":0,"like":4},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuGmPliUkAAHM7M.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"WaterForTX2017 Innovative Water Supply Awards"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Monday"}],"link":"/twdb/status/784098399645827073","source":"twitter","hashTag":["WaterForTX2017"]},{"time":"1475764200","body":"Looking for the best GIS training in the state? Register for the Texas GIS Forum. You don’t want to miss it!  http://bit.ly/2dH3SGO ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ct8y8uHUIAEjIZf.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"the Texas GIS Forum"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/784038000263065600","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TML_Texas","time":"1475690823","body":"We're at @TML_Texas Conference in Austin Oct 5-6. Stop by booth #621 to ask questions or say hi! #TMLAC2016","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":5},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"621"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TMLAC2016"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783730233878851584","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TMLAC2016"]},{"mentions":"TXColoradoRiver USGS","time":"1475685861","body":"According to @USGS there are 7510 miles of streams in the Colorado basin","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"@USGS"},{"category":"QUANTITY","term":"7510 miles"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Colorado"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783709423935959040","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1475682127","body":"We approved $54,700,000 in financial assistance for #txwater and wastewater system improvements. http://bit.ly/2dePnVD ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"54,700,000"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"txwater"},{"category":"PERSON","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/783693759959617537","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1475679351","body":"Our Board meeting has concluded. Thanks to everyone who participated! #txwater","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/783682118123593728","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"LaPorteByTheBay","time":"1475679034","body":"We approved $10,635,000 to @LaPorteByTheBay for wastewater system improvements. #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"10,635,000"},{"category":"GPE","term":"@LaPorteByTheBay"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783680785714778112","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"CityEaglePassTx","time":"1475678814","body":"We approved $44,065,000 to @CityEaglePassTx for #txwater system improvements.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"44,065,000"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783679865077788672","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"twdb_kathleen twdb_peter","time":"1475678002","body":"Board members @twdb_bech @twdb_kathleen @twdb_peter provide updates about outreach efforts & activities. #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CuAtlXlW8AAtt6F.jpg"],"keywords":[],"link":"/twdb/status/783676461093904384","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1475677029","body":"Board meeting today at 9:30 am in SFA Bldg., Room 170, Austin. Join us or watch live at //texasadmin.com/tx/twdb/  #txwater","action":{"retweet":0,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"TIME","term":"9:30 am in SFA Bldg"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783672378618503168","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"mentions":"EPAwatersense","time":"1475676002","body":"We’re celebrating #ShowerBetter with @EPAwatersense! Get in on the action at http://bit.ly/ShowerSwitch .","action":{"retweet":5,"reply":0,"like":3},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ct8tdCjUsAkemmn.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"MONEY","term":"ShowerBetter"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/783668069860192256","source":"twitter","hashTag":["ShowerBetter"]},{"time":"1475668800","body":"Reminder: We are holding a Board meeting today in Austin at the SFA Bldg. 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm. 170, at 9:30am.","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Board"},{"category":"DATE","term":"today"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"}],"link":"/twdb/status/783637864475090945","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"twdb_peter austintexasgov","time":"1475607603","body":".@twdb_peter & staff tour Seaholm rainwater sys. @austintexasgov, winner of 2015 TX Rain Catcher Awd. Apply for 2016 http://bit.ly/V8KfBf ","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ct8eIvLUkAAcR6Q.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"PERSON","term":"Seaholm"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"@austintexasgov"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2015"},{"category":"ORG","term":"TX Rain Catcher Awd"},{"category":"DATE","term":"2016"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/783381185023967232","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"HPUWCD","time":"1475591400","body":"Students 9-12 who live or go to school in the @HPUWCD area are encouraged to enter the H2YOU contest by Dec. 5. http://www.hpwd.org/contest/ ","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ct2fKZhVIAESvRf.png"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9-12"},{"category":"ORG","term":"@HPUWCD"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"H2YOU"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Dec. 5"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/783313225278431232","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1475526078","body":"Despite a record rainy end to summer, patches of drought continue across parts of TX. http://bit.ly/WaterWeekly ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":0},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"TX"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/783039244478521345","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"time":"1475505001","body":"Most of us use maps every day to plan, discover, & explore. We’re mad for #TexasMaps this month! #MapMadness","action":{"retweet":3,"reply":0,"like":6},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CtnLydKVMAAXE2Z.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"DATE","term":"every day"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"TexasMaps"},{"category":"DATE","term":"this month"}],"link":"/twdb/status/782950839023312896","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TexasMaps","MapMadness"]},{"time":"1475431201","body":"We are holding a Board meeting October 5, 2016 in Austin at the SFA Bldg. 1700 N. Congress Ave., Rm. 170, at 9:30am.","action":{"retweet":2,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":[],"keywords":[{"category":"ORG","term":"Board"},{"category":"DATE","term":"October 5, 2016"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"ORG","term":"the SFA Bldg"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"1700"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"N. Congress"},{"category":"PERSON","term":"Rm"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"170"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"9:30am"}],"link":"/twdb/status/782641300851929089","source":"twitter","hashTag":[]},{"mentions":"TML_Texas","time":"1475337602","body":"We’re at the @TML_Texas Conference in Austin Oct. 4-7, booth #621. Stop by! #TMLAC2016 http://tmlconference.org/ ","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":1},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CtcaPmsVIAAIkZH.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Austin"},{"category":"DATE","term":"Oct. 4-7"},{"category":"MONEY","term":"621"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/782248719907483649","source":"twitter","hashTag":["TMLAC2016"]},{"time":"1475283600","body":"We are hiring two Executive Assistants. Learn more about our job opportunities at http://bit.ly/12yQY1o . #txwater","action":{"retweet":1,"reply":0,"like":2},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ctm5_9uUMAAV97h.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"two"},{"category":"ORG","term":"Executive Assistants"},{"category":"ORG","term":" "}],"link":"/twdb/status/782022218394038272","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater"]},{"time":"1475245804","body":"Did you know that Texas has 191,000 miles of streams & rivers? That's like walking 8 times around the Earth! #txwater #BackToSchool","action":{"retweet":16,"reply":0,"like":8},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CtTe2hCUEAAn5sT.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Texas"},{"category":"QUANTITY","term":"191,000 miles"},{"category":"CARDINAL","term":"8"},{"category":"LOC","term":"Earth"}],"link":"/twdb/status/781863689502674946","source":"twitter","hashTag":["txwater","BackToSchool"]},{"time":"1475159405","body":"X is for Xeriscape: Xeriscape is a fantastic, drought-tolerant option that requires less water than a traditional landscape. #BackToSchool","action":{"retweet":7,"reply":0,"like":9},"img":["https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CtTd9FdVMAA2fjd.jpg"],"keywords":[{"category":"GPE","term":"Xeriscape"},{"category":"GPE","term":"Xeriscape"}],"link":"/twdb/status/781501303994261504","source":"twitter","hashTag":["BackToSchool"]},{"time":"1475073005","body":"W is for Water IQ: Know your water. The Water IQ program educates Texans about their wa