[{"time": "2018-05-02T10:25:38-0400", "body": " show chapters Full interview with John Calamos at the 2018 Milken Institute Global Conference 7:09 PM ET Tue, 1 May 2018 | 05:08 The Trump administration's focus on deregulation and the return of rising interest rates should benefit financial and banking stocks, according to Calamos Investments founder and chairman John Calamos Sr. \"I'm not overly worried that the interest rates start to go back to normal. We forget that if interest rates were more normal, banks would be doing better,\" he said during an interview with CNBC on Tuesday from the Milken Institute's global conference. \"If the banks had the ability to be loaning out more money, especially the smaller and mid-sized banks: that creates jobs. That's what's been lacking over the last 10 years.\" Calamos' comments came amid a return to historical levels of volatility in equity markets after an unusually calm 2017. Despite extremely wide swings and days with 1,000-point Dow Jones industrial average losses, stock strategists have remained largely confident stocks will ultimately adjust to rising interest rates. That process has been turbulent thus far, with the yield on the benchmark 10-year note topping 3 percent for the first time since 2014 last week and sparking a new round of uncertainty in the middle of earnings season. But, Calamos said, significant deregulation – a top priority of President Donald Trump's administration – could help ease the transition back to higher borrowing costs. Members of Congress are working to adjust aspects of the Dodd-Frank regulatory overhaul, which was passed in the aftermath of the financial crisis in an effort to tighten the behavior of a banking industry blamed for much of the economic instability. In March, the Senate voted to ease regulations on all but the largest banks, which would raise the level at which banks are considered \"systemically important\" and exempts smaller banks from other rules aiming to curb risky behavior. This deregulation \"is a tailwind for growth in the economy and I hope that continues. The worst economies in the world are going to be the ones that are over-regulated,\" Calamos said. Investors should see appreciation in financial and bank stocks, he explained, but other industries – like food and health care could see upside as well. Calamos, now in his seventies, took his mutual fund public in 2004 after decades of managing money outside the public sphere. His fund is often associated with growth equity as well as convertible bonds. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/02/105177384-GettyImages-676476436.jpg?v=1525259053", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "John Calamos"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2018"}, {"category": "EVENT", "term": "Milken Institute Global Conference 7:09 PM ET Tue"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Trump administration's"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Calamos Investments"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "John Calamos Sr"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Milken Institute's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the last 10 years"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "and days"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1,000-point"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Dow Jones"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "10-year"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "3 percent"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2014"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last week"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Calamos"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Donald Trump"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Congress"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Dodd-Frank"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Senate"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "his seventies"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2004"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "decades"}], "description": "Deregulation and the return of interest rates should benefit financial and banking stocks, John Calamos Sr. said Tuesday.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/calamos-says-us-economy-will-be-just-fine-as-rising-rates-deregulation-benefit-banking-sector.html", "author": "Patrick T. Fallon | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "title": "Calamos says US economy will be just fine as rising rates, deregulation benefit banking sector"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T14:31:43-0400", "body": " David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images Jen-Hsun Huang, CEO, Nvidia Barclays upgraded Nvidia to overweight on Thursday, citing swelling demand for semiconductors over the next several years and conceding to investors that it was behind the times on the company. \"We obviously are late to the party after two substantial years of outperformance but after taking a clean look at the AI landscape, we believe Nvidia is an overweight,\" analyst Blayne Curtis wrote in a note. \"Once again, ecosystem does matter and we believe that Nvidia has out a large moat around certain markets, like autos, and aims to create a similar ecosystem in robots,\" he added. The company's stock is up 117 percent in the past 12 months through Wednesday compared with the S&P 500's 10.3 percent gain. That performance ranks No. 2 in the entire S&P 500. The shares are down 11 percent from its high on March 13. The stock is up 2.7 percent Thursday. Curtis also bumped his price target on the stock to $280, implying 23 percent upside over the next 12 months. The stock opened slightly higher on Thursday. While the need for chips will likely scale over several years as more firms integrate AI platforms, the analyst noted that the company is likely seeing growth in its gaming segments thanks to new massive multiplayer online games in 2018 including Fortnite. Nvidia is expected to launch new Volta chip-based graphics cards — considered the company's next big step in the video games space — later this year, a release many on Wall Street think could carry profits higher. \"As opposed to last year's lack of gaming launches, 2018 has already brought on titles like PlayerUnknown's Battlegrounds and Fortnite, which are driving a revitalized cycle in gaming communities,\" Curtis said. \"Nvidia is also gaining share, which should be bolstered by the launch of Volta later this year and should have plenty of runway.\" Disclaimer ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/10/16/104775763-GettyImages-631003698-nvidia.jpg?v=1538139597", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "David Paul Morris"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bloomberg"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Getty Images Jen-Hsun Huang"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Nvidia Barclays"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Nvidia"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the next several years"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "two"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "AI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Nvidia"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Blayne Curtis"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Nvidia"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "117 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the past 12 months through Wednesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the S&P 500's"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "10.3 percent"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "11 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March 13"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "2.7 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Curtis"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "280"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "23 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the next 12 months"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "several years"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "AI"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2018"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Fortnite"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Nvidia"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Volta"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "later this year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last year's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2018"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "PlayerUnknown"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Curtis"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Nvidia"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Volta"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "later this year"}], "description": "Swelling demand for semiconductors over the next several years spells even better performance for chipmaker Nvidia, according to Barclays.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/nvidia-upgraded-at-barclays-as-chipmakers-unparalleled-scale-in-autos-robotics-spell-upside.html", "author": "David Paul Morris | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "title": "Nvidia upgraded by Barclays, sees 20 percent surge in next 12 months"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T03:15:13-0400", "body": " show chapters Bank of Singapore 'committed' to growth in Middle East 4:40 AM ET Thu, 3 May 2018 | 02:51 Bank of Singapore is upbeat on its prospects in the Middle East after getting off to a strong start to the year, a top executive at the institution said Thursday. The private banking arm of OCBC, Singapore's second-largest lender by total assets, saw its assets under management in Dubai grow about 30 percent from its launch in the city's financial center last year, according to Reuters. \"I firmly believe and I'm very optimistic about the prospects of the region,\" Vikram Malhotra, Bank of Singapore's global market head for South Asia and the Middle East, told CNBC's Sri Jegarajah. The bank moved to its premises in Dubai International Financial Centre in 2016 and currently has more than one hundred employees based in the city. Private financial wealth in the Middle East and Africa is estimated to grow 8.1 percent by the end of 2021 to $12 trillion, according to a global wealth report from the Boston Consulting Group last year. That growth figure is only surpassed by the 9.9 percent increase projected for the Asia Pacific region. Malhotra also weighed in on competition for clients in the region, as well as a greater focus on regulation, amid greater focus on regulations. \"I think that's pretty much industry-specific. All the global banks are present in Dubai and are investing and growing in the region. Having said that, I think we have grown much faster than our competitors,\" he said. \"Of course, regulatory expectations are much higher today and everybody is investing in that regard as well,\" Malhotra said. Less than half of the roughly 30 employees joining Bank of Singapore's Dubai branch last year were bankers as it focused on growing its support staff, he added. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/03/105180165-GettyImages-945485408.jpg?v=1525326836", "keywords": [{"category": "ORG", "term": "Bank of Singapore '"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "Middle East"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "3"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "02:51 Bank of Singapore"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "the Middle East"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "OCBC"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Singapore"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "second"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Dubai"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "about 30 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Reuters"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Vikram Malhotra"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bank of Singapore's"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "South Asia"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "the Middle East"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Sri Jegarajah"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Dubai International Financial Centre"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2016"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "more than one hundred"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "the Middle East"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "Africa"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "8.1 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the end of 2021"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "$12 trillion"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Boston Consulting Group"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last year"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "9.9 percent"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "the Asia Pacific region"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Malhotra"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Dubai"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "today"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Malhotra"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "Less than half"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "roughly 30"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bank of Singapore's"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Dubai"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last year"}], "description": "The private banking arm of OCBC saw its assets under management in Dubai grow approximately 30 percent last year.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/bank-of-singapore-upbeat-on-its-prospects-in-the-middle-east.html", "author": "Christopher Pike | Bloomberg | Getty Images ", "title": "Bank of Singapore is upbeat on its Middle East prospects"}, {"time": "2018-05-01T12:42:59-0400", "body": " show chapters Ethereum falls on report second-biggest cryptocurrency is under regulatory scrutiny: WSJ 12:43 PM ET Tue, 1 May 2018 | 01:01 Ethereum prices took a hit Tuesday after a report that regulators are exploring whether it and other cryptocurrencies should be treated like securities. Both U.S. commodities and securities watchdogs are questioning whether the same rules for stocks should apply to these digital currencies, The Wall Street Journal reported Tuesday. Until now, cryptocurrencies have not been drawn into wider crackdowns by the Securities and Exchange Commission this year. The cryptocurrency's creation in 2014 was \"probably an illegal securities sale\" in the eyes of some regulators, the Journal said, citing people familiar with the matter. show chapters Here's what sets ethereum apart from its rival bitcoin 8:10 AM ET Tue, 27 June 2017 | 02:21 Ether, which has a roughly $65 billion market cap, fell about 6 percent Tuesday, and was trading near $652, according to data from CoinMarketCap.com. The analysis is based on whether founders of virtual currencies other than bitcoin have any control over their value, similar to how a company's managers might influence a company's stock value based on strategy and investments, the Journal said. Two federal regulatory agencies have applied different definitions to what exactly a cryptocurrency is. The Commodity Futures Trading Commission has labeled them as commodities, meaning they're exempt from SEC regulation. The SEC on the other hand, has indicated that it sees cryptocurrencies as securities. In March, the agency said it is looking to apply securities laws to everything from cryptocurrency exchanges to digital asset storage companies known as wallets. Senior SEC and CFTC officials are among those scheduled to discuss the matter on Monday, the Journal reported, citing people familiar with the matter. The Ethereum foundation raised more than 31,000 bitcoin in July 2014, worth about $18.3 million at the time, when it first sold the first 60 million ether. Because investors were speculating that the launch would result in a rise in asset value, the deal resembled a security, the Journal said. Ethereum is the name of the company that created the digital token ether. The company created a platform for applications built on blockchain, the same technology that underpins bitcoin. Ether was first launched as a fundraising effort to develop the platform. A consortium called the Enterprise Ethereum Alliance, which includes companies like Microsoft and J.P. Morgan, is developing uses for the Ethereum blockchain. WATCH: There's a house full of cryptocurrency gurus in San Francisco, and it's like a modern-day commune show chapters There's a house full of cryptocurrency gurus in San Francisco, and it's like a modern-day commune 9:01 AM ET Sat, 5 Aug 2017 | 01:57 ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/05/01/105174288-GettyImages-951165946.jpg?v=1536697346", "keywords": [{"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "second"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "12:43 PM ET Tue"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "01:01"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Wall Street Journal"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Securities and Exchange Commission"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "this year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2014"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Journal"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "8:10 AM ET Tue"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "27 June 2017"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "roughly $65 billion"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "about 6 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "652"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Journal"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "Two"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Commodity Futures Trading Commission"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SEC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SEC"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SEC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CFTC"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Monday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Journal"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Ethereum"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "more than 31,000"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "July 2014"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "about $18.3 million"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "60 million"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Journal"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Enterprise Ethereum Alliance"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Microsoft"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "J.P. Morgan"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Ethereum"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "San Francisco"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "San Francisco"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "9:01 AM ET Sat"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "5"}], "description": "Regulators are looking into whether cryptocurrencies including ether, the second-largest by market capitalization, should be treated like securities, according to The Wall Street Journal.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/01/ethereum-falls-on-report-second-biggest-cryptocurrency-is-under-regulatory-scrutiny.html", "author": "Getty Images", "title": "Ethereum falls on report that the second-biggest cryptocurrency is under regulatory scrutiny"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T12:10:56-0400", "body": " show chapters Tesla earnings call was the best I've heard in a long time, says Jim Cramer 10:02 AM ET Thu, 3 May 2018 | 02:52 Shares of Tesla fell on Thursday after CEO Elon Musk delivered a bizarre earnings conference call. Musk dismissed a question from Toni Sacconaghi, an analyst at Bernstein, about gross margins, calling it \"boring.\" The stock's decline and Musk's comments took place after the company reported a narrower-than-expected loss for the previous quarter. Here's a wrap of all the major analyst opinions going out to Wall Street pros regarding Tesla on Thursday. Bank of America Merrill Lynch (Underperform): \"Key takeaways were as follows: 1) Revenue of $3.41bn was a bit ahead of our $3.29bn estimate, as lighter deliveries (relative to BofAML estimates) were offset by a greater proportion of vehicles sold with immediate revenue recognition; 2) Reported total company gross margin of 13.4% was lower than our 17.4% estimate, as Automotive was roughly in line and other segments relatively weak, although Auto gross margin of 19.7% was down roughly 800bps+ YoY due primarily to the slow Model 3 ramp; and 3) Operating expenses (SG&A, R&D) of $1.05bn were just above our $1.02bn forecast, up both YoY and sequentially.\" Bernstein (Hold): \"Tesla's Q1 earnings call was a unique experience, to say the least. For those who missed it – halfway through the call, CEO Elon Musk abruptly declared that our questions were 'boring' and 'not cool,' and pivoted to a 20-minute back-and-forth with a retail investor from YouTube. Beneath the bizarre theatrics, however, we see Tesla's Q1 as in-line with expectations on most metrics, including revenues, gross margins, and free cash flow.\" Morgan Stanley (Hold): \"To be clear. Tonight's conference call didn't go very well. Feedback we have received from investors during and following the call support this view. Irrespective of the Tesla CEO's annoyance with the genre of questions he was receiving from the analyst community, we note that an important part of Tesla's success has been its relationship with the capital markets in funding its ambitious plans.\" J.P. Morgan (Sell): \"Tesla reported mixed 1Q results after the close yesterday, marked by better than expected revenue, margin, & EPS but accompanied by a bigger than expected cash outflow and record net loss. Given that the market has seemed somewhat less focused on cash burn than we have been, initially we believed that the 1Q performance — combined with forceful management guidance for a strong 2H inflection in revenue, margin, and cash flow — would be enough to elicit a modestly positive reaction in the shares Thursday. Instead, we expect TSLA to fall today after CEO Elon Musk dismissed multiple analyst questions as 'dry' and 'boring' (including questions probing what we feel are key topics, such as profitability of the Model 3 and the company's capital requirements).\" Goldman Sachs (Sell): \"Altogether, we believe the update had more negative undertones than positive implications and believe shares should see pressure as a result. Ultimately, the path for shares over the next two months likely tracks available VIN registration data – which has helped point to weekly production cadence of the Model 3.\" Barclays (Sell): \"We expected the shareholder letter to be more about the future than about the quarter in the books that was plagued by a slow ramp of the M3. And in that we were right – the letter is replete with optimistic predictions of achieving positive profits in 2H, based on the assumption that it can get to a 5000/wk run rate (which we note is likely a steady 5k/week, not a burst rate). But at the same time, while still a large loss and cash burn, the quarter was less bad than we thought – with a modest amount of opex discipline, lower than expected capex (and a lower capex guide for the year) – which contributed to somewhat better cash burn (a mere $1.1bn instead of our more dire $1.9bn) and EPS.\" Guggenheim (Buy): \"As Tesla keeps grinding through its ramp of the Model 3, it continues to target production hitting 5K units/week entering Q3E, which we continue to forecast dramatically flipping the company's economics from sizeable cash-burn in 1H18E to profitability in 2H18E, with Model 3 volumes then driving meaningful positive leverage in 2019-20E off the big fixed-cost structure it has been building.\" Piper Jaffray (Buy): \"Management strongly rejected the need for new equity, while trimming its capex forecast and guiding for profitability in 2H. Model 3 choppiness notwithstanding, these results initially looked like a modest positive vs. bearish expectations. But then Elon Musk began dismissing analysts' questions and decided instead to field TWELVE questions from a YouTuber because it was 'way more interesting.' The unorthodox behavior sparked an after-hours sell-off. We still recommend TSLA, but in the next few months especially, we would expect significant volatility.\" Baird (Buy): \"Ignore the noise and focus on metrics. TSLA reported solid results and is successfully ramping Model 3 vehicle and battery production, although Elon refused to answer several questions on the conference call which he deemed mundane, which may create pressure on the stock. That said, we believe investors should continue to focus on TSLA's progress and recommend buying shares.\" Nomura (Buy): \"We are disappointed by the way last night's earnings call went. No shareholder wants to see a CEO lose his patience over important, albeit mundane questions about margins, capex and customer deposits. It will most likely divert attention today away from several positive fundamentals from the Q1 report and outlook.\" RBC Capital Markets (Hold): \"An odd conference call that lacked answers to questions on investors' minds and overshadowed earnings. Investor feedback is that the performance shook confidence, which we'd argue is an important piece of the Tesla story. The results themselves probably did little to incrementally persuade bulls/bears either way. There is still healthy, and warranted, skepticism about Tesla's near-term production capabilities.\" Evercore ISI (Hold): \"'Wow' is the only way to describe the Tesla Q1 call which was unlike anything we have heard before. The call yielded little of incremental value to investors in our view. However, it did witness CEO Musk somewhat curtly dismiss questions from two well respected peers in favour of a plethora of questions from a retail investor. Were the retail investor's questions basic or boring? No. However, they did not address the more granular aspects of Tesla's Q1 performance and Q2 expectations which the analyst community was attempting to address. Questions which we believe need to be answered in order for the broader investment community to become more constructive on a name that continues to burn cash and whose funding needs remain subject to debate.\" Oppenheimer (Hold): \"We expect many investors to focus on questions around strategic leadership as CEO Elon Musk hung up on analysts asking questions related to battery production runrate and what he deemed boring questions about financial and operational metrics. The company also effectively pushed out its year-end target for 10k/week runrate suggesting it would wait until 3Q18 before deciding how best to configure manufacturing to reach that runrate. Musk also indicated TSLA is in planning stages for a new factory to produce Model Y, it was planning to announce a Chinese factory, and Semi truck availability would be 2020 at the earliest.\" KeyBanc (Hold): \"While we remain Sector Weight on longer-term valuation sensitivity (and in spite of an unfavorable conference call), shares still look a bit oversold given a low Model 3 profitability bar to step over, a solid and likely improving demand narrative, almost certain headline upside risks as the Company works toward 5K/week, and likely incremental production announcements in the upcoming one to two quarters.\" WATCH: Elon Musk's big ambitions may be killing Tesla show chapters Tesla's earnings were better than expected, but Elon Musk still has a lot on his plate 8:48 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 05:31 ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/07/31/104621545-GettyImages-818980572.jpg?v=1528827368", "keywords": [{"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Jim Cramer"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "10:02 AM ET Thu"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "3"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "02:52 Shares"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Musk"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Toni Sacconaghi"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bernstein"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Musk"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the previous quarter"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bank of America Merrill Lynch"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Underperform"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "3.41bn"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "3.29bn"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Reported"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "13.4%"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "17.4%"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Automotive"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Auto"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "19.7%"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "YoY"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "3"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SG&A"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "1.05bn"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "1.02bn"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "YoY"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Bernstein (Hold):"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Q1"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "20-minute"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "YouTube"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Q1"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Morgan Stanley (Hold"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "Tonight"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "J.P. Morgan"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1Q"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "yesterday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EPS"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1Q"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "TSLA"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "today"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "the Model 3"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Goldman Sachs"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the next two months"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "the Model 3"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Barclays (Sell):"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "M3"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2H"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "5k/week"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the quarter"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the year"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "a mere $1.1bn"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "more dire $"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "1.9bn"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EPS"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Guggenheim"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "the Model 3"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "5"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "K"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Q3E"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2H18E"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2019"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Piper Jaffray"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2H."}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "TWELVE"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "YouTuber"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the next few months"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Baird (Buy):"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "TSLA"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Nomura (Buy)"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "last night's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "today"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "Q1"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "RBC Capital Markets"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Evercore ISI (Hold"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Musk"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "two"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Q1"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Oppenheimer (Hold):"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "year-end"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "10k/week"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "3Q18"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Musk"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "TSLA"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model Y"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Chinese"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Semi"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2020"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "KeyBanc (Hold)"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Sector Weight"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "5K/week"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "one to two quarters"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Tesla"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Elon Musk"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "8:48 PM"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}], "description": "Here's a wrap of all the major analyst opinions going out to Wall Street pros regarding Tesla.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/what-wall-street-thinks-of-teslas-quarterly-results-earnings-call.html", "author": "Brendan Smialowski | AFP | Getty Images", "title": "Here's what every major Wall Street analyst had to say about Tesla's results, Musk's peculiar call"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T17:51:25-0400", "body": " Lucas Jackson | Reuters The Spotify logo on the New York Stock Exchange, April 3, 2018. Check out the companies making headlines after the bell: Spotify shares plunged as much as 10 percent in the extended session. The entertainment company reported revenues and monthly active users that fell in line with estimates, but its guidance for the upcoming quarter was weak and it is still losing money. This quarter's earnings are the first the newly public company has reported. Square stock sank more than 6 percent post-market. The financial services and mobile payment company's earnings fell in line with what was expected and its revenues were better than expected. Its gross payment volume also fell in line with expectations. Weak earnings guidance disappointed investors. Tesla shares rose as much as 2 percent in extended trading after posting better than expected earnings, but the company's stock later gave up its gains. The electric vehicle maker and energy storage company's loss per share was smaller than expected and its revenue surpassed estimates. Its cash burn was also smaller than analysts expected. It also expects to be profitable and cash-flow positive in the second half of the year. The company previously stated that it wants to ramp up Model 3 production to 6,000 per week by the end of June. So far it is up to producing 2,020 by the end of the first quarter, still short of its growth goal. Shares of AIG fell nearly 6 percent after the bell. The finance and insurance corporation reported a substantial miss on earnings per share. Sprint stock gained nearly 2 percent in the extended session. The mobile carrier beat estimates on revenues and earnings but its net adds were lower than expected. It also announced that current CFO Michel Combes will become the company's CEO and current CEO Marcelo Claure will become Sprint's executive chairman. Claure will also fill the roles of COO at Softbank Group and CEO at Softbank Group International. The personnel changes come as Sprint plans to merge with T-Mobile. If the deal is approved, current T-Mobile CEO John Legere will remain CEO of the newly merged carrier. Express Scripts stock dropped more than 1 percent in the extended session before recovering its losses. The prescription management company beat estimates on earnings but missed on revenues. Its full-year earnings guidance was also lowered. Fitbit shares sank more than 4 percent post-market. The wearable technology maker reported a beat on revenues and a smaller loss than expected, but guidance for the upcoming quarter was weak on top and bottom lines. Shares of Zynga rose more than 2 percent in post-market trading after the company announced a new share structure. The gaming company said on Wednesday that it would move to a single class structure, reducing the voting power of chairman and co-founder Mark Pincus. It also reported a higher mobile audience and revenue of $208.2 billion. Kraft Heinz stock rose more than 3 percent in extended trading after reporting mixed earnings. The grocery manufacturer just missed revenue estimates but beat on earnings per share. The beat comes despite lower first-quarter sales. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/04/03/105105865-RTX5FL0V.jpg?v=1522767317", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "Lucas Jackson"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Reuters"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Spotify"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the New York Stock Exchange"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "April 3, 2018"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Spotify"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "as much as 10 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "monthly"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the upcoming quarter"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "quarter"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 6 percent"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "as much as 2 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the second half of the year"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "Model 3"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "6,000"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the end of June"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2,020"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the end of the first quarter"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AIG"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "nearly 6 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sprint"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "nearly 2 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CFO Michel Combes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Marcelo Claure"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sprint"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "COO at Softbank Group"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Softbank Group International"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sprint"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Mobile"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "John Legere"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Express Scripts"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 1 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "full-year"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 4 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the upcoming quarter"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Zynga"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 2 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Mark Pincus"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "$208.2 billion"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Kraft Heinz"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 3 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "first-quarter"}], "description": "See which stocks are posting big moves after the bell.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/after-hours-buzz-spot-sq-tsla-more.html", "author": "Lucas Jackson | Reuters", "title": "After-hours buzz: SPOT, SQ, TSLA & more"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T18:30:17-0400", "body": " Michael Newberg | CNBC Andrew Left, Citron Research Investors are putting too much attention on Square's bitcoin ambitions, Citron Research's Andrew Left told CNBC's \"Fast Money\" on Wednesday. The well-known short-seller was on to talk about Square, cryptocurrencies and Alibaba, the Chinese e-commerce giant. Earlier this week, Left tweeted that \"WallSt. drunk on Bitcoin nonsense.\" He put a short-term $30 price target on shares of Square, the card payments processor co-founded by Jack Dorsey. The stock was down 6 percent in aftermarket trading on Wednesday, after the company said second quarter earnings per share could be lower than what analysts are expecting. Square began offering bitcoin trading in the first quarter but said it only netted revenue of $200,000 from the activity. Bitcoin, Left said on Wednesday, \"keeps the focus away\" from Square's core business. Payments processing \"has a long-term trajectory of contracting\" margins and faces stiff competition. He has been more positive about Alibaba, which he calls a compelling growth story. \"It's the anti-Square,\" he told Fast Money. \"It's the tollbooth to the Chinese middle class.\" Shares of Alibaba were up 0.6 percent in afterhours trading. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/03/03/103441413-20160302-2-2104-3.jpg?v=1534171851", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "Michael Newberg"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Andrew Left"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Citron Research Investors"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Square"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Citron Research's"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Andrew Left"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Fast Money"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Alibaba"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Chinese"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Earlier this week"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "WallSt"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bitcoin"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "30"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Square"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Jack Dorsey"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "6 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "second quarter"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the first quarter"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "200,000"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bitcoin"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Left"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Square"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Alibaba"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Chinese"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Alibaba"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "0.6 percent"}], "description": "Investors are putting too much attention on Square's bitcoin ambitions, Citron Research's Andrew Left told CNBC's \"Fast Money\" ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/citrons-andrew-left-calls-squares-bitcoin-foray-a-distraction-for-investors.html", "author": "Michael Newberg | CNBC ", "title": "Citron's Andrew Left calls Square's bitcoin foray a distraction for investors"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T19:48:33-0400", "body": " show chapters Cramer: Snap's conference call was like SNL parody 10:12 AM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 03:18 Shares of social media company Snap plummeted by as much as 20 percent Wednesday following disappointing earnings, and Wall Street still sees room on the downside. The company significantly missed revenue estimates in its latest report and said its next quarter year-over-year revenue growth rate will \"decelerate substantially,\" partially due to ad prices. The company also missed analysts target for daily active users and revenue per user. As a result, multiple firms published bearish notes and knocked down their price targets for Snap's stock. Morgan Stanley dropped its price target to $8, about $6 below where the stock closed Tuesday, and remains underweight. Snap was trading at $11.45 on Wednesday morning, down nearly 19 percent on the day. \"1Q:18 miss and forward ad commentary speak to continued challenges SNAP faces in turning its business model around,\" Morgan Stanley analyst Brian Nowak said in a note to clients Wednesday. Michael Nagle | Bloomberg | Getty Images Pedestrians pass in front of Snap Inc. signage displayed on the exterior of the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) during the company's initial public offering (IPO) in New York, U.S., on Thursday, March 2, 2017. Nowak cited user churn, the bungled app redesign, poor performance on Androids and advertiser concerns as headwinds expected to continue into the second quarter. Analysts at Piper Jaffray were \"skeptical\" after the results, projecting an $11.50 price target. It cited leadership and said competition from Instagram could add to the pain. \"Snap is a poorly structured company that is demonstrating a clear pattern of mismanagement,\" Piper Jaffray analyst Sam Kemp said in a note to clients. \"We think the negative news cycle around Snap will continue and advertisers will likely continue to approach Snap skeptically.\" Analysts at Deutsche Bank were also bearish, keeping a $12 price target with a hold rating. \"Snapchat risks losing its 'cool' status with users frustrated by the redesign, which makes advertisers increasingly unlikely to put money into Snap advertising without clear ROI returns,\" Deutsche Bank's Lloyd Walmsley said in a note to clients Wednesday. \"We think Snap is a 'show me' stories to advertisers (and investors), and has to move fast to change the narrative, particularly given its cash burn levels,\" Walmsley said. Credit Suisse dropped its price target from $21 to $16, still above where the stock was trading Wednesday. While its analysts called the quarter \"conviction-testing,\" they maintained their outperform rating. \"As shares have already retraced back almost all of the gains, we elect to maintain our Outperform rating for now given the upside potential but acknowledge that further patience may be required,\" Deutsche Bank's Stephen Ju said. WATCH: Snap earnings and advertiser impact show chapters SNAP earnings broke camel's back for some advertisers: Analyst 3:34 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 05:12 ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2015/05/07/102658914-456877564-01.jpg?v=1497550407", "keywords": [{"category": "GPE", "term": "Cramer"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SNL"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "10:12 AM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "03:18 Shares"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "as much as 20 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "next quarter year-over-year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "daily"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Morgan Stanley"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "8"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "about $6"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "11.45"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "morning"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "nearly 19 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the day"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "1Q:18"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "SNAP"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Morgan Stanley"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Brian Nowak"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Michael Nagle"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bloomberg"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Getty Images Pedestrians"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Snap Inc."}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the New York Stock Exchange"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NYSE"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "New York"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Thursday, March 2, 2017"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Nowak"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Androids"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the second quarter"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Piper Jaffray"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "11.50"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Instagram"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Piper Jaffray"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sam Kemp"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Deutsche Bank"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "12"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "ROI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Deutsche Bank's"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Lloyd Walmsley"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Walmsley"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "21"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "16"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the quarter"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Outperform"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Deutsche Bank's"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Stephen Ju"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "SNAP"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "3:34 PM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}], "description": "Wall Street sees more room for Snap to fall after its disappointing earnings results. ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/after-snap-stock-crash-wall-street-analysts-see-more-pain-ahead.html", "author": "Getty Images", "title": "After Snap stock crash, Wall Street analysts see more pain"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T09:25:05-0400", "body": " Lisa Maree Williams | Getty Images Richard Branson The billionaire entrepreneur Richard Branson is to take his first foray into the world of private equity. The Virgin Group founder is to partner with London-based Metric Capital in managing a new fund which will seek stakes in firms with consumer-facing businesses, such as food and beverage, luxury, and leisure. First reported in the Financial Times, and confirmed to CNBC by a source close to the matter, the partnership will seek to raise 500 million euros ($600 million) from institutional investors and will focus its bets on Europe and the United States. Metric Capital declined to comment when contacted by CNBC. Branson has reportedly known the founder of Metric Capital, John Sinick, for more than twenty years. \"I have been impressed by the development and growth of Metric Capital,\" Branson said in a statement provided to CNBC by the Virgin Group. \"Their experience in the rapidly changing consumer and digital markets is particularly attractive and I look forward to helping John and his team with this new fund.\" The fund, believed to be the first of three to be launched in the coming years, will target returns of 20 percent. The Financial Times also reported that the fund is to donate 10 percent of profits to women's and children's charities. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/12/11/104890981-lead01_1.png?v=1512992808", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "Lisa"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Maree Williams"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Getty Images"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Richard Branson"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Richard Branson"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Virgin Group"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "London"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Metric Capital"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "First"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Financial Times"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "500 million"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "$600 million"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "Europe"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "the United States"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Metric Capital"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Branson"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Metric Capital"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "John Sinick"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "more than twenty years"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Metric Capital"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Branson"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Virgin Group"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "John"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "three"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the coming years"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "20 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Financial Times"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "10 percent"}], "description": "The billionaire’s fund will focus on U.S. and European firms.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/richard-branson-takes-first-step-into-private-equity-with-600-million-fund.html", "author": "", "title": "Richard Branson takes first step into private equity with $600 million fund"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T12:01:41-0400", "body": " show chapters Scott Minerd discusses market health 7:20 AM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 03:45 Investors should expect a surge in stocks over the next 12 to 18 months before they fall off a cliff amid a recession in 2020, according to Scott Minerd of Guggenheim Partners. \"I think stocks will go up another 15 to 20 percent, but ultimately, when the recession arrives — and it will arrive — there's going to be a very hard sell-off in equities,\" the firm's global chief investment officer told CNBC's Brian Sullivan at the 2018 Milken Global Investment Conference on Tuesday. The interviewed aired on CNBC's \"Worldwide Exchange.\" He said stocks will look more attractive to investors in the near term as valuations come down due to higher risk premiums. Adam Jeffery | CNBC Scott Minerd \"Right now, in the penultimate year before a recession, because we think a recession is coming in 2020, that typically is a very good year for equities,\" Minerd said. But \"the longer the expansion has been, the more likely the sell-off will be hard.\" The U.S. economy is on its second-longest expansion on record, growing for 106-straight months. However, U.S. stocks have been under pressure in 2018. Year to date, the S&P 500 is down nearly 1 percent after reaching an all-time high on Jan. 26. Minerd also reiterated his call for a 40 to 45 percent drop in stocks starting in late 2019 and into 2020 as the U.S. economy enters a recession. He previously made his prediction last month during another interview with CNBC. \"Recessions occur when the economy reaches constraints. As the economy reaches constraints, prices begin to rise and the Federal Reserve has to raise interest rates and, as I like to say: Every economic expansion does not die of old age; it dies because the Federal Reserve shoots it in the head,\" Minerd said Tuesday. —CNBC's Matthew J. Belvedere contributed to this report. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2016/03/16/103475398-20160316-8161-2127.jpg?v=1479923358", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "Scott Minerd"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "7:20 AM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "03:45 Investors"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the next 12 to 18 months before they fall"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2020"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Scott Minerd"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Guggenheim Partners"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Brian Sullivan"}, {"category": "EVENT", "term": "Milken Global Investment Conference"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Worldwide Exchange"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Adam Jeffery"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Scott Minerd"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the penultimate year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2020"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "a very good year"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Minerd"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "second"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "106-straight months"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2018"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Year to date"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "nearly 1 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Jan. 26"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Minerd"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "40 to 45 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "late 2019"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2020"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last month"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Federal Reserve"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Federal Reserve"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Minerd"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Matthew J."}], "description": "Investors should expect a surge in stocks over the next 12-to-18 month before they fall off a cliff amid a recession in 2020, according to Guggenheim's Scott Minerd.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/guggenheim-investment-chief-sees-stocks-rising-20-percent-more-before-a-recession-fueled-sell-off.html", "author": "Adam Jeffery | CNBC ", "title": "Guggenheim investment chief sees stocks rising 20% more before a recession-fueled sell-off"}, {"time": "2018-05-01T18:56:46-0400", "body": " Kai Pfaffenbach | Reuters Chipmaker stocks jumped late Tuesday after Apple reported steady iPhone sales, easing fears of a significant decline. Skyworks Solutions climbed 3 percent in after-hours trading, following gains of 4.77 percent during Tuesday's session. The VanEck Vectors Semiconductor ETF (SMH) climbed 0.8 percent. Micron Technology shares rose more than 1 percent, shares of Cirrus Logic gained nearly 3 percent, and Broadcom climbed 2 percent. Apple said it sold 52.2 million iPhones in the quarter ended March, up from 51 million a year ago. The figure for the latest quarter did miss expectations of 53 million, according to FactSet consensus estimates. However, some analysts have feared worse. Last week, Bernstein analyst Toni Sacconaghi cut his fiscal-year earnings-per-share estimate for Apple based on his team's analysis of supply chain companies that \"increasingly point[ed] to weakness.\" WATCH: iPhone sales & Apple's cash burn show chapters Unclear iPhone X will be a real product for Apple, says analyst 5:14 PM ET Tue, 1 May 2018 | 04:31 ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2015/07/14/102833417-RTX1K9S0.jpg?v=1537529147", "keywords": [{"category": "NORP", "term": " "}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Kai Pfaffenbach"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Reuters Chipmaker"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "late Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Apple"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "iPhone"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Skyworks Solutions"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "3 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "after-hours"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "4.77 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "0.8 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Micron Technology"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 1 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Cirrus Logic"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "nearly 3 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Broadcom"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "2 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Apple"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "52.2 million"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "iPhones"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the quarter ended March"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "51 million"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "a year ago"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the latest quarter"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "53 million"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "FactSet"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Last week"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bernstein"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Toni Sacconaghi"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "fiscal-year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Apple"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "iPhone sales & Apple's"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "iPhone X"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Apple"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "5:14 PM ET Tue"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}], "description": "Chipmaker stocks jumped late Tuesday after Apple reported steady iPhone sales, easing fears of a significant decline. ", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/01/semiconductor-stocks-climb-after-apple-eases-fears-of-iphone-slump.html", "author": "Kai Pfaffenbach | Reuters", "title": "Chip stocks climb after Apple eases fears of iPhone slump"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T16:17:06-0400", "body": " Daniel Berman | Bloomberg | Getty Images Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella. Technology stocks, rather than industrial heavyweights, drove much of the surge in capital investment in the first quarter, preliminary data show. Capital expenditures are on track to post 25.9 percent growth for the first quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S, as of Tuesday morning. Much of that comes from 59.8 percent projected growth in investments from information technology companies. \"Internet and Software are pushing Tech capex to 5-year highs,\" Credit Suisse's Jonathan Golub and his team said in a Monday report that looked at the 55 percent of S&P 500 quarterly reports. They said Google parent Alphabet and Microsoft accounted for much of the increase, along with spending related to cloud computing and semiconductors. #dw-chart{width: 100%;height: 500px;border: none;padding-top: 32px;box-sizing: border-box;-moz-box-sizing: border-box;-webkit-box-sizing: border-box;}jQuery(document).ready(function($){var iframe=document.getElementById(\"dw-chart\");$(window).on(\"orientationchange\",function(){iframe.src=iframe.src;});}); President Donald Trump and Republicans slashed the corporate tax rate to 21 percent from 35 percent late last year. But so far, the extra capital appears to have gone more into dividends and share buybacks than capital investments that typically spur economic growth. Few companies have discussed increases in capital expenditures due to tax reform, according to CNBC analysis of the latest earnings calls using financial search engine AlphaSense. In addition, the industries whose spending is most directly tied to that growth are not investing. Industrials are tracking for a 3.3 percent drop in capital investment for the first quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S. Excluding tech, growth in S&P 500 capital expenditures would slow to 19.5 percent from 25.9 percent for the quarter. Consumer discretionary is second to tech in capex growth, and much of that is coming from e-commerce giant Amazon.com, cruise operator Royal Caribbean and General Motors, according to Credit Suisse. The report pointed out that Royal Caribbean's $1.7 billion pickup \"results from several new ships.\" Technology also accounts for the most capital expenditure growth among smaller companies. S&P 400 tech companies posted 48 percent growth in first-quarter capex as of Tuesday, according to S&P Global Market Intelligence. \"We're not hearing a lot of evidence yet of increased CapEx tied to tax reform,\" John J. Engel, CEO of electrical equipment distribution company Wesco International, said during an earnings call last week. However, \"we actually think that's still a future upside as we move through 2018 and into 2019,\" Engel said, according to a Thomson Reuters transcript from AlphaSense. \"We've heard the beginnings of that with respect to some of the tech companies, citing that as a reason for stepping up their project activity or capital.\" Analysts are less optimistic for the near term. Tech capital expenditures are projected to slow for the rest of the year to just 11.6 percent growth in the fourth quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S. Growth in overall S&P 500 capital investments is also expected to drop off, and ultimately post a 2.5 percent decline in the fourth quarter. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/10/27/104802148-GettyImages-860270486-nadella-microsoft.jpg?v=1533941312", "keywords": [{"category": "ORG", "term": " Daniel Berman"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bloomberg"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Getty Images Microsoft"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Satya Nadella"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the first quarter"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "25.9 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the first quarter"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Thomson Reuters"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "morning"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "59.8 percent"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Software"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Tech"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "5-year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse's"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Jonathan Golub"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Monday"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "the 55 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "quarterly"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Google"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Alphabet"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Microsoft"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "500px;border"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Donald Trump"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Republicans"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "21 percent"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "35 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "late last year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AlphaSense"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "3.3 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the first quarter"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Thomson Reuters"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "19.5 percent"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "25.9 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the quarter"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "second"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Amazon.com"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Royal Caribbean"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "General Motors"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Royal Caribbean's"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "$1.7 billion"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "48 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "first-quarter"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "S&P Global Market Intelligence"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "John J. Engel"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Wesco International"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last week"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2018"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2019"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Engel"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Thomson Reuters"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AlphaSense"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the year"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "just 11.6 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the fourth quarter"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Thomson Reuters"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "2.5 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the fourth quarter"}], "description": "Technology stocks, rather than industrial heavyweights, are driving much of the surge in capital investment in the first quarter, preliminary data show.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/technology-companies-are-driving-a-capital-spending-surge.html", "author": "Daniel Berman | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "title": "Technology companies are driving a capital spending surge"}, {"time": "2018-05-02T14:25:40-0400", "body": " show chapters Fed leaves rates unchanged 2:20 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 00:43 This is a comparison of Wednesday's FOMC statement with the one issued after the Fed's previous policymaking meeting on March 21. Text removed from the March statement is in red with a horizontal line through the middle. Text appearing for the first time in the new statement is in red and underlined. Black text appears in both statements. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/06/14/104529664-GettyImages-695997668.jpg?v=1497464992", "keywords": [{"category": "ORG", "term": "Fed"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "2:20 PM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "00:43"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "one"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Fed"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March 21"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}], "description": "This is a comparison of Wednesday's FOMC statement with the one issued after the Fed's previous policymaking meeting on March 21.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/02/may-fed-meeting-heres-what-changed-in-the-new-fed-statement.html", "author": "Andrew Harrer | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "title": "Here's what changed in the new Fed statement"}, {"time": "2018-05-01T17:36:03-0400", "body": " show chapters Facebook co-founder Chris Hughes: Facebook hasn't done enough to protect user data 4:46 PM ET Tue, 1 May 2018 | 05:01 Facebook co-founder Chris Hughes told CNBC on Tuesday he doesn't think the social media giant has done enough to protect its users' personal data. The issue over privacy came to the forefront after the research firm Cambridge Analytica was recently accused of improperly accessing the personal user data of as many as 87 million Facebook users. Hughes said it is now a question of what Facebook and others will do next, and whether that should include government intervention. \"It's not just enough to trust the corporations. I think that there's a role for public policy as well,\" he told Brian Sullivan on \"Closing Bell\" from the Milken Institute Global Conference. He believes public pressure should be kept up on companies to make sure data are secure. At the same time, there should be something like a data privacy bill of rights or some type of \"consumer data protection bureau that makes sure that there's the rule of law when it comes to these questions,\" he said. Hughes, a Harvard dormmate of Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg, was the early spokesperson for the social network. He also worked on the products team. Hughes left Silicon Valley to help organize the online efforts for Barack Obama's 2008 presidential campaign. \"There is a sense all of these companies have gotten very big very fast. Perhaps too big,\" said Hughes, now co-chair of The Economic Security Project. During his congressional testimony in April, Zuckerberg acknowledged it is \"inevitable\" there will need to be some regulation of social media. \"I also think you have to be careful about what regulation you put in place,\" the CEO said. Hughes said while companies can and should innovate, they should also make sure that data is protected and that \"people can share in the upside,\" he said. \"A small group of companies is creating historic level of profits\" from that consumer data, he said. He thinks they can put about 5 percent into a sovereign wealth fund and then cut a dividend check. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/02/20/105017401-IMG_1852r.JPG?v=1525209381", "keywords": [{"category": "ORG", "term": "Facebook"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Chris Hughes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Facebook"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "4:46 PM ET Tue"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "1"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Chris Hughes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Tuesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Cambridge Analytica"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "as many as 87 million"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Facebook"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Hughes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Facebook"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Brian Sullivan"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "\"Closing Bell\""}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Milken Institute Global Conference"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Hughes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Harvard"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Facebook"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Mark Zuckerberg"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Hughes"}, {"category": "LOC", "term": "Silicon Valley"}, {"category": "FAC", "term": "Barack Obama's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2008"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Hughes"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Economic Security Project"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "April"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Zuckerberg"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Hughes"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "about 5 percent"}], "description": "“It’s not just enough to trust the corporations. I think that there’s a role for public policy as well,” says Chris Hughes.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/01/facebook-hasnt-done-enough-to-protect-user-data-co-founder-hughes.html", "author": "", "title": "Facebook hasn’t done enough to protect user data, says co-founder Chris Hughes"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T10:45:23-0400", "body": " show chapters A ‘really strange’ trend is hitting the markets this earnings season, Credit Suisse’s Jonathan Golub says 5:36 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 01:42 Market bull Jonathan Golub said stocks will make another record run this year just as the Dow sank back into correction territory. The Credit Suisse chief U.S. equity strategist believes Wall Street is making a mistake by not embracing an unprecedented first-quarter earnings season. \"It's really strange. We're seeing the best earnings season maybe ever. Twenty-five percent year-over-year growth in the ninth year of a recovery, and companies are beating by 8 percent,\" Golub said Wednesday on CNBC's \"Trading Nation.\" \"But the market's response to this is far more muted than normal.\" His thoughts came shortly after the Federal Reserve made its latest decision on interest rates, leaving them unchanged, but noted it detected inflation. \"I'm generally a believer that we overemphasize the importance of the Fed as opposed to the economic backdrop and the earnings backdrop,\" said Golub. The market didn't welcome the Fed's assessment. Stocks finished the Wednesday in the red. The Dow has now dropped more than 10 percent below its Jan. 26 intraday all-time high of 26,616.71. The S&P 500 is now 8 percent below its intraday record high of 2,872.87 from that same date. Despite the leg down, Golub expects a comeback. He predicts the S&P 500 will rally about 13 percent to 3,000 by year-end. \"This ultimately powers through. Take a look at stocks. They started the year with a forward P/E [price to earnings ratio] of 18x. Today it is a forward P/E of 16x,\" Golub said. \"Stocks, if they don't rally, are going to get cheaper and cheaper.\" Vote Vote to see results Total Votes: Not a Scientific Survey. Results may not total 100% due to rounding. show chapters Credit Suisse’s Golub on the market’s lukewarm reaction to remarkable earnings 5:12 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 06:29 Disclaimer ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2013/09/30/101072577-177648353.jpg?v=1538077974", "keywords": [{"category": "DATE", "term": "this earnings season"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse’s"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Jonathan Golub"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "5:36 PM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "01:42 Market"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Jonathan Golub"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "this year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Dow"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "first-quarter"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "season"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "Twenty-five percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "year-over-year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the ninth year"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "8 percent"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Golub"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Trading Nation"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Federal Reserve"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Fed"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Golub"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Fed"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Dow"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "more than 10 percent"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Jan. 26"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "26,616.71"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "8 percent"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2,872.87"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Golub"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "about 13 percent"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "3,000"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "year-end"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the year"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "18x"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Today"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "16x"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Golub"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Vote Vote"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "a Scientific Survey"}, {"category": "PERCENT", "term": "100%"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Credit Suisse’s"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Golub"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "5:12 PM"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Disclaimer"}], "description": "Market bull Jonathan Golub questions why jitters are hitting Wall Street so hard when earnings are so strong.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/stocks-to-power-through-slump-credit-suisses-jonathan-golub-says.html", "author": "Tim Boyle | Bloomberg | Getty Images", "title": "Stocks will 'power through' slump, new records are coming, Credit Suisse's Jonathan Golub predicts"}, {"time": "2018-05-01T16:31:35-0400", "body": " Reuters Then-National Rifle Association First Vice-President Sandra Froman waves to the crowd after making remarks during opening ceremonies of the NRA's national meeting April 15, 2005 in Houston. Next week, activist shareholders will make their first attempt at shaking up the gun industry using their votes instead of just their voices. One big campaign is against an NRA-connected director on the board of Sturm Ruger & Co., one of the nation's largest gun makers. Groups are threatening to withhold their votes for Sandra Froman's renomination as director to the board, where she has been a member since 2015. Froman has been a director of the National Rifle Association for 26 years and was its president from 2005 to 2007. Amalgamated Bank, which describes itself as promoting socially responsible causes, wants Sturm Ruger to agree to a list of demands involving gun safety and sales practices by this Friday or it says it will withhold its vote for Froman. The company, it says, is too closely tied to the NRA. show chapters Who makes the AR-15 rifle? 7:01 PM ET Thu, 15 Feb 2018 | 02:19 The relationship between Sturm and the NRA \"may inhibit the ability of your company's Board to accurately evaluate the risks the company faces,\" Amalgamated's CEO, Keith Mestrich, wrote in a letter to the company last month. \"The NRA plays a key role in shaping the gun industry's response to calls for gun control measures, opposing even incremental changes and common sense reforms supported by a majority of gun owners.\" Sturm Ruger's meeting comes just days after the NRA holds its annual meeting this weekend in Dallas, where Vice President Mike Pence is among the scheduled speakers. A Sturm Ruger spokesman didn't return a call for comment. And a request to Froman for comment, made by way of an NRA spokesman, also wasn't returned. Another community group, Majority Action, is organizing retail investors to push big fund companies like BlackRock and Vanguard, Sturm Ruger's biggest shareholders, to assert their voting power. The group organized about six weeks ago, seeing now as a crucial moment for changing the gun industry. \"We were looking at how you enable everyday investors to access the levers of power when it comes to holding companies accountable,\" said James Rucker, its co-founder, who is on the board of directors of the Southern Poverty Law Center. But even before these recent demands, controversy was certain to erupt at Sturm Ruger's meeting, scheduled to take place May 9 at a resort in Arizona thousands of miles from its Connecticut headquarters. The company has a factory in the area. Wednesday's vote will be the first test this year of a proposal by a faith-based shareholder group urging the nation's gun industry to act after recent extreme examples of gun violence. Specifically, that proposal, backed by the Northwest Coalition for Responsible Investment, asks gun makers like Sturm Ruger to prepare a report about the financial and reputational risks associated with their business. The coalition plans to introduce a similar proposal on the proxy of American Outdoor Brands, which typically holds its meetings in the fall. Two major shareholder voting advisory firms, Institutional Shareholder Services and Glass Lewis, have thrown their support behind the coalition's proposal, Sturm Ruger's board, on the other hand, is advising shareholders to vote against it. \"We believe that firearms safety is a laudable and appropriate goal,\" it said in the proxy. \"However, we also believe that adequate safety practices and procedures are available.\" BlackRock said in a note to clients in March that it is time to take action on gun violence, adding it could use its position as a large shareholder to vote against boards and management and back shareholder proposals management doesn't like. But it won't comment about how it plans to vote its 2.8 million shares next week. Several companies connected to the gun industry have changed their policies in recent weeks in response to the upswell of protests after a shooting in a Florida high school in February left 17 people dead. Major retailers such as Walmart and Dick's Sporting Goods put limits on gun sales, and banks like Citigroup said it would restrict gun sales by business partners. Fund managers like BlackRock and State Street said they would start a dialogue with gun makers about what they are doing to promote safety. BlackRock has even rolled out new funds that specifically remove stocks of gun makers and sellers. Amalgamated wants the gun maker to publicly endorse universal background checks, funding for government to to crack down on illegal distribution, and funding for government research into gun safety and public health. They also want a commitment to responsible distribution contracts, monitoring of distribution chains and investments in gun safety technology and commercialization. Froman, 68, is a lawyer and long-time gun industry supporter. The Southern Poverty Law Center found her name in a 2014 member directory of a secretive ultra-conservative group called the Council for National Policy. Tax forms from 2015 and 2016 filed by that organization list her as treasurer. The year she became president of the NRA, the gun lobby won a crucial legal battle in the form of a new law limiting liability claims against gun makers. That same year, a donor program for the NRA launched and, as reported by Bloomberg in 2012, took in nearly $15 million from gun-related companies. Froman has pointed to Smith & Wesson's decision in 2000 to voluntarily comply with certain gun safety measures as its downfall. Grassroots gun supporters forced the company into bankruptcy after it made that \"deal with the devil,\" she has said. \"The grass roots is a powerful force that the government can't control and can't fight,\" she said in a speech in 2011 to a group that supports knife ownership. \"Just look at what's happened with the rise of the Tea Party movement. Most of the battles that NRA has won have been won by sheer political power.\" The NRA is said to be the subject of fresh scrutiny about its ties to a Russian government official recently sanctioned by the U.S. That official, Alexander Torshin, is a lifetime NRA member, CNN reported Friday. One of Torshin's former aides, Maria Butina, the founder of the Russian group \"Right to Bear Arms,\" was hosted by Froman as part of the annual NRA Women's Leadership luncheon in 2014. Butina posted a photo of the two on her blog back then, calling Froman a \"legendary woman.\" Everytown for Gun Safety, a gun safety group that began as an organization founded by former New York major Michael Bloomberg, also details the NRA's connections to Russians, including Torshin and Butina, on its website. The proxy advisory services have advised shareholders to vote in favor of all the of the directors nominated to Sturm Ruger's board, including Froman. ISS did note that Sturm Ruger has a contract with the NRA for some of its promotional and advertising activities and paid the group $800,000 last year. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2018/04/30/105172715-RTXNEHK.jpg?v=1525122009", "keywords": [{"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sandra Froman"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "April 15, 2005"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Houston"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Next week"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "One"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sturm Ruger & Co."}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "one"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Groups"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sandra Froman's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2015"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the National Rifle Association"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "26 years"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2005"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2007"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Amalgamated Bank"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Friday"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "7:01 PM ET Thu"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "15"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Feb 2018"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Sturm"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Board"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Keith Mestrich"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last month"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "just days"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "annual"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "this weekend"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Dallas"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Mike Pence"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sturm Ruger"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Majority Action"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BlackRock"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Vanguard, Sturm Ruger's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "about six weeks ago"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "James Rucker"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Southern Poverty Law Center"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 9"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Arizona"}, {"category": "QUANTITY", "term": "thousands of miles"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Connecticut"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Wednesday"}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "this year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Northwest Coalition for Responsible Investment"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "American Outdoor Brands"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "the fall"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "Two"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Institutional Shareholder Services"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Glass Lewis"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger's"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BlackRock"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "March"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2.8 million"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "next week"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "recent weeks"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Florida"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "February"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "17"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Walmart"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Dick"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Sporting Goods"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Citigroup"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BlackRock"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "State Street"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BlackRock"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "68"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "The Southern Poverty Law Center"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2014"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Council for National Policy"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2015"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2016"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "That same year"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bloomberg"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2012"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "nearly $15 million"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Smith & Wesson's"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2000"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2011"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the Tea Party"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Russian"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "U.S."}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Alexander Torshin"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNN"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "Friday"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "One"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Torshin"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Maria Butina"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Russian"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Bear Arms"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "annual"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA Women's Leadership"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "2014"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Butina"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "two"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Everytown for Gun Safety"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "New York"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Michael Bloomberg"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Russians"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Torshin"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Butina"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger's"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Froman"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Sturm Ruger"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NRA"}, {"category": "MONEY", "term": "800,000"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "last year"}], "description": "Next week, activist shareholders will make their first attempt at shaking up the gun industry using their votes instead of just their voices.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/01/gun-safety-activists-prepare-to-put-their-power-behind-shareholder-voting-at-sturm-ruger.html", "author": "Reuters", "title": "Gun safety activists prepare to put their power behind shareholder voting at Sturm Ruger"}, {"time": "2018-05-03T08:45:51-0400", "body": " show chapters \"Fast Money\" final trades: SNAP, SPOT and more 6:16 PM ET Wed, 2 May 2018 | 01:00 The \"Fast Money\" traders shared their first moves for the market open. Pete Najarian was a buyer of AbbVie. Karen Finerman was a buyer of Xerox. Dan Nathan was a buyer of Snap. Guy Adami was a buyer of Spotify. Trader disclosure: On May 2, 2018, the following stocks and commodities mentioned or intended to be mentioned on CNBC's \"Fast Money\" were owned by the \"Fast Money\" traders: Pete Najarian is long calls AAPL, ABBV, AKS, AMD, ARNC, BAC, BEL, CI, COP, CTL, DVN, GLD, GM, HD, KHC, LUV, MAS, MGM, MSFT, NEM, OIH, OLN, SLV, SVU, XHB, XLF, XOP. Pete is long stock AAPL, ATVI, BAC, BKE, C, FUL, GM, HLT, IBM, INTC, KMB, KMI, KO, LOW, LVS, MRK, MSFT, MU, PEP, PFE, PII, STZ, TGT, TPX, UFS, UPS, VFC, WYNN, XOM. Pete owns puts QQQ, XLI. Pete bought ABBV, XOP calls. Pete sold CRM, FB, IBM, MRVL, MU, WMB calls. Pete sold KMX, PG stock. Pete bought XLI puts. Karen Finerman's firm is long ANTM, C, FB, FL, FNAC, GOOG, GOOGL, GLNG, GMLP, INTC, JPM, KORS puts, LYV, SPY puts, SPY put spreads, WIFI. Her firm is short IWM. Karen Finerman is long AAL, BAC, BOT Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Ethereum, C, CAT, DAL, DVYE, DXJ, EEM, EPI, EWW, EWZ, DVYE, FB, FL, GM, GMLP, GLNG, GOOG, GOOGL, INTC, JPM, LYV, KFL, KORS, KORS calls, MA, MTW, SEDG, SPY puts, TACO, WIFI, WFM. Karen Finerman is short TBT calls. Bitcoin and Ethereum are in her kids' Trust. Karen bought CAT. Dan Nathan is long SNAP, SPY. Dan bought SNAP. Dan sold IWM. Guy Adami is long CELG, EXAS, GDX, INTC. Guy Adami's wife, Linda Snow, works at Merck. ", "urlToImage": "https://fm.cnbc.com/applications/cnbc.com/resources/img/editorial/2017/01/27/104245575-final-trade-logo.jpg?v=1485535953", "keywords": [{"category": "ORG", "term": "SNAP"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "6:16 PM ET"}, {"category": "CARDINAL", "term": "2"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2018"}, {"category": "TIME", "term": "01:00"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "The \"Fast Money\""}, {"category": "ORDINAL", "term": "first"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete Najarian"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AbbVie"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Karen Finerman"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Xerox"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Dan Nathan"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Snap"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Guy Adami"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Spotify"}, {"category": "NORP", "term": "Trader"}, {"category": "DATE", "term": "May 2, 2018"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CNBC"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "Fast Money"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "the \"Fast Money\""}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete Najarian"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AAPL"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "ABBV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AKS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AMD"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "ARNC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BAC"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "BEL"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "CI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "COP"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CTL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "GLD"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "GM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "HD"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KHC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "LUV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MAS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MGM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MSFT"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "NEM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "OIH"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "OLN"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SLV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XHB"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XLF"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XOP"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "AAPL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "ATVI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BAC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BKE"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "FUL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "GM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "HLT"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "IBM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "INTC"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "KMB"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KMI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KO"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "LOW"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "LVS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MRK"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MSFT"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MU"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "PEP"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "PFE"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "PII"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "STZ"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "TGT"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "UFS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "VFC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "WYNN"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XOM"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "QQQ"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XLI"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "ABBV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XOP"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "PRODUCT", "term": "CRM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "IBM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MRVL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MU"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "WMB"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KMX"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Pete"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "XLI"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Karen Finerman's"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "ANTM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "GOOG"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "GLNG"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "GMLP"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "INTC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "KORS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "LYV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SPY"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SPY"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "WIFI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "IWM"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Karen Finerman"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "AAL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "BAC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "BOT Bitcoin"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bitcoin Cash"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CAT"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "DAL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "DVYE"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "DXJ"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EEM"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EPI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EWW"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EWZ"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "DVYE"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "FL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "GM"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "GMLP"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "GLNG"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "INTC"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "LYV"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KFL"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KORS"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "KORS"}, {"category": "WORK_OF_ART", "term": "MA"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "MTW"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SPY"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "TACO,"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "WIFI"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "WFM"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Karen Finerman"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Bitcoin"}, {"category": "GPE", "term": "Ethereum"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Karen"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CAT"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Dan Nathan"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "SNAP"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "SPY"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Dan"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "SNAP"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Dan"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "IWM"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Guy Adami"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "CELG"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "EXAS"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "GDX"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "INTC"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Guy Adami's"}, {"category": "PERSON", "term": "Linda Snow"}, {"category": "ORG", "term": "Merck"}], "description": "The \"Fast Money\" traders share their first moves for the market open.", "link": "https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/03/your-first-trade-for-thursday-may-3.html", "author": "", "title": "Your first trade for Thursday, May 3"}, {"time": "2018-05-07T13:04:12-0400", "body": " Daniel Acker | Bloomberg | Getty Images Deepak Ahuja, Tesla CFO (left) and Elon Musk, Tesla founder and CEO (right), at the Nasdaq opening bell ceremony for the Tesla initial public offering on Tuesday, June 29, 2010. For five quarters in a row ahead of Wednesday earnings, free cash flow has been negative at Tesla, and the electric-car maker has been burning through more than $6,500 every minute, according to data compiled by Bloomberg this week. What's more, executives, including on the financial department, are coming and going. Yet this isn't the first time Tesla has had to survive some pretty harsh financial woes. And no one knows that better than Deepak Ahuja. The CFO joined Tesla in July 2008. Two months later the global economy crashed. Challenged with managing Tesla's balance sheet through the 2008 crisis, Ahuja saw Tesla through its hugely successful IPO just two years later. Shares of the company continued on their upward trajectory, and in 2015 Ahuja retired somewhat of a hero. Now he's back to reclaim his hero status as a cash-manager, having retaken the CFO post in February 2017 after Jason Wheeler left the company. Ahuja's task will be difficult, and there probably will be speed bumps. Tesla continues to burn through cash at an alarming rate and could run out of money before year-end, according to the most bearish analyst reports. Last year the company raised more than $1 billion in equity and later offered almost $2 billion in a junk-debt issue. In late March, Moody's downgraded Tesla credit and changed the outlook to \"negative\" from \"stable.\" In its Wednesday earnings report for the first quarter, even though cash flow remained negative, Tesla reported a slower cash burn rate and losses that were narrower tha