[{"filename": "AAR 5440112001", "text": "Once the ene force was found the Air Cavalry developed the situation and provided the Commander of the 1st ARVN Division with the size and disposition of the en troops thus allowing him to effectively maneuver against the threat to FSB Reilly. 17 27 September Troop was in direct support of the 1st ARVN Division in the vicinity of FSB Reilly. Troop was used in general support of both the 1st ARVN Division and the 101st Airborne Division. Lessons Learned The attempted assault on FSB Reilly was prevented by the early detection of ene locations and intentions. REPRODUCED AT THE NATIONAL ARCHIVES DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY TROOP 2D SQUADRON 17TH CAVALRY 101ST AIRBORNE DIVISIDN AMBL APe San Francisco 96383 AVOO SQ 18 October 1970 SUBJECT Feeder After Action Report September 1970 30 September 1970 Commanding Officer 2d Squadron 17th Cavalry 101st Airborne Division Ambl ATTN APe San Francisco 96383. On the early morning on the 15 September 1970 FLIR spotted possible truck depot. Elements of Troop 2d Squadron 17th Cavalry conducted visual reconnaissance missions to the south east and west of FSB Spear. Sequence of Significant Activities September an unknown size ene force was known to be in the location of FSB Spear. This action points out the effectiveness of Air Cavalry assets when used as itegral units and employed on mission basis. Commanders Reoommendationsl Air Cavalry assets be used to looate and develope the ene strength and disposition", "keywords": [{"term": "the Air Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ARVN Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FSB Reilly", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "17", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "27", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "September Troop", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 1st ARVN Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FSB Reilly", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Troop", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 101st Airborne Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FSB", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "THE NATIONAL ARCHIVES DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY TROOP 2D SQUADRON 17TH CAVALRY 101ST", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "San Francisco", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "18 October 1970", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "SUBJECT Feeder After Action Report", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "September 1970 30", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "September 1970", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2d", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Squadron 17th Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Ambl", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "San Francisco", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "96383", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the early morning", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "15", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "September 1970", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Troop 2d Squadron 17th Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FSB Spear", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "September", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "FSB Spear", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Air Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Commanders Reoommendationsl Air Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "October 1970"}, {"filename": "AAR 23850429001", "text": "Two searchlights Battery 29th Artillery were attached to the 2d Battalion 9th Artilleey during the period 10 2Z pril 19671 with the mise ion of illuminating the perimeter of an area in close proximity to the 3d Brigade TF forward base can. Intelligence indicated that the 2d Regiment of the 3d NVA Division was located in the high ground to the west of DUC PHO Gity. General Operation IE JEUNE comnenced l91200H April 1967 with the 3d Brigade TF tactically deployed in the OOC PHO Area Under the operational control of the 1st Cavalry Division Airmobile. other intelligence sources and agent reports placed numerous eneJrtV units in the high ground to the northwest of the suspected location of the 2d VC Regiment. Aviatioh Battalion suppori the 3d ipde TF with the 174th Assault Helicopter Co Dpan ye Troop liftS landing zone preparations cotrma nci and control capability and re supply mission were provided Artillery atpport During the period 19 22 AprU 1967 the mi sion the 2d Battalion 9th Artillet7 was direct support of the 3d Brigade TF. Alt hough 3d Brigade elements suffered 10 casualties WIA from sniper fire and booby traps the eneqr sutrered ar re 29 KIA due in great sense not only to the superior US air and ground firepower but also to the aggressive spirit of the individual soldier. The 2d VC Regiment and these other force posed major threat to CIDG and Special Forces in the area of operations as well as to DUC PHO District itself. Battelj 4th Battalion 60th Artillery was attached to the 2d Battalion 9th Artilleey during the period 19 22 April 1967 with the mission of providing direct fire support for LZ GUADAICANAL. other intelligence sources and agent reports placed numerous enemy units in the high ground to the northwest of the suspected location or the 2d VC Regiment. be eration ended with the 3d Brigade TF 25th Infantry Division being released from the operational control of the 1st CavaJ ri Division AirmbUe to the operational control of TF OREGON", "keywords": [{"term": "Two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Battery 29th Artillery", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "the 2d Battalion 9th Artilleey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "pril 19671", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TF", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the 2d Regiment", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "NVA Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DUC PHO Gity", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "April 1967", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TF", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the OOC PHO Area", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "the 1st Cavalry Division Airmobile", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 2d VC Regiment", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Aviatioh Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3d", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "TF", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the 174th Assault Helicopter Co Dpan", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Artillery", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "19 22", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "1967", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2d Battalion 9th Artillet7", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3d Brigade", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "WIA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "29", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "KIA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "The 2d VC Regiment", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CIDG and Special Forces", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "DUC PHO District", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "4th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "the 2d Battalion 9th Artilleey", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "19 22 April 1967", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the 2d VC Regiment", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "TF 25th Infantry Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 1st", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "CavaJ ri Division AirmbUe", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "TF", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "OREGON", "category": "GPE"}], "time": "May 1967"}, {"filename": "AAR 26240122006", "text": "During the evening hoUJ II ot April nlll llrous engngffl llnts occurred tt VC tried to br out of the oncirclemnt The entire obj octi Te va11 etf ctivelf illun inated thro1J8hout the night by Spocky flnro ship aortie11 IT Hq 60 ruxl 60 Inf wre ll ed frol Binh Phuoc to Rach Kian arriving at 2020 hours At nd inight 60 Int wns rm mitted to til gap vie XS 692704 between Inf ind 10 C11v JiVN. At npi roxiI ntel 600 the brig de RRF 60 In was nirLftod 1nto LZ vie 713690 anc Xlved along tha south bnnk ot the river MG ostnblished blocking position The encircl8ltlllnt vas complstod 60 Int was a1rll ted to LZ vie 687713 and IOna to blooldng position on the northern portion of the MJ vio XS 686705. Tho 3d Brignrle ntt nt ked See Ovorlo to locnte and tcstroy the eneley in the objoctive aren nd co pturti or ctoet roy ll one IY oquipm nt nnd upplies loco therein. erinl aurveillanco of the riren of the 1ni thl strike ve 11 invnh1able 1n iclontl fying the VC farce mich h1 been locllt ttd and hich rec pitat tho operatfon Ini 0v91 11 of AO Wl US MURRAY CH RU URRAY Colonel Infnntr1 Co rYUldi ng r1. During the night OO 022SH 0254HT Co Int IJ CCN to 39 Int in an 111bush position vie XS 341790 flngng tot ot ins he di north ta rd Sl igon. nt the nntic nnd returned tio 12 Copre nders This opernt ion Mora thnn nrv other ir ffa he rtediat reection po 1J1llty the brign ilhane nn ol Ol ati ln ot thia magnitude con be generated aui partad with irtUlll 17 no time tr plan ref locta great nbi it nnd initint on over1 mant ez ot the cocrwvl Whan colJll lng th lessee suGtninert b7 tha Jd Brign 1n coI pl iaon 1th those Wlictod on the eno1 11 the overwhel rting ire powr ot well trninecl Md d111cipl1nt1tl unit is tli ronstratocl lyond doubt Jj Less0ns Learned Tho brign le rust rzinbin the flexibilit to divort plnmed operntlons ngniruit lucrnti tnrgcts prorluced by he rd int elli ence Upon initi ltion nn unsche iuled operation pl Ma llllat. The disposition ot units nt nlghttl ll lCIII IffC and Co1a nnd int Hha Di IS 91 822 Co nt IS 858900 Md Co 39 IJ Jl lr 39 Int nt XS 89 802. the 39 Int oonituotod ainobllo and rooon in tt co cpvrntions nolt heMt of Ilia Be. The tin 11 dhpoaiticn ot thu unit lt nighttill HIC Co ind it FS PB SaolN X3 789769 Co at XS 791JJZ9 nd Co it XS 814822. At 2020 urs the rol wos avilf eng 1gecl by SA Ild lt fire orn tt ir south Cpook7 flare ship illuminated the reu as nrtiller fire 1o ns Ued in on the suspec er VC positin to In cl ition J9 inf and 10 RVN rUr pl ncod frox RAch Kion tl roinforco the patrol", "keywords": [{"term": "the evening", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "VC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Spocky", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "60", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "60", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Binh Phuoc", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Rach Kian", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2020 hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "60 Int", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "XS 692704", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Inf", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "600", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1nto", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "LZ", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "713690", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Xlved", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MG", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "60 Int", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "LZ", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "687713", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "MJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "XS 686705", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Brignrle", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "IY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1ni", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1n", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "VC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Ini 0v91", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "AO", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "US", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "URRAY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the night", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "OO 022SH 0254HT", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Int IJ CCN", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "39", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "XS 341790", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Mora", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "1J1llty", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "17", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Whan", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "suGtninert", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Jd Brign", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Wlictod", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "eno1 11", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Md d111cipl1nt1tl", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Jj Less0ns", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ma", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Co1a", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Hha Di", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "91 822 Co", "category": "PERCENT"}, {"term": "IJ Jl", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "39", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "XS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "802", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "39", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Ilia", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "HIC Co", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FS PB SaolN X3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "XS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "814822", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2020", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "1gecl", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "SA Ild", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1o ns Ued", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "VC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "RVN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RAch Kion", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "February 1968"}, {"filename": "CHECO F031100020271", "text": "Phase beginning on 24 Jan 66 was the movement of the maneuver battalions to the opera tion area by USAF 123 Army UH lD and CH 47 and ground vehicles Phase II planned for the morn ng of 25 Jan 66 began with the 1st Batta lion of the 7th Regiment Cav making diversionary attack on hill mass to the southeast of Bong Son GEORGE The Cav was to move to te north to secure Position DOG for the Brigade Command Post. Based on the defensive positions and number and type of weapons encountered it was estimated that elements of the 93rd and 95th Battalions of the Quyet Chien 2n VC Regiment and elements of the Regimental Headquarters and Weapons Battalion were engaged in the lron Triangle Extensive TAC Air was used to prepare landing zones and air cover was used throughout the operation to strike at pockets of enemy resistance. The 12 Cav was to be landed in the northern end of the area of operation and would attack to the south. Phase III was to start on 28 Jan 66 with airmobile and ground attacks north up the coastal plain by the Cav air landing of the Cavon the high ground to the west then attacking to the east. The ARVN area of operation was pr1ma rilyto the north and west of the 1st Cavalry between the coast and Route. On the 4th and 5th of March the 2nd Brigade moved from Bong Son back to he ase camp at An Khe thus completing the movement of the 11 1st Air Cavalry out of the area of operation. Prior to the initiation of the operation the. responsible for destroying the 18th Regiment Command Post and routing the enemy Captain David Brown the FAC for 12 Cavalry gave the following 25 accounts of air support for the battalion On 22 February TAC Air was called in to support Company which was engaged by an unknown number of Viet Cong. and to the southeast of the 3rd Brigade area of operation. On one of its robes the 12 Cavalry came under heavy fire and the Cavalry was directed to sweep the hill mass to the NE of BIRD where the activity had taken place", "keywords": [{"term": "24 Jan 66", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "USAF 123 Army UH", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CH 47", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Phase II", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "25 Jan 66", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Batta", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the 7th Regiment Cav", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bong Son", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Brigade Command Post", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "93rd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "95th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "VC Regiment", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Regimental Headquarters", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Weapons Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Triangle Extensive TAC Air", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "The 12 Cav", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "28 Jan 66", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Cavon", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the 1st Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Route", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "4th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "5th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "March", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2nd Brigade", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bong Son", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "11 1st", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Air Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 18th Regiment Command Post", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "David Brown", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "FAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "25", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "22 February", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "3rd Brigade", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 12 Cavalry", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Cavalry", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "the NE of BIRD", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "Mar 1966"}, {"filename": "CHECO F031100071097", "text": "js the cd fren the receirt Cr re est for an immediEte air strike until dlV lce is fhed at the tarpet by the anOOd FAC. The objectives of the sty Bronco Evalua tion ere to. The AIO and FACs assipned to the 25th Inf ntry Division TACF also locpt at Cu Chi participated in the rro. was establis for the Tactical Air Control Center to conduct an oJ erational evaluation of the anred FAC conce in SEA. Fhase II laS ccnducted in CC US to develop taetics profUes and procedures for the eval uation of the armed. the cost of the cOII nation. Data collection on each mission as recorded by the FAC and the USAF radio orera tor the Brip de TACP. Jerendinp on the she of the er tac nd jnter sity cf receiveu the rround cc mandprccuJd ueft crdn ce cr ir ed te close air Sl ncrt. The CV lOA aircraft and ctical Air Control Farty 5uHorti the 2nd rigade US 25th Infantry Division ere utilized in the eval tion. TIe follCN ing rersonne1 ere resronsible for the Iranagement aM conduct of the test am for the rrerarc tion of this report", "keywords": [{"term": "Cr", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the anOOd FAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Bronco Evalua", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "AIO", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "25th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Inf ntry Division TACF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Cu Chi", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the Tactical Air Control Center", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "FAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "SEA", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "CC US", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "profUes", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "FAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "USAF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Brip de TACP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Jerendinp", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "mandprccuJd", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "CV", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Air Control Farty", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "5uHorti", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "2nd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "US 25th Infantry Division", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "follCN", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Iranagement", "category": "PERSON"}], "time": "July 1969"}, {"filename": "COMNAVFORV 13120201001a", "text": "The Swi ft boat destroyed the large building which the evading personnel were seen to enter as well as four additional surrounding structureso On the 29th PCF 62 on routine MARKEl TIME patrol along the coast of Sinh Dinh province eight miles south of Qui Nhon sighted ar unlighted sampan heading toward the beach The Swift boat ilium inated the sampan and one man las observed manning the tiller As the Swift boat drew closer to the ampan five six persons in green and khaki uniforms were observed lying in the bottom of the craft The sampan failed to heed the signals from the Swift to stop and as the patrol boat drew still doser one the sampan occupants arose and threw grenade which exploded on the fore castle of the peF wounding the Officer in Charge Two more gre nades were thrown one bouncing down into the Swift boatia cabin and the other landing on the starboard side main deck wounding another crewman The Swift then opened up on the enemy with 50 caliber machine gun fire destroyed the sampan and killed the oc cupants probable though moderately damaged PeF 62 proceeded to Qui Nhon er her own power after being relieved on station by another Swift boat Second Coastal Zone ft7 provided blocking services in sup port of ARVN and Korean units approximately four miles east of Qui Nhon on 10 January CONFIDENTIAL CONFIDENTIAL Third Coastal Zone The aggregate of junk lJ1d sampan traffic ined low in the Third Coastal Zone during January as only 261 craft were detectad approximately the same number that were detected during December. In response to the heavy fighting which erupted throughout Vietnam during the last days of the month coastal surveillance forces continually aided allied forces with gunfire support and all units maintained alert and aggressive patrolso OPERATION MARKET TIME During January there was an increase in Operation MARKET TIME activity as the heavy seas and inclement weather associated with the northeast monsoon season abat in the northern coastal zon thus allowing all MARKEl TIME stations to be manned thl ougho tt high percentage of the month. The Swift boat aided by helicopters recovered three of the four crewmembers and the peF located the wreckage and provided cover for divers who recovered the unition from the downed helicopter. The Swift boat returned and suppressed the fire and destroyed the sampan. The majority of the gunfire suwort missions were fired in the Third and Fourth Coastal Zones where fair weather prevailed throughout the month. The task force organization of TF 116 is revised to effect greater responsiveness and enhance the coordinating capa bility of the elements of the Hiver Patrol orce. First Coastal Zone Alt cugh the weather in the northern areas of the First Coas tal Zone was unpredictable during January routine MARKEl TIME ac tivitiy ncreased as the zone patrol units detectad 15 804 junks and sampans duri the month an increase of over 000 from Decem ber total. The Swift boat stood by 200 yards from the beach and contacted the Marines who later turned the detainees over to the Vietnamese Navy Coastal Group 12 for further investigation. On the 22nd PCF 55 provided immediate nav gunfire assistance to the Vietnamese Navy Coastal Group 14 which was receiving heavy harassment fire approximately 13 miles southeast of Danang on the coast of the South China Sea. The boardings resulted in the detention of 53 craft and 438 pereons", "keywords": [{"term": "four", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "29th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "PCF 62", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "TIME", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Sinh Dinh", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "eight miles", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Qui Nhon", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "five", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Charge Two", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "50 caliber", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "PeF 62", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Qui Nhon", "category": "WORK_OF_ART"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Second Coastal Zone", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Korean", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "approximately four miles", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Qui Nhon", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10 January CONFIDENTIAL CONFIDENTIAL Third", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Coastal Zone", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "only 261", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Vietnam", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the last days of the month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "OPERATION MARKET TIME", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "four", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "peF", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Third", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Fourth Coastal Zones", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TF 116", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the Hiver Patrol", "category": "LAW"}, {"term": "First Coastal Zone Alt", "category": "LAW"}, {"term": "First", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TIME", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "15", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "804", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "over 000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Decem", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Swift", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "200 yards", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Marines", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "the Vietnamese Navy Coastal Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "22nd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "PCF 55", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "the Vietnamese Navy Coastal Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "14", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "approximately 13 miles", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Danang", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the South China Sea", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "53", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "438", "category": "CARDINAL"}], "time": "9 February 1968"}, {"filename": "COMNAVFORV 13120201001b", "text": "helicopter fire team on routine pa trol spotted large concentration of enemy junks and sampans just north of the rTOuth of the HaIT4 Luong river along the coast of the South China Sea The Seawolvo then piloted their armed gunsh ps in an 2ttack agaifist the enemy supply force expending 2c75 inch rockets and 62 rn rrachine gun fire in relJeated attacks Although light small arms and autoffi tic weap ms fire was returned there were no friendly casualtieso Two secQndary explosions were observed in the surface targets and wer8 estimated to be comparable to th lt of 155 mm shells Four junks 00 10 amYinS were destrord and 20 other craft were damagedu On the evening of 10 January Operation PHEAKNESS III was la2nched along the Ba Lai river an area of high Viet Cong activity particularly around the focal points of Thu Ba Lai village and Ong LU0ng Canal The first was major staging administrE tive and 3st area while the second area was rrajor receivirlS and transportation 41 CONF IDENTIAL CJNFIDENTIAL center for and arrrnunition. The increased 40 and 41 rocket attacks alone killed one FBR sailor and wounded 36 othersj in addition to one Department of the Navy civilian as the Viet Co scored hit on the patrol boatso However the enemy suffered greater losses 120 killed 36 wounded and 51 captured as Operation GAME WARDEN con tinued to deny tr Viet Cong the free use of the waterways of the Mekong Delta and the Rung Sat Special Zone. CONDON USN the Commanding Offic of Underwater Demo lition Team TWELVE and wounded one rewm ember The next morning two ASPS 91 and 9l proceeding south of the Tai Phu streamp th miles southeast of Ben Tres were ambushed by 40 rockets and automatic weapom fiI from the west bank The enemy fire was rapidly silenced but Viet Cong c8sualt ies were undetermined One Vietnamese nterpreter was slightly wounded Operations in Qinh Tuo ln On 22 January thL MRB relocated to the convergence of the Kekong and Co Chien rivera 1n order to provide support for MRF units conducting Operation CORONADO 22 23 January in the Cai Be district of Din Tuong province. For the rellE inder of the peration and until the vy units ere ready to return to their bases at Binh Thuy and Sa Dec on February the SMLs kept key installations in the city secure wf ile the PBRs patrollen and blockaded all ater entrances into the city. The special search and rescue operation was conceived planned and executed within haure of the reported crash and the search units of the MRF moved out froID Dong Tam at 0200 under the cover of darkness to commence the operation. PERs 723 and 726 responded to the call of the boats under fire and at full power roared to the scene of the action. For two days the Navy helicopters CONFIDENrIAL were constantly airborne naking repeated strikes against the Viet Cong who had overrun parts of the city while the PERs operated on the river to close off the enemy avenues of resupp. Becaus of the size of the enemy force the SEAL wi thdrew to the river to join up with the PBRs and report their intelligence At 10 the city of Chau Doc carne under heavy enemy attack by large concentration of enemy troops estimated to be about 400 men. While the enemy con tinued to fire on the patrol PBR 112 went alongside the stricken boat and removed the rew members from the burning craft. While transitting the canal psychological operations were conducted and all water traffic was searchedo Flying ahead of the boats the Navy lISeawolveslt be dn blasting enemy bunker posi ions alcmg the canal while the AL3 were put ashore at the upper and lower ends of tre canal As the SEALs rroved in the Sea wolves continued their airstrike as the boats along he canal be gan their attack against 1iet ong positionsd Viet Gong resistance wa limited to sporadic small arms fire but there was no doubt about his pre5ence Nearly every structure flew Viet Cong flag and contained pictures of comnunist leaders Jhen the SEALs om pleted their sweep they had captured 51 Viet Cong sU3pects", "keywords": [{"term": "the HaIT4 Luong", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "the South China Sea", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "2c75 inch", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "62", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "155", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Four", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "20", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the evening", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "10 January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Lai", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Thu Ba Lai", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "first", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "3st", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "second", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "receivirlS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "41", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "CONF IDENTIAL CJNFIDENTIAL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "40", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "41", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "FBR", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "36", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Department of the", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Navy", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Viet Co", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "120", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "36", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "51", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Operation GAME", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Mekong Delta", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Rung Sat Special Zone", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Underwater Demo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "ASPS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "91", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "9l", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Ben Tres", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "40", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "fiI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "One", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Vietnamese", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Operations", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Qinh Tuo", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "22 January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "MRB", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Kekong and Co Chien", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1n", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "MRF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Operation CORONADO", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "22 23 January", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Cai", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Din Tuong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "rellE", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "February", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "MRF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Dong Tam", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "0200", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "723", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "726", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "two days", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Navy", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Viet Cong", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Becaus", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "SEAL", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Chau Doc", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "about 400", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Navy", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "AL3", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Sea", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Viet Gong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Jhen", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "51", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Viet Cong sU3pects", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "9 March 1968"}, {"filename": "COMNAVFORV 13120201001c", "text": "The cessation of the Truce was followed by reports of massive Viet Gong attacks on My Tho Ben Tre Vinh Long and Can Tho in the IV Corps areao As the general tuation rapidly deteriorated contingency plans were immediately put into effect to withdraw to the MRB in to better react to requests for reinforcements from the beseiged major provincial cities of the Mekong Deltao On the afternoon of 31 January jI twv infantry cf mpanies of the MRF were airlifted from the area of operations one to assist in the deferrse of Vinh Long Airfield which was nder heavy attack and the other to reinforce the base defenses Dong Tamo Later that evening the remaining irSantry companies embarked in their riverine craft conducted nighttime withdrawal from the Ruong Stream the ene of devastating battle on December. the ITDuth of the. Air strikes and naval gunfire were called in upon the site of the ambush during the afte noon of the 25th and 77 CONFIDENTIAL CJ IFIDl IAL 0n the 27th normal river traffic resumed with cOiltinuous mine sweeping being. Eight Viet Cong then attempted second assault on the building and were killed by the combined firepower of the VNN and Vietnamese Military Police. The Viet Gong fire was on suppressed and the PHR sailors evacuated two wounded Popular Force troops and assisted in extinguishing fires st rted in the village by the enemy grenades. UPI ABC and CBS was briefed on the capabilities of the air cushioned vehicle by Command Coastal Divison SEVENTEEN and also observed demonstration of the vehicle ability to operate over land and watero Meanwhile on the same day the PACV ramp Jess than mile came under sporadic small arms fire which C3 l1Sed bullet hole in PACV. The maj rity of the civic action performed around the junk bases was in the Jrm of 2elf help projects wherein UNCLJ SSIFThD 94 UNCLASSIFIED the villagers do IWst 0f the work. The effectiveness of the corrective actions recoID flencted by the IG were not measurable at nonth end because of the turmoil generated by the country wide Viet Gong attacks. About 0400 on the 4lth Coastal Group 11 junks patrolling on the Cua viet iver supported Dai loc hamlet with Tr 1chine gun and IJK rtar fire and directed USHC artillery fire into the positions of the Jiet Cong force attacking the hamlet. The missions were conducted en route to and in the area of operation in Dinh Tuong and Kien Hoa provinces", "keywords": [{"term": "Truce", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Viet Gong", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Tho Ben Tre Vinh Long", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "IV Corps", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "MRB", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Mekong Deltao", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the afternoon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "MRF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Vinh Long Airfield", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dong Tamo", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Later that evening", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "irSantry", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "nighttime", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "the Ruong Stream", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "ITDuth", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "77", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "cOiltinuous", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Eight", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "second", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "VNN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Vietnamese Military Police", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Viet Gong", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "PHR", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "two", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Popular Force", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "UPI ABC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "CBS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Command Coastal Divison SEVENTEEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the same day", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "PACV", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PACV", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Jrm of", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "UNCLJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "94", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "UNCLASSIFIED", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "0f", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "recoID", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "IG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Viet Gong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "About 0400", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Coastal Group", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Cua", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Dai", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "1chine", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "IJK", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Jiet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Dinh Tuong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Kien Hoa", "category": "PERSON"}], "time": "9 April 1968"}, {"filename": "COMNAVFORV 13120201001d", "text": "At the close of the mon riverine fDrees in the Thtrd and Fourth Riverine Areas were 120 CONFIDENTIAL NOFORN chiefly engaged in defensive operations to counter the Viet Cong ret Jffensive. Navy forces to interdict Viet Cong movement on the major water ways of the Mekong Delta and the RSSZ. The RAG boats landed the PF troops in the area and then searched sampans on the river for enemy infiltrators or supplies. Few assignments even in the civilian parish are as interesting and challenging During phase one of the tour functioned mainly as Circuit Hider of Mval Support Activity Saigon visit ing sue bases as Nha ile in the Rung Sat Spe cia Zone Vinh Long Sa Dec and Can Tho in the Eekong Delta and occa ionally xlducting servi es at Cui Jhon on the coast in III Corps. the night of 31 Janwry the Area were eng ged in troop lifts evacuation and logistic lifts in support of the cities of Can Tho Tho Vir Long and Chau Doc. Of course part of the real joy of this ministry is to meet and work with the young children of this war rn land and see them given fresh start in the wc rld. force made up of Navy craft and Army units designed and trained for amphibious assaults in the Mekong Delta and the RSSZ. This operation in the vicinity of the lam Co Dong river 15 miles southwest of Saigon resulted in three Viet Cong killed one captured and nine suspects detained. This is particularly true in the case of the hssistant Force Chaplain job on the staff of Commander. Riverine Area Naval Comma nds At the end of JanuAry the RAGs and the River Transport Escort GrcJup had 225 craft assigned 1aily average of 150 craft were avai1 ble for operations and 129 were employed", "keywords": [{"term": "120", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the Viet Cong", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Jffensive", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Navy", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Mekong Delta", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RSSZ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "RAG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the PF troops", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Circuit Hider of Mval Support Activity Saigon", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Nha", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Rung Sat Spe", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the Eekong Delta", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "III Corps", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the night", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Janwry the Area", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Tho Vir Long", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Chau Doc", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Navy", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Army", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Mekong Delta", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "RSSZ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Co Dong", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "15 miles", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "Saigon", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "three", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Viet Cong", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "nine", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Force Chaplain", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Riverine Area Naval Comma", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the end of JanuAry", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the River Transport Escort GrcJup", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "225", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "150", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "129", "category": "CARDINAL"}], "time": "9 April 1968"}, {"filename": "Phung Hoang AAR 24993208053", "text": "30 20 24 45 21 24 824 117 117 13 30 291 34 12 15 147 31 12 26 21 10 14 17 63 22 24 120 22 26 18 23 2Q 13 12 18 14 21 110 16 26 22 71 51. 18 35 555 129 272 32 20 39 500 87 110 112 69 20 11 31 10 it 13 20 31 13 65 34. BINH LONG 82 75 33 42 BIND TUY 86 82 73 GIA DINH 103 113 113 HAU NGHIA 89 93 93 LONG AN 303 330 330 LONG IOIANB 84 60 24 PHUOC LONG 38 16 Ut 21 PHUOC TUY 108 lUt TAY NINH 95 15 9h RUNG SAT 26 14 24 IV CORPS 1533 658 1638 AN GIANG 37 37 37 57 14 32 AN XUYEN 102 116 116 18 BA XUYEN 91 112 112 21 BAC LIEU 71 75 75 CHAU DOC lll 112 112 11 20 13 13 18 18 13 16 10. 37 24 CHUONG THIEN iJ7 89 89 DINH nJONG 81 97 97 18 GO CONG 120 118 118 KIEN GIANG 46 146 146 KIEN BOA jJ KIEN PHONG 42 60 60 18 KIEN TUONG 59 58 58 PHONG DINH 146 rr SADEC 99 04 10 VINH BINH 15 175 21 14 lt tir NH 34 ffi ffi 1t TRAINING ENTER 205 21 211 12. TOTAL 1572 303 CORPS 134 51 QUANG NAM QUANG NGAI 80 40 QUANG TIN 23 QUANG TRI 18 THUA TIUD 10 11 II CORPS 306 70 BINH DINH 44 13 BINH THU DARLAC KHANH BOA 10 34 KON TUM LAM DONG NINH TBtJA il PHU BON PHU YEN 18 PLEIKU QUANG DUC 20 TUI DUC III CORPS 446 56 BIEN BOA BINH DUON li BINH LONG BINH TUY GIA DINH HAU NGHIA l5 LONG AN 20 LONG lnl PHUOC LONC. Provincial Reconnaissance Unit Monthly Report As of 31 August 1968 II. 162 21 ll2 295 383 19 10 30 59 f79 16 26 47 19 28 31 48 52 38 39 17 18. Provincial Reconnaissance Unit Monthly Report As of 31 August 1968 III INTEL REPORT DISSEMINATED. 203 56 113 26 14 20 140 42 42 66 10 21 26 36 12 22 36 36. Iii 81 47 36 79 14 134 QUANG NGAI 338 353 348 15 QUANG TIN 195 195 195 QUANG TRI 186 188 188 12 10 rH IE 21 18 t1 tI CORPS 825 79 417 374 20", "keywords": [{"term": "30", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "20", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "24 45", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "24", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "824", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "117", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "117", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "30", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "291", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "15", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "14 17", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "22", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "24", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "120", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18 23", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "13", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "14", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "110", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "71 51", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "35", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "272", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "32", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "20 39", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "500", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "87", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "112", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "69", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "20 11 31 10", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "13", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "20 31 13", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "65 34", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "82", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "75", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "TUY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "86", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "82 73", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "103", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "113", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "113", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "93 93", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "LONG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "303", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "84", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "60", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "24", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "PHUOC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "38 16", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "PHUOC TUY", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "108", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "TAY", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "15 9h", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "IV CORPS", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "658", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "37 37 37 57", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "14 32", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "XUYEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "102", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "116", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "116", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "BA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "112", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "112", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "BAC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "71 75 75", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "CHAU DOC", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "112", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "16 10", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "24", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "CHUONG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "THIEN", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "DINH", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "81 97", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "97", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "GO CONG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "120", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "118", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "118", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "46 146", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "146", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "KIEN BOA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "KIEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "42 60", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "KIEN", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "59", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "PHONG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "146", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "SADEC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "99", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "15", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "175", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "14", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "NH 34", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "1", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "205", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "211", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "12", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "303", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "CORPS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "QUANG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "23", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "TRI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "II CORPS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "44 13", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "BINH", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "THU", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "KHANH", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "10 34", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "KON", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "LAM", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PHU BON", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "PLEIKU", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "DUC 20", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "56", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "BIEN BOA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "HAU", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "20", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "LONG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "PHUOC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Provincial Reconnaissance Unit Monthly Report", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "31 August 1968 II", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "162 21", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "295", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "383", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "19", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "59", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "16", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "28", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "48 52", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "38", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "39", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Provincial Reconnaissance Unit Monthly Report", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "31 August 1968 III", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "203", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "56", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "113", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "140", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "42 42", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "21", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "26", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "36 12 22", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "36", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "81", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "79", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "14", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "NGAI 338", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "353", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "348", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "QUANG", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "195", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "195 195", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "TRI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "186", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "188", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "188", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "10 rH", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "18", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "79", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "417 374", "category": "MONEY"}, {"term": "20", "category": "CARDINAL"}], "time": "August 1968"}, {"filename": "SF AAR 24990401008", "text": "The mission Task Force Bath was to conduct reconnaisBance and quick reaction operation to seek out and destroy elements of the 95B Regiment in the area South and Southwe11t ot An Khe. The company patrolled in this area until 231600 hours and then moved west to follow the e11gnraent ot Dak Xaro River to exploit the enemy shortage of water in the area. th the mission of moveing north to help block enemy movement south as the result of 26th MSF company contact and the result ot friendly elements ioovement operating to the north of AO BATH. At 71530 hours BRl 88319 the comparoJ was directed to swing south and then east to clear along the southern banks of the Dak Pop Ho iiver. The company continued to sweep with negative contact and was subsequently extracted to An at 021830 houn. the MSF is to be taxed will oontinueing operat ions of this nature that the atructure of the comm and and control ele ment be complemented to avoid aving vacaum when indi vidual start members deploy to the field. During the first 16 days of the operation ground fog prevented the use of ircraft late at night and during the early houri of the morning. The 21th 181 Company was relocated into 1tD Bll1E at 241100 hoU1 at BR27l329 with the mission of aweeping weet along the southem aide of the Dak Xaro River. The hne JfSF Co Ccapaey Eleaente and the COllll8Dd and Control Detac haent returned to Pleiku by road on the 4th ot April closing at 1830 houn. These units are the 17 Engineer Company ldrl ch is reported to work with or subordinate to the Kain Force Battalion and in the past bB been used to set ambushes and 18 mines long highway 19", "keywords": [{"term": "South", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Southwe11", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "231600 hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Dak Xaro River", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "26th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "MSF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "AO", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "71530 hours", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "comparoJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "021830", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "MSF", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the first 16 days", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "late at night", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "The 21th 181 Company", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1tD Bll1E", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "241100", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "COllll8Dd", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Control Detac", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Pleiku", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "4th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "April", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "1830", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "17", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Engineer Company", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Kain Force Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "18", "category": "QUANTITY"}, {"term": "19", "category": "CARDINAL"}], "time": "April 1968"}, {"filename": "USMC CC 1201049016", "text": "The zone of the downed CE 46 was sc cured with Company Ie on high ground on the northern half of the perimeter and Company to the south. This marked the commence ment of Operation CORTEZ the mission of which was to furnish security for the downed helicopter as well as to conduct extensive patrolling into the mountains and valleys of the objective area. The platoon made thorough search of the area and was helilift ed back to the Battalion CP the same afternoon. ri th the addition of Company 11 and the Battalion CP the RCLIGHT follow up was given the name of Op eration CORTEZ. The 1M was contacted on 99 at the rear area and upon learning of the difficulty attempted to shift both aircraft and ground unit to Button Redll UHF and in turn Button Brown. On the morn ng of the ARCLIGHT one platoon reinforced from Company was he lili ted into the target area to exploit the miss on. NClASSIFlED DstciWi DECLASSIFIED DECLASSIFIED rru 1if ng of the downed CH 46 by the liflying craneil was handled competently and quickly Orig n311y it hEld beEn suggested hat the crane upon departure from the area circlE to the northeast how eyer the pilot chose straight line course nearly eastward cmd received enemy ground fire miles outside of the safe perimeter. day December 1966 At 051140H Company Rein was helo lifted from the 3rd Battalion 5th iiarines CP at BT 465073 and joined with recon uniJG from the 1st Recon Bat Galion on the woy to the landing zone. Company continued their ground recon of the central portion of the liliCLIGHT area and were mOVing into the northern sector. On December the balance of Company Rein as upwn in to reinforce the platoon", "keywords": [{"term": "46", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "half", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Operation CORTEZ", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "the Battalion CP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the same afternoon", "category": "TIME"}, {"term": "Company 11", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "the Battalion CP the RCLIGHT", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "The 1M", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "99", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Button Redll", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Button Brown", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "ARCLIGHT", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "DstciWi", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1if", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "46", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Orig", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "day December 1966", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "051140H Company Rein", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3rd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "5th", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "CP", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "BT 465073", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1st", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Recon Bat", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "December", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Company Rein", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "January 1967"}, {"filename": "USMC CC 26240206004", "text": "17 Fe 14 17 Fo 21 29 Fob 26 29 Fe ART III lo FlO Cmcy nization Cocmi tted to Col lbato Caz lba lliseion fmj Oeoo py and defend assignetl TAORo Ii aintam saturation lwel of patl ol aoti vi ty 1i thin the TAOR On der ba prepared to conduct oftensive operv tions outside the TAORo Inte rclic and deny the use ot va and other i1tes or egz esa Jr Ul Be the er er zyo Provide oecuri ty ar tho rood net and traffic rt thin the TAC Ro LoCl tep capture or dos troy oee attooptillg to lOVe l1D terl al or rockets in to tho ro et bolto Con du et pn oifiontion progron in su rport of tbe GVlI Assist in the tra1niJls or opulo Foroeso Assist in the Revoluticnary Dov3lo pnent Pro C011FTDEt1TJAL. Do ttnlions 3lot Re lnont llVA 111ho 38GB Jrli er Recimnt WA bo so mp ui th tho ra Dcntal hoo dqunrtoro nnd the 1st JbttnU on ni bollarod locntod in the scm thatrcstcrn portion of tr TACR ri lo lr1 th tlw 5lot Tloc1 tlw ta hoodqa nrtorn The 1st end 3rd na tta lion of the 31st Rogmont vo been identified in tho TAOR Tho locntiou of the 2nd Datto lion ia unlmolJ Ilo Tho 2nd Ba tto lion ol hc 368B Relf nent mn reported both in tho iouthern one. the LlJ ru The cnr ITUGd no jor 11TET11 of fe YJ Civ du ring the eo rly po rt of the re rpo rti criod cto Uinnt friendly tu1 tn uoro nl TLOJ OUSo thin he 1st co1ion1 7th Ho rinc OR the er cecry met nnd defoo ted 111 th henvy cs 0so hc Jt contact ua oolim be th lcncr of the 31 si ec lnc lt 1TV be ing th hillf of the rc po ri lr pcrioilr th rc. Wi lRA nn sum IAf lo the nonth of 1618 snall unit pa tro1 ci itica uere conductooe Thay rooul ted in 70 contact or uhich uere tio ht by riondly faroes nd 57 the VCI To1ev zy cnsualties aru lis ed h1 TIIo Inten sive so tu tion trol ctivity utilizing 3Ii10 ll mil t0 lo ll ranae pn trola uas conducted tln oughout the month to lerry the enon cc ess to the rockot beltp and rocket lonnching aiten 3o Durin the Dont of rebru ry nore Ephn sis uo placed 16 rifle tr 11 cru and clt1l lm ngp fron illo riza tion firinc1 oottle si htGr nnd inmedio te nctionc Wier training included basic map rnadir1. no Qo in the proaeso of polio 1c ll loose nocly mid Tho Soul. entral portion of tho TAORo is bclievad thoy re nor locntod in the uoatern ncmituina ui th orunrd elemcmto loce ood in tho ccntr portion or tho TACRo bro ot looo tion of 3rd Battclion or tho an Roginont 1ro ot detominedJ houever. ni2 rn booby rap nc cc ts TU HD ri ed to the JrL iYo enc ny novB JJ rc thr oucl1crLrt cl 1L ll 13 the ln Lte portion of Ulc ror rtir rariod. ri ch heavy 0000 dury tiono horc tvo ili lve in nd dj 11t to tho OR S0nc Yen on U1e ec Jt ill lJ ii 1c sc1 and Song cy ken in hG uo umli JC ueoto The 9rinciyi. il Fo fio ionoonc1nc12d cm cf cJJ cks to th0 itco of Tii11 00 opurotion le cl 11 itil tho 16 ch Hi th oic nif cc nt cm ct cn001 e1 te ed op tion co110iotcd. strlke led in the tc of Ilill 2700 ilio second cJ ey reoultad", "keywords": [{"term": "17", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "14 17 Fo 21", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "29", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Fob 26", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "29", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Fe ART III", "category": "FAC"}, {"term": "FlO Cmcy", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Cocmi", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Caz", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Oeoo", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "1i", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Inte", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Jr", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the TAC Ro LoCl", "category": "EVENT"}, {"term": "al", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "tra1niJls", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Foroeso Assist", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Revoluticnary Dov3lo", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "Pro", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3lot", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "38", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "GB Jrli er Recimnt WA", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 1st", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TACR", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "lr1", "category": "PRODUCT"}, {"term": "The 1st end 3rd", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Datto", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "2nd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "368B", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Relf", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "LlJ", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Uinnt", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "tu1", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "TLOJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1st", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Ho", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "111", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "0so", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "31", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Wi", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "IAf", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1618", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "tro1", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Thay", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "70", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "57", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "VCI", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Inten", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3Ii10", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "the month", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Durin", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Ephn", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "16", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "htGr", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1c", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "3rd Battclion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "1ro", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "detominedJ", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "ni2", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "TU HD", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "JrL", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "JJ", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "1L", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "13", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "Ulc", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "0000", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "S0nc Yen", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Song", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "JC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "9rinciyi", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "00", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "16", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "cn001", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "Ilill 2700", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "second", "category": "ORDINAL"}], "time": "March 1968"}, {"filename": "USMC CC F015800480370", "text": "Also on December 1967 the 3rd Platoon Company 3rd Tank Battelionjwes redesignated the 2nd Pl toon Company 1st Tank Battalion and was assigned the 2nd Platoon command frequency On 17 Docembor 1967J the 1st Tank Batta1ion joinec Company Rein 1st AT Battalron. Results of the various activities in which the 1st Tank Battalion participated during ember were 11. This cadra will handle the recor and aintain filos for tho AntitAnk Battalion in the ovont the roorg nization of tho Battalion is ordered. Company oontinues in direct support of the 5th Marines in the Marble Nountain area Trafficabili ty in the Marble Mountain area is good beoause of the sandy terrain. The lccation of the gun companies. Marine standing vratch on the tank throw the grenDde fram tho tonk but roceived slight injuries when the gr cnadedotonotod in the. rG9Nfl8EHp2 UNClASSifiED OPERATIONS AND TRAINING During the month of November the lst Talut Battalion participated in one major operation. The successful unf etected launching of these rafts is indicative the elusiveness the VC in this ea. Of pnrticula interest was map showing the location for the North defl3nsive tank posi tL at the 30i Cnu do Bri0ge. On 27 Decambor reprosentative from tho 1st Tank Battalion traveled to the Binh Son nrell to the 2nd Korc Harino Brig Haadquarters AS the Tar Battalion roproson", "keywords": [{"term": "December 1967", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "the 3rd Platoon Company", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "3rd", "category": "ORDINAL"}, {"term": "Tank Battelionjwes", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "the 2nd", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "2nd", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "17", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1st Tank", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "Company Rein 1st", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the 1st Tank Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "11", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "AntitAnk Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "5th Marines", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "Marble Nountain", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Trafficabili", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Marble Mountain", "category": "LOC"}, {"term": "Marine", "category": "NORP"}, {"term": "grenDde", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "OPERATIONS", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the month of November", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Talut Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "one", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "VC", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "North defl3nsive", "category": "GPE"}, {"term": "30i", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "27", "category": "CARDINAL"}, {"term": "1st Tank Battalion", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "the Binh Son", "category": "ORG"}, {"term": "2nd", "category": "DATE"}, {"term": "Brig Haadquarters", "category": "PERSON"}, {"term": "Tar Battalion", "category": "ORG"}], "time": "December 1967"}]